<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: filesystem | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/filesystem/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-02T19:41:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Not Working, Not Creating Report Files Either + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-not-working-not-creating-report-files-either-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T14:49:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-not-working-not-creating-report-files-either-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a Magento site that is consistently erroring out and giving you the report screen with the file name, but the file does not exist in the reports folder then this could be your solution.</p>

<p>The most likely culprit in this scenario is that the filesystem has run out of space. If this happens, Magento will die because it literally can&rsquo;t create any files and it needs to do this for caching, session etc.</p>

<p>You can easily check this by running this command:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>df -h</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you see any filesystems with 100% usage then you have your answer, you have run out of hard drive space and need to free some space up by deleting files.</p>

<p>On occasion though you might run this and see that you still have plenty of space. This can be puzzling at first though you need to bear in mind that Linux filesystems don&rsquo;t purely use space but also something called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inode" title="wikipedia explanation of inodes" target="_blank">inodes</a>.</p>

<p>An inode is like a file pointer, you need one for every file that is in the filesystem. Also there is a limit to the number of inodes in any file system. If something goes crazy and your system creates lots of small files then you might find that you run out of inodes before you run out of hard drive space.</p>

<p>To check if this is your issue run this command:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>df -i</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you see any lines with 100% then you have run out of inodes and you need to delete some files. There are numerous possible causes of this and tactics that can be used to clear them out. When dealing with Magento though there are a few usual suspects.</p>

<p>Magento is a real culprit for this behaviour as it uses file system based sessions by default. Session files are very small and can be very numerous.</p>

<p>The quick fix is just to completely remove the sessions directory:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>rm -rf /path/to/magento/var/session</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Magento will recreate it on the next request.</p>

<p>If you would like to try to clear out just older sessions then you can do something like this:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>find /path/to/magento/var/session -name &lsquo;sess_*&rsquo; -type f -mtime +7 -exec rm {} \;</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rsync For Beginners]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/rsync-for-beginners-2.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T16:42:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/rsync-for-beginners-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>What is Rsync in general ?</h3>


<p>Rsync works like the <a href="http://linux.about.com/od/commands/l/blcmdl1_rcp.htm" rel="nofollow">rcp</a> command in linux. It is used to copy files across machines. It uses efficient checksum algorithm that looks for modified files by time and size. It is used for two purposes:</p>

<h2>Backup</h2>


<p>Rsync is used to transfer file from the local to a remote machine. By default Rsync will use rsh, however you can instead use <a href="http://linux.about.com/od/commands/l/blcmdl1_ssh.htm" rel="nofollow">ssh</a> for high security. Compressed files are transferred to save file transfer time and reduce the load on the network. It helps to transfer bulk files in minutes.</p>

<h2>Mirroring</h2>


<p>Rsync can synchronize file between two servers location(i.e) local and remote. By using the checksum algorithm it updates local files only if it is updated in remote server.</p>

<h3>How to use Rsync</h3>


<p>
```php</p>

<p>rsync -avze ssh -p2020 root@server.com:/sitepath/files   /localdata</p>

<p>```
This command transfer files from remote server to local machine.</p>

<p>a  Archive. It is denotes all related files and documents.
v  Verbose.It will display status message as it is processing.
z  Compression.It achives better compression ratio.
e  It allows to chose alternative remote shell program for communication.</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>rsync -avze ssh -p2020 &mdash;exclude home/var/cache root@server.com:/sitepath/files /localdata</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This command will transfer files from remote server to local machine by excluding cache folder.</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>rsync -avz /sitepath/files root@server.com:/localdata</p>

<p>```
This command will  transfer all file from local to remote server. It is uses default remote shell protocol.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
