<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: management | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/management/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-07T15:20:44+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency Server Recovery Support - PHP, MySQL, Fatal Error, Site Down, Table Crashed + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/management/emergency-recovery-php-mysql-fatal-error-site-down-table-crashed-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-11-26T11:55:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/management/emergency-recovery-php-mysql-fatal-error-site-down-table-crashed-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If your site has suddenly gone down and you are tearing your hair out because the people you usually call for server support aren&rsquo;t answering the phone then fear not &ndash; we can help you out.</p>

<p>Along with our core business of building, customising and extending e-commerce web sites, we are also pretty handy at fixing problems when the pressure is on and you need results quickly.</p>

<p>If you are running a PHP/MySQL based web site on a Linux server and its stopped working with Fatal Error or even an empty white screen then get in touch with us.</p>

<p>We appreciate that your e-commerce web site is your business and when the site is down your doors are closed and you are losing money. We can help you to get your doors back open again as quickly as possible.</p>

<p>Get in touch with us on <b>0844 357 020</b>1 and drop us a <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk">contact form</a></p>

<p>We will support you in your server emergency.</p>

<h3>Errors that you might encounter include:</h3>


<p>Fatal Error</p>

<p>Warning</p>

<p>MySQL Error</p>

<p>Headers Already Sent</p>

<p>There has been an error processing your request</p>

<p>Error log record number</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ecommerce Back Office Optimisations]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/management/customer%20services/ecommerce-back-office-optimisations.html"/>
    <updated>2008-02-25T10:47:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/management/customer%20services/ecommerce-back-office-optimisations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Its easy sometimes to focus entirely on the front end features of your web site or ecommerce business. Without a doubt the front end is the most imporant part of your web site as it needs to work well to allow your visitors to find and purchase what they are looking for.</p>

<p>However, the back end of your ecommerce site also needs some investment putting into it. A well designed and implemented back end will mean that your customers get better customer services and your staff are happier and therefore more cheerful and better at making your customers happy.</p>

<p>A well designed back office system will have the utmost automation built in, which means that your staff costs are lower and the capacity for human error to upset the flow of your business is minimised. Naturally it is the most mundane and boring tasks which are the most ripe for automation. This means that your staff are happier as they can concentrate on the tasks that really do require a human mind to be dealt with effectively.</p>

<p>The other major aspect of a well designed back end system is easily accessible and relevant information. This means that if your customer services operative takes a call from a customer who is chasing up an order, your operative can be looking at all of the relevant information within a couple of seconds, and can quickly determine the current status and advise the customer with accurate and up to date information.</p>

<p>It also means that as a manager, you can have access to performance indicators and other management information just as easily. This will allow you to quickly spot and diagnose problems and take action to fix current problems and prevent future problems.</p>

<p>All of this means a better bottom line.</p>

<p>If you would like to get some help with your ecommerce back office, get in touch today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
