<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Addons on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/addons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Addons on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 13:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/addons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Developer Toolbar for Firefox</title>
      <link>http://example.com/web-development/web-developer-toolbar-for-firefox.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/web-development/web-developer-toolbar-for-firefox.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The web developer toolbar is an excellent addition to the great firefox web browser. It allows you ultimate control over the behaviour of your web browser and helps you to fine tune layouts. The toolbar has a real time html and css editor built in which is great for tweaking things. For those of you who have a nice big 22&amp;rdquo; monitor to develop on, the resize functionality is awesome for replicating the viewport of whichever resolutions you want, so that you can ensure your layout still works on an 800 x 600 display for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a web development tool for those of us who hand code things instead of using dreamweaver or whatnot - it is an excellent tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the web developer toolbar &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/60&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is some kind of bug with Firefox where if an update fails or the browser crashes, then your web developer toolbar may stop working. In fact it is still working but all of the icons disappear. All you have to do to fix it is right click it, select customize and then  select &amp;ldquo;Restore Default Set&amp;rdquo;. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.voodish.co.uk/articles/web-developer-toolbar-broken-empty-not-showing-fix/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Voodish &lt;/a&gt;for the fix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>