<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: crontab | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/crontab/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-29T16:52:40+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Increase the Stabilty of your Magento cron]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/increase-the-stabilty-of-your-magento-cron.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-24T13:51:04+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/increase-the-stabilty-of-your-magento-cron</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes when your cron process in Magento seems to not be working it is worth doubling up the ways it gets executed.</p>

<p>One reason for this is various extensions (notably EERP from boostmyshop) set up an override to ensure that the same cron task is not run a second time if it&rsquo;s still running when the first run happens.</p>

<p>Often the cli setup for php is not configured with the same timeouts etc. that the web setup is.  Therefore one thing that can make your cron more &ldquo;stable&rdquo; is to use wget or curl to fetch the cron.php file rather than (or as well as) running the cron.sh script.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what to add to the server&rsquo;s crontab (/etc/crontab or crontab -e) to use wget to fire off the cron :
```</p>

<ul>
<li><ul>
<li><ul>
<li><ul>
<li><ul>
<li>/usr/bin/wget -O- www.mycoolsite.com/cron.php > /dev/null 2> /dev/null</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>```</p>

<p>That of course needs the url changing to match your domain.  It&rsquo;s worth noting that having output and stderror piped to /dev/null in a crontab is probably not the best practice but given that any module can create cron tasks that output stuff, your sysadmin might dislike getting that emailed to them!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Server Migration - Synch Cron Tab via SSH]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/server-migration-synch-cron-tab-via-ssh.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T17:54:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/server-migration-synch-cron-tab-via-ssh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are handling a server migration and would like to have a scripted way to copy the crontab from one machine to the other then you might like this little snippet.</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>ssh -p2020 <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#x6f;&#58;&#114;&#x6f;&#111;&#116;&#x40;&#x31;&#50;&#x33;&#x2e;&#49;&#50;&#51;&#46;&#x31;&#x32;&#51;&#46;&#49;&#x32;&#x33;">&#114;&#x6f;&#111;&#116;&#64;&#49;&#50;&#x33;&#x2e;&#x31;&#50;&#x33;&#x2e;&#49;&#50;&#51;&#x2e;&#49;&#50;&#51;</a> &lsquo;crontab -l&rsquo; | crontab &ndash;</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This will get the contents of the root crontab from one server and apply it to the current server, replacing any current cron tab settings.</p>

<p>This is nice if you want to have a repeatable server resynch process whilst you are migrating and the crontab on the old server may change</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
