<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Implement Themes on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/implement-themes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Implement Themes on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 17:26:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/implement-themes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending a Modules CSS within a Theme in PrestaShop</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/extending-a-modules-css-within-a-theme-in-prestashop.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 17:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/extending-a-modules-css-within-a-theme-in-prestashop.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PrestaShop has a really nice structure for handling all the CSS that will appear in a site. It starts by splitting the CSS so that the CSS is split up per modules. There is a global CSS sheet but this should only be used for things that genuinely appear on all pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extending the CSS of a module in PrestaShop is easy. All you need to do is create a CSS file that matches the naming convention of the module you are looking to extend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example if you wanted to change the CSS of the “Wishlist block” module (a.k.a. blockwishlist) in your theme, you would create the file themes/mytheme/css/modules/blockwishlist/blockwishlist.css. This file will then be included on every page that the CSS from the blockwishlist module appears on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system is good because it minimises the amount of CSS the browser has to load and also splits the concern of CSS into separate files making it much easier to manage. It also makes adding to a modules CSS with in a theme much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem with this method of handling CSS is that by default a PrestaShop site may want the browser to download ten or more individual CSS files which is quite a overhead. Fortunately since PrestaShop 1.4 it has supported CCS merging (referred to as CCC in the admin) which causes the CSS for a page to be merged into a single file on the server to prevent the client having to download tens of CSS files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slipstream Bikes</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/slipstream-bikes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/slipstream-bikes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Brand new website &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is being created and developed from the beginning. The project required to build and implement a theme, create custom functionality, integrate with wordpress, and design the product category for the particular needs of the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; Slipstream Bikes new launch &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slipstream Bikes are an e-commerce retailing company, that are specialising in bikes. They have currently launched carbon race frames for the next season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>