<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Migration on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/migration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Migration on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 18:03:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>cPanel Download Site Files and Database</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/cpanel/cpanel-download-site-files-and-database.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 18:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/cpanel/cpanel-download-site-files-and-database.html</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Often a client won&amp;rsquo;t have access to SSH, or won&amp;rsquo;t be able to provide you with some of the more specifics such as FTP, PHPMyAdmin etc. All they know to give you is access to their cPanel. Through this there&amp;rsquo;s various tools at your disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-ssh&#34;&gt;Try SSH&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your cPanel login is actually a Linux user login, which cPanel&amp;rsquo;s FTP hooks into. The first step is to navigate in your cPanel to FTP Accounts and click Configure FTP client on a user. These are SFTP details and can very often provide you with SSH shell access, unless the host has disabled this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply try &lt;code&gt;ssh user@host -p 1234&lt;/code&gt;, where the user, host and password are your cPanel login, and the port displayed on the FTP Accounts page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here you&amp;rsquo;re free to use &lt;code&gt;tar&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mysqldump&lt;/code&gt; etc to acquire the files and database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-ssh-isn-t-enabled&#34;&gt;If SSH isn&amp;rsquo;t enabled&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the host disables SSH access, only allowing its use for SFTP. There are still many ways to acquire the site&amp;rsquo;s files and database:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Getting hold of the files&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plain old FTP&lt;/strong&gt; - You can just use an FTP client such as Filezilla to access and download the site&amp;rsquo;s files using FTP or SFTP. This is the simplest way, but can take a long time because of the amount of files involved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File Manager Web UI&lt;/strong&gt; - compressing the site&amp;rsquo;s files obviously shrinks the download size, but also vastly reduces the amount of connections you need to make, leading to a faster download speed.

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to the File Manager section (remember to tick &amp;ldquo;Show hidden files&amp;rdquo; to pick up .htaccess files)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse to the web root folder, select all the files and folders you want using Ctrl+Click. Remember to exclude unnecessary large files such as sql dumps, media folders and the var folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Compress from the toolbar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Getting hold of the database&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHPMyAdmin&lt;/strong&gt; - PHPMyAdmin offers an array of options for dumping your database. You should start by checking the database&amp;rsquo;s size and considering excluding the dump of tables such as &lt;code&gt;log_url&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;log_url_info&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;log_visitor&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;log_visitor_info&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;report_viewed_product_index&lt;/code&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to the PHPMyAdmin area of cPanel and locate the database in use (check your &lt;code&gt;app/etc/local.xml&lt;/code&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure which&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Export tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Custom: here&amp;rsquo;s where you can selectively export information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tick &amp;lsquo;Disable foreign key checks&amp;rsquo; and set &amp;lsquo;Dump table&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;structure&amp;rsquo;. This will have PHPMyAdmin set up only the tables&amp;rsquo; columns but no data (we&amp;rsquo;ll get to that)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once this is complete, navigate back to the Export page and click Custom again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deselect (ctrl+click) any tables which are unnecessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tick &amp;lsquo;Disable foreign key checks&amp;rsquo; and set &amp;lsquo;Dump table&amp;rsquo; this time to &amp;lsquo;data&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will provide you with two files representing the database. Import first the Structure one, and then the Data one (or concatenate the two together)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magmi</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magmi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 13:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magmi.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It used to be that importing products into Magento was incredibly time consuming and difficult to handle. Whilst recent updates to Magento has improved the Dataflow process it is still not a perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help get round this a project was set-up called &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/apps/mediawiki/magmi/index.php?title=Main_Page&#34; title=&#34;Magmi&#34;&gt;Magmi&lt;/a&gt; which allowed products to be imported directly, rather than using the Magento ORM. As this evolved it added more useful features and is now the only way that I handle importing products into Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of steps that need to be carried out before the system can be used properly. After it has been installed the first thing that needs to be done is to secure the web interface. This can be done using Basic Auth or IP restrictions in Apache. To generate a basic auth password for a .htaccess file you can use this &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.dynamicdrive.com/password/&#34;&gt;handy tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have it secured the next step is to install some extensions to allow you to use some of the more advanced features. To install plugins you download them from here:&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/magmi/files/magmi-0.7/plugins/individual/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/magmi/files/magmi-0.7/plugins/individual/&lt;/a&gt; and then extract them into the plugins folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can use plugin packages and you can actually install these directly from the web interface if your server supports it (Thanks Dweeves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plugins are really what makes MAGMI so great as they allow you to do things like handle configurable products, categories and other things that standard dataflow and import/export are no where near being able to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For advanced purposes it is possible to leverage the power of MAGMI in your own custom import purposes as part of a bespoke application using &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/apps/mediawiki/magmi/index.php?title=Magmi_Datapump_API&#34;&gt;MAGMI datapump&lt;/a&gt;. We have used this technique for numerous clients when building a direct import from supplier feeds etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Magento Database Migrations to Track Configuration Changes</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-database-migrations-to-track-configuration-changes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 09:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-database-migrations-to-track-configuration-changes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often when working on a Magento site, there is a requirement to build custom functionality or implement new themes etc but to finish the job, the final step will be to perform some admin configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This manual step can introduce the possiblity of human error if a step is missed or not performed exactly correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also if the configuration is to be applied multiple times across staging, pre production and final production then these risks increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only sure way to make sure that the correct configuration is applied and also to provide a proper audit trail for configuration changes is to use Magento&amp;rsquo;s database migrations - install and upgrade scripts - to update the database programmatically with the required configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assist with this, there is a nice simple module you can find on Git Hub:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/danslo/MigrationHelper&#34;&gt;https://github.com/danslo/MigrationHelper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This module will automatically create the migration files for you which can be a real time saver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would always suggest you create your own custom namespaced configuration migration module that is purely to track these configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ongoing Magento Support and Consultation</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buckleylondon.com&#34;&gt;Buckley&lt;/a&gt; is a UK based company that prides itself on designing and manufacturing high quality fashion &amp;amp; costume jewellery at competitive prices since its inception in 1989. The company has rapidly expanded into a worldwide brand with jewellery collections available to a vast market of over 200 stores including more than 60 Duty Free shops and 120 airlines . We are glad to hear that Buckley has contributed over US$3 million to the funding of the Royal British Legion through the sale of its elegant Buckley Poppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The development idea:&lt;/h3&gt;
Buckley Jewellery was initially launched using Wordpress and used an ecommerce package called ShopperPress. As the company grew and they started to expand their business to Duty Free shops and airlines, it became apparent that WordPress could not provide enough support for their complex modifications and customisations. This is when the idea of re-building the site in Magento was suggested.

We started working with Buckley in 2011 and have been providing them with continuous support since then. Some of the main requirements were broadly to do the following:

&lt;h3&gt;1. Magento implementation and migration from previous platform&lt;/h3&gt;
We installed and configured Magento onto Buckley’s chosen hosting platform and installed the essential extensions such as shipping and payment gateways including PayPal and SagePay. We also migrated all of their products, customers and orders database from the previous platform into Magento. A clean and clear design was created and customised to their specification and we have been tweaking it per their needs and requirements ever since.

&lt;h3&gt;2. Magento training&lt;/h3&gt;
After successfully migrating the site to Magento, we did an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-course-details/&#34;&gt;on-site one day introduction course&lt;/a&gt; with Buckley, where we gave them the background understanding and some useful skills required to get the most out of their new Magento store. 
Here is a quote from Mark at Buckley Jewellry: “&lt;em&gt;The day was extremely useful with just the right amount of content to set us on our way&lt;/em&gt;.”

&lt;h3&gt;3. Magento upgrade and Magento security patch applied&lt;/h3&gt;
It is important to make sure that your Magento site is up to date. We have done two upgrades for Buckley so far and they all went really well.The upgrades were done in three separate phrases - exploratory upgrade, bugs fixing and deployment to live. We hit a few bugs but managed to fix them within hours. 
Around mid July 2012, a serious security hole was found in Zend Framework which allow hackers to gain access to mysql server credentials. A patch was quickly applied to Buckley live store using a nice Bash script we put together. We offered this free security patching service to all Magento sites with a voluntary charity donation and had a lot of sites take us up on this offer.

&lt;h3&gt;4. Ongoing support&lt;/h3&gt;
Buckley have joined our retainer scheme where we provide them with daily maintenance supports, bugs fixing and consultation services. Various &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery/&#34;&gt;firesale promotions&lt;/a&gt;, extensions and marketing exercises were installed and configured into their website.
Recently we had migrated Buckley and its sister site &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.attwoodandsawyer.com&#34;&gt;Attwood &amp; Sawyer&lt;/a&gt; to a dedicated server, which is faster, more secured and gives them better control over the sites.
Buckley also engages in designing beautiful vintage inspired pieces in the silver &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bouton.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Bouton&lt;/a&gt; rages and we are currently managing the merger process of Bouton into Buckley main sites. 

&lt;h3&gt;Testimonial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a quote from Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Buckley Jewellery originally approached &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk&#34;&gt;Edmonds Commerce&lt;/a&gt; to take our existing site and develop it onto a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/platforms/magento/&#34;&gt;Magento platform&lt;/a&gt;. Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp;amp; expand our ecommerce business. The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design. I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice”. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/screenshot-thumb1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Google Apps - Google Apps Reseller</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 14:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are big fans of Google Apps and have built a large portion of our business processes around the system. For this reason we have absolutely no problem recommending the service to our clients and have assisted numerous clients with a migration to the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first benefit you will get is your emails migrated over and a much better email service. You have the option of using normal IMAP access so you can continue to use your preferred desktop application however we suspect that you will start to use the web interface as it is really quite powerful with some unique features that you can not access on a normal desktop client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with this you have great support of mobile devices, especially if you opt for Android with powerful and free native apps meaning that you can have all the access to your emails that could possibly wish for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the really excellent email functionality you also have powerful online documents giving you the basic office application functionality along with really powerful collaboration features allowing multiple people to be working on the same document simultaneously from geographically separate locations. This can be great when putting together proposals, specifications etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now called Google Drive, the documents system has grown from managing purely office documents into a fully featured online file store that can be used to store and share all kinds of files across your organisation and with third parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the calendar functionality is great. If you have never used Google Calendar then I suspect the first things you will notice is the abilty to easily drag and drop appointments around when reorganising your schedule. The ability to quickly create appointments using natural language such as &amp;ldquo;call steve at 11am&amp;rdquo; is really nice. A full barrage of reminders can be set up if you wish including on screen, SMS and emails meaning you should never miss an appointment again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all we think Google Apps is great and would love to help you move your organisation across to the system. If you would like to discuss this in more detail please do &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;get in touch today&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are a Google Apps Reseller.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Sun Java repo</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/linux-sun-java-repo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 10:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/linux-sun-java-repo.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I setup a machine with Linux Mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that was I needed to install was an up to date version of Sun Java. However, for various reasons, this no longer appears in the official repos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully there is a different repo available here &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.duinsoft.nl/packages.php?t=en&#34; title=&#34;http://www.duinsoft.nl/packages.php?t=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.duinsoft.nl/packages.php?t=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.duinsoft.nl/packages.php?t=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where you can download the latest version and ensure that it is updated&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Multiple MySQL Queries in a Single Function</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/run-multiple-mysql-queries-in-a-single-function.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 12:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/run-multiple-mysql-queries-in-a-single-function.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to be able to run multiple queries in a single function call, for example doing the classic drop table blah; create table blah; then you might like this function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use case is for things like database migration systems which you might copy and paste chunks of SQL including multiple queries from things like phpMyAdmin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;/**&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * Run multiple queries passed in as a single string&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * This is optimised for copying and pasting from phpMyAdmin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * Handy for things like database migration systems&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * @param string $sql  multiple queries terminated with ; and a new line&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;function multiQuery($sql)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    $sqls = preg_split(&amp;#39;%;$%m&amp;#39;, trim($sql));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    foreach ($sqls as $q) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        if (empty($q)) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;            continue;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        mysql_query($q); //suggest you replace this with your custom query function or if not throw in some extra error checking at least&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Migration - Pipe Tar from Server to Server using Netcat</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/server-migration-pipe-tar-from-server-to-server-using-netcat.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 14:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/server-migration-pipe-tar-from-server-to-server-using-netcat.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you need to transfer a large amount of data from one server to another you might normally create a large tar archive, send it across and then untar it on the other end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However a slightly slicker and easier repeated way of doing this is to pipe tar directly from one server to the other doing all three steps in one go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this you would create a script on each server. You could of course type the commands directly but in the interests of easy repeatability and removing the scope for human error, scripts are my preferred way of doing this kind of task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old server script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
#!/bin/bash

cd /var/www/vhosts

# where new server IP is 123.123.123.123 and 9999 is the port the new server is listening on
tar -xvj . | nc 123.123.123.123 9999


&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Server Script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
#!/bin/bash

cd /var/www/vhosts

nc -l 9999 | tar -xvf --same-owner


&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now save these scripts and make them executable (chmod +x)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run the new server script on the new server and then run the old server script. You should quickly see the list of files being transferred appearing in both terminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Migration - Synch Cron Tab via SSH</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/server-migration-synch-cron-tab-via-ssh.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 17:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/server-migration-synch-cron-tab-via-ssh.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are handling a server migration and would like to have a scripted way to copy the crontab from one machine to the other then you might like this little snippet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;

ssh -p2020 root@123.123.123.123 &#39;crontab -l&#39; | crontab -


&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will get the contents of the root crontab from one server and apply it to the current server, replacing any current cron tab settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is nice if you want to have a repeatable server resynch process whilst you are migrating and the crontab on the old server may change&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple way to check Magento email setup</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/simple-way-to-check-magento-email-setup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 15:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/simple-way-to-check-magento-email-setup.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;ve just moved a magento setup from one host to another, and you want to check if the email setup is correct, how do you do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple easy way to do this is to have a test front-end user (which you probably already have) and send a password change email to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple trick but a good timesaver.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass Seed Store - Migration from OSCommerce</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/grass-seed-store-migration-from-oscommerce.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 16:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/grass-seed-store-migration-from-oscommerce.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grass Seed Store – Migration from OSCommerce with Custom Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grass Seeds Store wants to migrate away from OSCommerce to Magento in order to improve stock management. They also need to maintain DEFRA compliance and have custom reports generated to do so. The custom reporting was based on the sales of seeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Grass Seed Store&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grass Seed Store specialises in the sale of a many different types of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thegrassseedstore.co.uk/&#34;&gt;grass seed, fertiliser and live stock pasture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/grassseed-300x205.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is a great example of customising Magento to be compliant with an industry governing body and shows that Magento can be used in almost any for the sale of any type of product. The project is currently a work in progress and the Magento implementation is currently only a wire frame demonstrating the functionality that is ultimately required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over Board - Magento Migration</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 16:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Over Board – Migration to Magento from OSCommerce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board wished to move away from OSCommerce due to limitations encountered while using OSCommerce. Using Magento allows the company the flexibility they desired. This project involved implementing a new site design as well as importing data from the old OSCommerce site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Over Board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board are an eCommerce company specialising in the sales of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.over-board.co.uk/&#34;&gt;water proof device cases and bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/overboards-300x224.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was terrific as it demonstrates the ability to move away from a relativity old system to a new system and at the same time enabling a lot more functionality and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce to Magento Migration with Redesign Starting from £1280</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/oscommerce-to-magento-migrations-with-redesign-starting-from-1280.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 11:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/oscommerce-to-magento-migrations-with-redesign-starting-from-1280.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Migrate your &lt;strong&gt;osCommerce, CRE Loaded or Zen Cart&lt;/strong&gt; store to &lt;strong&gt;Magento&lt;/strong&gt; for as little as &lt;strong&gt;£1280&lt;/strong&gt;. Get in touch today and we can discuss your particular requirements and help you at every step of the way in your migration to &lt;strong&gt;Magento&lt;/strong&gt;, without a doubt the best open source ecommerce platform available today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of upgrading or migrating from your osCommerce, CRE Loaded or Zen Cart based store to Magento then you should definitely get in touch with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce have years of experience working with osCommerce and its derivatives and know the platform inside out, back to front. We have done all kinds of things with osCommerce and still have a large number of clients still using the platform with great success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However Magento is becoming more and more of an attractive option. It is new, modern, powerful and is definitely on the up. Certain Magento features, such as the multi store would be so hard to achieve with an osCommerce based store (or CRE Loaded, Zen Cart) that a migration to Magnento is the only realistic option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading Magento specialists, we have worked on a large number of Magento sites for a wide range of clients in all kinds of industries. We spotted Magento on the up when it was still in its infancy. We knew that osCommerce was getting a bit long in the tooth and the market was wide open for its successor as the most popular open source ecommerce platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later and it has certainly achieved that status, eclipsing osCommerce in every way apart perhaps from the number of sites running it. Having been around for a long time and being very successful, there are still a large number of sites using osCommerce (or CRE Loaded, Zen Cart). However we are now seeing more and more new and existing clients looking to move away from osCommerce and onto Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are able to help you perform and smooth and seamless transition from one platform to the other. We can migrate all the necessary data over and get your new store working perfectly and to your satisfaction before making a seamless switch so you suffer no down time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to get some Magento training we are also able to help you with this, offering both classroom based Magento training in Leeds, West Yorkshire and online training for those for whom Leeds is a bit difficult to get to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If you would like to know more or get in touch&lt;/b&gt;
Please &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;click here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to go to our contact form and get in touch with us regarding osCommerce to Magento migrations by osCommerce and Magento experts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Google Apps</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 07:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We recently decided to give Google Apps a try, mainly due to the requirement for some decent webmail and it being a brilliant webmail system at the unbeatable price of free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my quick guide to migrating easily:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Migrating emails - sign up to the free trial of the premier edition and use the IMAP migration system. It is by far the slickest option and will faithfully and accurately import all of your emails across. Best, you can set it going and then shut down your local machine, its all handled server side, so no requirement to shunt emails up from your desktop or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nested Folders - if you do the above and have a lot of nested folders, you will notice a pretty ugly massive list of tags with forward slashes in. To get back your nested sub folder like functionality you need to go to settings, then labs and then enabled the nested tags extension. This will give you a sub folder like interface for your tags and tidy the whole thing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turn off those adds at the top - If you notice adds being displayed at the top and would like to get rid, its easy - Gmail calls them web clips and you can turn them off in the settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating osCommerce Sites to a New Server (also CRE Loaded, Zen Cart etc)</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/migrating-oscommerce-sites-to-a-new-server-also-cre-loaded-zen-cart-etc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 11:27:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/migrating-oscommerce-sites-to-a-new-server-also-cre-loaded-zen-cart-etc.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you need to move your osCommerce (and derivatives such as CRE Loaded and Zen Cart) based site to a new server, here is a quick explanation of our approach which enables you to handle the migration without any downtime and no loss of order or customer information despite the fact that in the propagation period, visitors may visit the new server or the old server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This propagation period is due to the fact that DNS servers around the globe may have cached your old DNS record, which points your domain name at your old IP address. These caches can stay alive for up to 48 hours meaning that you can not be certain that a visitor will definitely go to your new server within this period despite the fact that you have updated your domain name to point at your new name servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First - Copy the Files + Database:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you need to copy all of the site files from the old server to the new server. The slowest and least reliable way to do this is via FTP. By using FTP, you have to actually download all the files on your old server to your local PC and then upload those files from your local PC to the new server. This can take a long time, especially the uploading part (thanks to the asynchronous nature of ADSL).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the database you need to create a dump file via the command line or exporting from phpMyAdmin. Like FTP for the files, if you use phpMyAdmin then you have to download the dump file to your local machine and then upload it to the new server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better method for moving the files and database dump is to use SCP to copy files directly from the old server to the new server. I have written an article explaining this technique here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/hosting/basic-server-migration-using-ssh-scp/&#34;&gt;Basic Server Migration Using SSH + SCP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configuring the New Server&lt;/strong&gt;
Unfortunately osCommerce based sites often require register globals to be enabled. They also use the old fashioned long arrays. That means that you will probably need to edit the configuration of the new server to enable these old PHP features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an example vhost.conf (don&amp;rsquo;t forget to create the vhost_ssl.conf with the same settings) for Plesk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;Directory /var/www/vhosts/********.co.uk/httpdocs&amp;gt;
php_admin_value open_basedir /var/www/vhosts/******.co.uk/dbCreds:/var/www/vhosts/******.co.uk/httpdocs:/tmp
AllowOverride All
php_admin_flag register_globals on
php_admin_flag register_long_arrays on
&amp;lt;/Directory&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I have specified a non webaccessible folder called dbCreds which contains the database credentials. I can then simply include this file from within the includes/configure.php and admin/includes/configure.php files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensuring No Loss of Customer or Order Information&lt;/strong&gt;
To make sure that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose any customer or order information, we need to take a couple of extra steps. First though an explanation of what can go wrong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the propagation period, there is a distinct possibility that you will be taking orders on both servers. If you don&amp;rsquo;t take any extra steps, then you might have orders and customers on both servers that have the same id number on the database. This can then make transferring the missing orders from the old server to the new server problematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple solution is to simply edit the autoincrement value on the orders and the customers table. I would normally suggest using a big jump in increment like 1000. This will mean that new orders and customers created on the new server will have id numbers that are 1000 higher than the old server. By doing this, we can then import any missing order and customer information over, safe in the knowledge that the id numbers will not clash. Of course, if you expect to create 1000 orders or customers within a couple of days then you will need to make a bigger increment increase on the new server. You are probably also turning over vast amounts of cash :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the propagation period is over, lets say 3 days after you update your name servers, you can use this little script I created to help you to export the missing orders from your old server to your new server&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://addons.oscommerce.com/info/5958&#34;&gt;Server Migration Orders / Customers Synchronisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Someone To Handle it For You&lt;/strong&gt;
Of course, if you prefer you can book someone to handle the migration for you. If you would like us to take care of your migration, just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-oscommerce-server-migration.html&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>