<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>World on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in World on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 08:42:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>World Clock on Ubuntu - Its As Standard</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/world-clock-on-ubuntu-its-as-standard.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 08:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/world-clock-on-ubuntu-its-as-standard.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We are starting to get more and more international clients primarily from America and Australasia. It&amp;rsquo;s great to be getting a more global market, though keeping track of client&amp;rsquo;s local time is sometimes confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the thought occurs: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m using Linux, there&amp;rsquo;s bound to be an excellent app to help me deal with this&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out there is and its included with Ubuntu as standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desktop clock, normally displayed in the top right actually has functionality to allow you to add as many extra locations as you want, so with a single click you can check the current time in whatever locations you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set these up, simply click the clock which then drops down a calendar view. At the bottom of that view there is a Locations option. Click that to display a map and also an [Edit] button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit the [Edit] button and you can add whatever locations you wish. Once they are set up you can check the local time for any of your locations by simply clicking the clock in the top right again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome. Got to love Ubuntu and Linux :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>