<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: web | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T19:37:13+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prevent zooming in a mobile browser]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/prevent-zooming-in-a-mobile-browser.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-26T14:09:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/prevent-zooming-in-a-mobile-browser</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It may some times be necessary to prevent a user from zooming in on a mobile browser.</p>

<p>This can be done with the following meta tag</p>

<p>```html</p>

<p><meta content='width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0, maximum-scale=1.0, user-scalable=0' name='viewport' />
<meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width" /></p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20project%20management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-04T12:19:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20project%20management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When embarking on a project to launch or relaunch an e-commerce web site it can seem like a daunting and overwhelming prospect. The danger is that without proper planning and project management, the final outcome can be much less effective and efficient than if proper planning and preliminary research is used to define clear goals and then ensure these are met.</p>

<p>In my role as user experience designer, web designer and design project management I always advise clients to follow a clear and defined process to get the best results. The following describes this process in detail. If you have any questions regarding this article or would like to discuss your redesign or launch project with us please <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">do get in touch</a>.</p>

<h3>Project Plan Overview</h3>




<blockquote><em>Abraham Lincoln - If I had six hours to chop down a tree, I'd spend the first four hours sharpening the axe.</em></blockquote>


<p>Planning is extremely important.</p>

<p>From what I&rsquo;ve learned I tend to break down every project in following phases.</p>

<ul>
 <li>1. Research and Planning</li>
 <li>2. Wire-framing</li>
 <li>3. Visual Design</li>
 <li>4. Front-end development</li>
 <li>5. Back-end development</li>
 <li>6. Content entry</li>
 <li>7. Testing</li>
 <li>8. Launch</li>
<li>9. Ongoing Support and Maintainence</li>
</ul>




<h2>Project Phases</h2>


<p>Here is some more details on the specific steps of a project.</p>

<h3>Research and Planning</h3>


<p>This phase is perhaps the most important. Discoveries made here will have a dramatic impact on decisions made later on in the project and the key is to ensure we gather as much high quality information as possible to facilitate the optimum plan for the project.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Requirements gathering – the most important phase. Try to get as much information as possible. It may take a lot of time at the beginning to set clear goals and strategies, but it will speed up the project management later on. That’s why it’s broken down to:

    <ul><li>Business requirements – what are the goals on the project monetization</li></ul>

    <ul><li>Design requirements – are there some special design considerations</li></ul>

    <ul><li>Technology Requirements – are there some limitations to platform or language, etc.</li></ul>

    <ul><li>User Requirements – who is this project created for, what’s the main audience, describe it as detailed as possible and create personas.</li></li></ul></ul>


<pre><code>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Industry best practices / reports – see what’s already out there, what kind of research is available to speed up the learning curve. This step gathers very important information on which aspects to focus in competitor analysis.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Competitor analysis – see what strategies main competitors are using, identify their strengths and weaknesses, make short proposal of unique or best approach based on obtained intelligence. It really helps to create a checklist – to which against the competitors are analysed.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Overall Project Planning – after all of the basic information is gathered about the upcoming project, the competitors and the industry closely researched - create a basic proposal of what to include in the project and why (communicate the benefits). This is a good place for short recommendations on features, strategy, frameworks, platform, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
</code></pre>

<p></ul></p>

<h3>Wireframing</h3>


<p>Once the plan is in place we know everything that we want on the site. The next phase is to put together a wireframe (also referred to as a mockup) of the site that arranges the pages and structure of the site with all features. Wireframes are very simple layouts with no advanced colour or visuals and allow us to focus on layout and structure exclusively.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Site map – create a map of all included pages and write short user stories about them. It will play an important role to understand the total volume of the project and organize it. Help yourself as a web project manager - to keep with the plan and make sure that nothing is missed. It is a good visual material to present to your client as well.</li>

    <li>Low-to-High Fidelity Wireframes – Allows to define information hierarchy of each page and visualises the end-user behaviour. Start by determining layout by boxes only, simply play around various sceneries and get client feedback early. After conceptual layout is signed off, proceed to next phase by adding main typography elements and some real content to ensure that both - client and you are on the same track of understanding. Don't worry that already signed off layout needs changes, it's normal to evolve, after all - quality is what matters and the one who changes – survives. Feel free to use colour (I recommend Gray Scale) to set element priority within the wireframe. (For better wire framing and presenting I personally recommend <a href="http://blogs.adobe.com/fireworks/2013/05/the-future-of-adobe-fireworks.html" title="The future of Adobe Fireworks" target="_blank">as Adobe announced to stop further development of Fireworks</a>)</li>

    <li>Functional specification – It’s extremely important to clarify all use sceneries and functions. Like what happens when item is added to cart and so on. Describe and visually enhance specification by adding meaningful images and annotations directly in wire-frames. Make sure to maintain close communication with Client and sign off the stage once it’s done.</li>
</ul>




<h3>Design</h3>


<p>Once the wireframes are completed and signed off with the client, the next phase is to start implementing those layouts as fully fledged visual designs. At this phase things like colour, shape and style become the focus. The design is in no way functional, the result is a flat image that will represent exactly how the web site will look.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Overall design – focus on first page, header and footer. Try to think over all elements and design rules, create the overall feel. This usually takes much longer time than any other section of site.</li>

    <li>Page design – just follow the wire-frames and overall design rules.</li>
</ul>




<h3>Completion</h3>


<p>When the designs are finalised the project passes across to the more technical side of the team for the process of making a live dynamic web site based upon the wireframes and designs.</p>

<p>The front end development phase is the conversion of the design into HTML, CSS and JavaScript that can be rendered in a web browser.</p>

<p>Back end development involves making your CMS system or platform such as Magento or WordPress generate the correct HTML and CSS, generally as part of a custom theme. This phase also includes building any custom functionality that is required or implied by the design.</p>

<p>Once the theme is live, the next phase is to populate the site with content. This could include products and categories, pages and articles or any other content that gives the site its true purpose and structure.</p>

<p>The final step before launch is to thoroughly test the site in a secure staging environment. Staging environments should be password protected with no chance of search engine spiders discovering and indexing the site before launch.</p>

<p>Once all parties are happy that the site is working perfectly, the final step is to launch the site. This generally involves deploying code and database to a live web server. Often this phase also includes some server setup and optimisation to ensure the site is working perfectly.</p>

<p>Once the site is launched, a phase of ongoing support and maintenance ensues which may last for weeks, months or indefinitely depending on the scale of the site and your ambitions for future growth and improvements.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>


<p>These are few of the basic guidelines for effective web project management. I don&rsquo;t insist that this is the one and the only right approach, it&rsquo;s just the approach that helps me to get the project done to the highest standards.</p>

<p>This approach is constantly evolving as new techniques and tools are discovered. I haven&rsquo;t gone into the details of development, testing and launch phases as this article is mostly focused on design and planning phases which is my primary role.</p>

<p>If you would like to discuss your redesign, relaunch or new site launch project with Edmonds Commerce please <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch today</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Magento: App, Responsive Theme or Mobile Version]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/mobile-magento-app-responsive-theme-or-mobile-version.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-07T18:06:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/mobile-magento-app-responsive-theme-or-mobile-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mobile internet usage is perhaps one of the defining revolutions of this decade.</p>

<p>People love how quick and easy it is to quickly look up something on their mobile that they carry around 24/7.</p>

<p>Signs of mobile usage are now all around us. People scroll through websites on tablets, smartphones, notebooks and other web-enabled mobile devices to pass their time.</p>

<p>According to the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-14731757" target="_blank">BBC</a>, almost 50% of people have used the internet whilst away from their computer in a survey last year. In fact that article was published in 2011 so the reality now is probably much higher.</p>

<p>Have a look at these statistics which clearly show how mobile use is climbing year on year and now well over 10% of total usage:</p>

<iframe width="600" height="570" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="" id="na634982574962912257"></iframe>


<script type="text/javascript">document.getElementById("na634982574962912257").src="http://netmarketshare.com/report.aspx?qprid=61"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qptimeframe=M"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpsp=164"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpnp=6"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpch=350"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpdt=1"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpct=4"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpcid=fw486185"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpf=16"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpwidth=600"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpdisplay=1111"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpmr=10"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"site="+window.location.hostname</script>


<p>So if you are wanting to increase access to your site this is definitely something to consider!</p>

<h3>Developing World</h3>


<p>Mobile use is truly becoming a global phenomenon. Whilst China and India have the majority of mobile connections, the use of mobile phones by developing nations is also under a period of rapid growth.</p>

<p>Many people in the developing world are unable to buy or charge a computer but they can afford to use internet on their phone; they often lack a wired internet infrastructure, however the mobile technology is much easier to implement.</p>

<h3>Mcommerce</h3>


<p>As people have more access to sites on their phones, it is not surprising that they want to buy the things that they see on their phones.</p>

<p>According to a <a href="http://www.sas.com/offices/europe/uk/downloads/press/sas-verdict-retail2012.pdf" target="_blank">report by SAS and Verdict Consulting</a> survey m-Commerce &ldquo;is growing fast and will become an integral part of shopping for all ages –
retailers need mobile capability to engage with shoppers as well as sell to them.&rdquo;</p>

<h3>App</h3>


<p>Building Apps is quite a bespoke task which means you can modify your app to your specific modifications.</p>

<p>However designing the app means that you need to create it individually for each type of device, so this can become expensive as you will need at the least both an iOS (iPhone etc) app and also an Android app. You might also want a Windows Phone app giving you a total of three separate apps that need to be coded.</p>

<p>The popularity of mobile Apps has not gone unnoticed by Magento themselves as they have launched their own Magento mobile integration.</p>

<p>If you would like to find out more about Magento mobile app capability <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/product/mobile">here is the link to their website.</a></p>

<h3>Mobile Version of your Website</h3>


<p>Rather than opting for an app, we always recommend that instead you focus on having a mobile friendly web site.</p>

<p>There are two ways to optimise your site for mobile devices: these are responsive themes and mobile versions. They have positive points and drawbacks and it really depends on what you are looking for.</p>

<p>We offer both types of mobile optimisation so whatever option you decide, we are happy to implement it.</p>

<p>Just in case you are not sure about what the differences between responsive themes and mobile versions is, I shall give some more detail on this below.</p>

<h3>Responsive Theme</h3>


<p>Responsive themes are basically your current website but with the capability to scale itself to the size of a mobile device. The idea is rather than having one web page you can shape,size and place the elements of your site to fit any size browser.</p>

<p>According to <a href="http://googlemobileads.blogspot.co.uk/2012/07/mobile-websites-vs-responsive-design.html" title="Google" target="_blank">google</a> responsive themes are great for SEOs and for ease of updating the site. This may be because they minimise bounce rate which means it minimises problems of when a visitor presses the back button when the site is unresponsive. This in turn will improve your site ranking. Another SEO benefit is that it directs the user to one URL.  It is also easier to update than a mobile version of your site.</p>

<h3>Mobile Version</h3>


<p>A mobile version is literally a completely different website. This means that you can edit your site to be completely how you want it rather than tweak an existing site. The disadvantages of this is that it can time consuming and expensive.</p>

<p>A mobile version is served up as a completely alternative version of your website if a mobile user agent is detected. For Magento there are some modules that do a nice job of offering a fairly bog standard mobile version which is optimised for slow connections etc. These days with large screen powerful smartphones running on 3G networks, the issues that prompted the mobile version are less of an issue so we tend to lean more towards the responsive strategy these days.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>


<p>To summarise it is a great idea to optimise your site with mobile capability so that your customers can properly view your site. Responsive themes are best if you want to have a mobile version of your site that is easier, quicker and cheaper to update, while mobile versions are better if your aims are to have a bespoke mobile version of your site that you would not need to update regularly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend Certified Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/zend-certified-developers.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-25T11:24:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/zend-certified-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Edmonds Commerce employs a team of specialist PHP web developers who are all Zend Certified Engineers. This is a highly respected PHP qualification that ensures the highest standards of PHP development expertise. By achieving this certification we ensure that our developers have the kind of well rounded and deep understanding of the PHP language that can be utilised to achieve the highest quality production.</p>

<p>All of the e-commerce platforms, such as Magento and OpenCart are written in PHP and so the first thing to be sure of when you have a developer working on your projects is that they are very skilled in PHP itself as well as having an expert knowledge of the platform.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb3.png"></p>

<p>You can read all about the <a href="http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/" title="ZCE information" target="_blank">ZCE exam here</a>.</p>

<p>In a nutshell the exam is designed to test knowledge and skill that a professional PHP developer would need to tackle the kind of day to day issues they are likely to face. The exam covers a broad range of topics and really tests the in depth and broad knowledge of PHP that is required to really get the most out of the language and deliver the highest quality PHP development.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sticky page scrolling in JavaScript with JQuery]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/sticky-page-scrolling-in-javascript-with-jquery.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-20T17:35:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/sticky-page-scrolling-in-javascript-with-jquery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a page that keeps getting longer because new items appear on it at the bottom and what&rsquo;s at the bottom of the page is most important it can be a paint to have to keep scrolling done to see it.</p>

<p>You can make it auto scroll continuously with JQuery but that&rsquo;s potentially really awkward if at any point you need to scroll up (it basically means you can&rsquo;t).</p>

<p>The best solution is to make the page auto scroll in a sticky fashion. So when the page is already scrolled all the way to the bottom it auto scrolls, when it&rsquo;s not at the bottom it does not scroll.</p>

<p>This can be achieved quite easily with the following code:
```javascript</p>

<p>var num = (lastDocumentHeight &ndash; $(window).height()) &ndash; $(document).scrollTop();
if(num == 0) {</p>

<pre><code>$(&amp;quot;html, body&amp;quot;).animate({ scrollTop: $(document).height() }, &amp;quot;slow&amp;quot;);
</code></pre>

<p>}
lastDocumentHeight = $(document).height();</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>In this example lastDocumentHeight is a global. It works by determining if the current position is the same as it was previously and this position equates to being at the bottom of the page then scroll. This needs to run after your page length has increased.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
