<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dedicated Server on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/dedicated-server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dedicated Server on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 06:50:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/dedicated-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How 10,000 Geeks break the UK&#39;s biggest distributors, RS and Farnell (Raspberry Pi)</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 06:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, 6am this morning (Wed 29 2012), a bunch of geeks eagerly awaiting the Raspberry Pi have killed the websites of both RS Components and Farnell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, you ask? Because the servers were not prepared for the influx of visitors that such an announcement brings.  Raspberry Pi themselves (a UK Foundation, like a Charity) were well prepared and are presently serving up a static page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you&amp;rsquo;re running an eCommerce site, like Magento or osCommerce, and are warned by one of your suppliers, or your manufacturing department that you&amp;rsquo;re launching a new product, be prepared.  Raspberry Pi certainly were and provided their suppliers with the information that they would be getting a huge amount of traffic, unfortunately those suppliers didn&amp;rsquo;t listen hard enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is to all intents a DDoS attack, but not an intentional attack.  Well done for keeping everyone updated via twitter though @raspberrypi, we know it isn&amp;rsquo;t your fault.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>