<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tkman on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/tkman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tkman on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 07:12:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/tkman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>TkMan Linux Man Pages GUI Tool</title>
      <link>http://example.com/linux/tkman-linux-man-pages-gui-tool.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 07:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/linux/tkman-linux-man-pages-gui-tool.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Want to browse your man pages but not in the console?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can of course hit the search engines but its got to be better to be looking at your own man pages so you know the instructions are for your machine, version etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
sudo apt-get install tkman

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you have a simple but useful man page reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to get dropped into the applications menu so you can add it manually by right clicking the Applications menu, selecting Edit Menus then go to System Tools and then hit the Add Item button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the title to Man Page Reader and the command as tkman. You can choose whatever icon you prefer by clicking the springboard icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you launch it, I found it a lot nicer to switch the fonts to arial and normal weight across the board. Its worth messing around with the other options as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>