<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hd on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/hd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hd on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 17:35:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/hd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu VirtualBox Clone VDI / Hard Disk</title>
      <link>http://example.com/ubuntu/ubuntu-virtualbox-clone-vdi-hard-disk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 17:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/ubuntu/ubuntu-virtualbox-clone-vdi-hard-disk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are using VirtualBox in Ubuntu for your virtual machine requirements, some times you might decide that you want to clone a machine so that you can have different versions of the OS (perhaps running different browser versions for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clone the VDI you need to first of all completely shutdown the virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you need to go to File-&amp;gt;Virtual Media Manager and Release the VDI that you want to clone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you need to open a terminal and type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
cd ~/.VirtualBox/HardDisks/

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to figure out which VDI you want to clone (lets assume xp.vdi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you need to run this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
VBoxManage clonehd xp.vdi cloned_xp.vdi

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now back into the VirtualBox GUI, you need to go back to the Virtual Media Manager and click the Add icon and add your newly created cloned VDI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you create a new VM as normal, but when you get to the Hard Disk part of the wizard, select the use existing hard disk option and select your new VDI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>