<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Checkout on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/checkout/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Checkout on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 17:34:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/checkout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Way to Simplify Git Merges</title>
      <link>http://example.com/git/a-great-way-to-simplify-git-merges.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 17:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/git/a-great-way-to-simplify-git-merges.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are struggling with a git merge with a long list of failed merge files then this little trick might be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard approach is to go file by file and use git mergetool to open the files in a tool like Meld and then manually manage the differences. In many cases though you know exactly which version you want and this is simply a laborious process that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really require human input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution to this is deceptively simple. All you need to do is to check out the file from the branch you want to keep the version of. If you have an entire directory where you know that the branch (for example master) has the correct version then you can check out that entire directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might find that sensible use of this technique can save you lots of time and really make the mergetool the one you use for the files where you really do need to merge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/914939/simple-tool-to-accept-theirs-or-accept-mine-on-a-whole-file-using-git?answertab=active#tab-top&#34;&gt;this StackOverflow answer&lt;/a&gt; for simplifying this for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Checkout &#34;undefined&#34; Pop Up &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-checkout-undefined-pop-up-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 16:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-checkout-undefined-pop-up-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are struggling to understand why you are getting a popup on the Magento checkout with the simple message &amp;ldquo;undefined&amp;rdquo; then here is what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use Fire Fox and install the extension Firebug&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Switch Firebug on and go to the console tab&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hit the place order button and you will see the HTML response to the AJAX request (how did we cope with AJAX before Firebug!!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should then see a meaningful error message telling you what is causing the problem and hopefully help you to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce Checkout Problems &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://example.com/oscommerce/oscommerce-checkout-problems-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 10:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/oscommerce/oscommerce-checkout-problems-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If your osCommerce checkout starts behaving badly and bits of info seem to go missing eg billing address then you should definitely try this fix before you tear your hair out completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most osCommerce installs store session information to a MySQL table called (suprisingly) sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes (I have only seen this twice on umpteen osCommerce sites) the sessions table will become corrupted. The irritating thing is that if this happens it seems that the site will not stop working completely with a useful error message, but instead will continue to work but will behave very strangely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your osCommerce site is behaving strangely then try this fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open phpMyAdmin and select your SQL database and then copy and paste the following into the SQL section and hit run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;REPAIR TABLE `sessions`;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Checkout Empties Basket &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-checkout-empties-basket-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 13:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-checkout-empties-basket-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A client recently experienced an issue where certain customers were having issues with the checkout redirecting people to the homepage instead of letting them checkout as normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing some research the client found that the issue is related to a security setting in Magento. Magento uses the IP address of a user as part of its session validation. This is perfectly reasonable approach and helps protect against XSS among other things. However it seems certain ISP&amp;rsquo;s (AOL as usual) actually rotate the IP&amp;rsquo;s that customers connections come from, which makes Magento think that the session is being hijacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can disable this security setting by doing the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Change the Session Validation settings in the Magento Admin, found under System &amp;gt; Configurations &amp;gt; Web,  to ‘no’ on everything except “Validate HTTP_USER_AGENT.” After doing this,  go to System &amp;gt; Cache Management and refresh the configuration cache to apply the changes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
(originally found &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewellrunsite.com/2009/02/12/fixing-the-magento-checkout-glitch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to blog about this one as it seems this would be a good idea to change on all Magento installations and by blogging about it I will remember.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>