<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: chrome | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/chrome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-07T10:56:25+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting rid of the chain of quoted replies in Gmail]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/getting-rid-of-the-chain-of-quoted-replies-in-gmail.html"/>
    <updated>2015-03-02T19:02:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/getting-rid-of-the-chain-of-quoted-replies-in-gmail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The problem with quoted replies</h2>

<p>One of Gmail&rsquo;s stronger features is its threaded email conversations, allowing you to see emails as a chain of the back-and-forth, instead of the classic Inbox and Sent folder situation.</p>

<p>Mail clients often include the email chain as part of the email itself, and for the most part these are marked up in such a way that Gmail can hide them with the small ellipses button.</p>

<p>Sometimes though this doesn&rsquo;t work, and you end up having to scroll past page after page of quoted replies, which can be a right pain.</p>

<p>In probably 75% of the cases these have some HTML wrapped around them, which we can use to hide them when needed.</p>

<h2>Using Stylish to hide them in your browser</h2>

<p>Because Gmail is a web-based client, you can use normal browser extensions to manipulate it. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stylish">Stylish</a> is a browser extension that allows you to set up CSS rules that are applied on the pages you&rsquo;re using.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a snippet of CSS that will hide the needless quoted replies, with the ability to hover over them if you really need to see them</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>// Make quoted replies a small block
.im, .gmail_extra {
  height:30px;
  width:100px;
  background:#EFEFEF;
  overflow:hidden;
  display:block;
}</p>

<p>// Allow these to be expanded when hovered
.im:hover,
.gmail_extra:hover
{
  height:auto;
  max-height:250px;
  width:auto;
  overflow:auto;
  background:#EFEFEF;
}</p>

<p>// Show a little notice that they can be expanded
.im:before, .gmail_extra:before {
  content:&ldquo;Snipped Quote, hover to expand&rdquo;;
  color:#666666;
}</p>

<p>// Don&rsquo;t hide nested quote blocks
.im .im,
.gmail_extra .gmail_extra,
.im .gmail_extra,
.gmail_extra .im</p>

<pre><code>  {
</code></pre>

<p>  height:auto;
  max-height:none;
  width:auto;
  overflow:auto;
  background:#EFEFEF;
}</p>

<p>.gmail_extra .im:before {
  content:&ldquo;&rdquo;;
}</p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>The result</h2>

<p>What was previously a big mess of nested quotes and signatures</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2015-03-02-GmailQuote1.png"></p>

<p>Becomes a small &ldquo;Hover to expand&rdquo; box</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2015-03-02-GmailQuote2.png"></p>

<p>Viewing it in the scrollable box</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2015-03-02-GmailQuote3.png"></p>

<p>These styles work at the date of publication, but obviously Google might change the classes used for these.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behat Selenium arguments[0] is undefined Problem + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/behat/behat-selenium-arguments-0-is-undefined-problem-plus-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2015-02-17T12:33:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/behat/behat-selenium-arguments-0-is-undefined-problem-plus-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just spent a good amount of time struggling to see why my perfectly functional looking code was not working.</p>

<p>Tests were failing with the error message:</p>

<p><em>arguments[0] is undefined</em></p>

<p>A little bit of Googling later and I found the issue.</p>

<p>It seems that some Firefox versions will bomb out and give you this error message.</p>

<p>The simple solution, if you can, is to switch to using Chrome and Chromedriver</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSL testing and SHA-1 Sunsetting]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/ssl-testing-and-sha-1-sunsetting.html"/>
    <updated>2014-11-12T13:03:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/ssl-testing-and-sha-1-sunsetting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over last few days we been doing a bit of work on doing some audits for people and one of the things that has come up is ssl. For the purpose of checking the servers ssl implementation we have been using <a href="https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/">Qualys SSL Labs</a> which is a excelent tool.</p>

<p>The checker checks for the ssl certificate and tells you if your server setup is vulnerable to attacks such as Poodle and OpenSSL CCS Injection. We will produce a blog post shortly on the best practise setup to prevent these attcks.</p>

<p>For the moment SHA-1 as a certificate signature algorithm is getting depricated in <a href="https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2014/09/09/sha1-deprecation-what-you-need-to-know">chrome</a>. As the cost for collision attcks against SHA-1 will become more <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2012/10/when_will_we_se.html">affordable</a> in the next few years.</p>

<p>Goole have set the cut off for certificates after 2016 but we will be seeing some crosses on the padlock in chrom during the first quater of 2015.</p>

<p>If your certificate expires in 2015 then you will not see any chrome. If your certificate expires in 2016 you will see some minor errors being reported in chrome. However if your certificate expires in 2017 then chrome will treat it as an insecure certificate in 2015.</p>

<p>So our advice is:</p>

<ul>
<li>If your certificate expires in 2015: When you come to renew make sure you get SHA-256 as the certificate signature</li>
<li>If your certificate expires in 2016: Think about getting renewed during 2015 or earlier.</li>
<li>If your certificate expires in 2017: Think about getting a new one issue as soon as possible.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mute Chrome/Chromium in Gnome Shell]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/mute-chrome-slash-chromium-in-gnome-shell.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T10:09:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/mute-chrome-slash-chromium-in-gnome-shell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You might not be aware that in Gnome Shell and likely anything else using Linux you can easily block sound from entire applications.</p>

<p>For me this means blocking annoying auto playing videos with sound that are cropping up as I&rsquo;m trying to listen to some nice tunes whilst I work.</p>

<p>To block the sound is very easy, simply go to the sound control panel which in Gnome Shell is access via the top right panel.</p>

<p>Once into the sound section, go to the right most tab where you can control sounds on an application by application basis. Simply turn off the annoying onces.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/mute-chromium.png"></p>

<p>Beautiful :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disable JavaScript alerts for a page]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/disable-javascript-alerts-for-a-page.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-28T09:21:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/disable-javascript-alerts-for-a-page</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you encounter a webpage that is generating a lot of alerts, the following bookmark will prevent them from stealing focus but still allow you to see what is being said.</p>

<p>```js</p>

<p>javascript:alert = function ( text ) { console.log( text ); return true; };</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
