<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: chrome | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/chrome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-14T13:45:08+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSL testing and SHA-1 Sunsetting]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/ssl-testing-and-sha-1-sunsetting.html"/>
    <updated>2014-11-12T13:03:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/ssl-testing-and-sha-1-sunsetting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over last few days we been doing a bit of work on doing some audits for people and one of the things that has come up is ssl. For the purpose of checking the servers ssl implementation we have been using <a href="https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/">Qualys SSL Labs</a> which is a excelent tool.</p>

<p>The checker checks for the ssl certificate and tells you if your server setup is vulnerable to attacks such as Poodle and OpenSSL CCS Injection. We will produce a blog post shortly on the best practise setup to prevent these attcks.</p>

<p>For the moment SHA-1 as a certificate signature algorithm is getting depricated in <a href="https://community.qualys.com/blogs/securitylabs/2014/09/09/sha1-deprecation-what-you-need-to-know">chrome</a>. As the cost for collision attcks against SHA-1 will become more <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2012/10/when_will_we_se.html">affordable</a> in the next few years.</p>

<p>Goole have set the cut off for certificates after 2016 but we will be seeing some crosses on the padlock in chrom during the first quater of 2015.</p>

<p>If your certificate expires in 2015 then you will not see any chrome. If your certificate expires in 2016 you will see some minor errors being reported in chrome. However if your certificate expires in 2017 then chrome will treat it as an insecure certificate in 2015.</p>

<p>So our advice is:</p>

<ul>
<li>If your certificate expires in 2015: When you come to renew make sure you get SHA-256 as the certificate signature</li>
<li>If your certificate expires in 2016: Think about getting renewed during 2015 or earlier.</li>
<li>If your certificate expires in 2017: Think about getting a new one issue as soon as possible.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mute Chrome/Chromium in Gnome Shell]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/mute-chrome-slash-chromium-in-gnome-shell.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T10:09:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/mute-chrome-slash-chromium-in-gnome-shell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You might not be aware that in Gnome Shell and likely anything else using Linux you can easily block sound from entire applications.</p>

<p>For me this means blocking annoying auto playing videos with sound that are cropping up as I&rsquo;m trying to listen to some nice tunes whilst I work.</p>

<p>To block the sound is very easy, simply go to the sound control panel which in Gnome Shell is access via the top right panel.</p>

<p>Once into the sound section, go to the right most tab where you can control sounds on an application by application basis. Simply turn off the annoying onces.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/mute-chromium.png"></p>

<p>Beautiful :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disable JavaScript alerts for a page]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/disable-javascript-alerts-for-a-page.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-28T09:21:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/disable-javascript-alerts-for-a-page</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you encounter a webpage that is generating a lot of alerts, the following bookmark will prevent them from stealing focus but still allow you to see what is being said.</p>

<p>```js</p>

<p>javascript:alert = function ( text ) { console.log( text ); return true; };</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easily Test Mobile Version of your Site with Chrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/easily-test-mobile-version-of-your-site-with-chrome.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T15:33:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/easily-test-mobile-version-of-your-site-with-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have opted to have a customised mobile theme displayed for mobile users of your web site then it can be useful to be able to test this theme from the desktop. This is quite simple to do and there are plugins for most browsers. These days though Chrome users have this functionality built in, and quite nicely as well.</p>

<p>To access a mobile version of a site simply open Chrome and navigate to the site you would like to view in mobile version.</p>

<p>Then hit F12 to bring up the developer tools. Alternatively you can go to the right hand menu and select developer tools under the tools menu. This should bring up a screen looking similar to this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-162921-600x475.png"></p>

<p>In the bottom right hand corner of this screen you will see a little cog icon, please click that:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-162956.png"></p>

<p>This gives you the overrides menu where you can select the phone you want to emulate. You can also tick the device metrics box so that the displayable area corresponds to that of the phone giving you a good emultation of the phone experience.<img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-163013-600x354.png"></p>

<p>Tick the box next to User Agent and choose a phone.</p>

<p>Once you have selected the phone you want to emulate under the &ldquo;user agent&rdquo; section and also optionally ticked the box next to &ldquo;Device metrics&rdquo; then you can reload the page (hit [ctrl] + [f5]) and the page will be reloaded and should show you the mobile version of your site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add Jquery to Any Page via Console]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/add-jquery-to-any-page-via-console.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T18:44:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/add-jquery-to-any-page-via-console</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you might want to do a little on the fly DOM editing using your favourite Javascript library &ndash; jQuery.</p>

<p>To do this you might need to include jQuery on the page, you can do this by pasting these lines into your console in Chrome or Firebug in Firefox.</p>

<pre class="lang:js decode:true " title="Run this in your console" >var jq = document.createElement('script');
jq.src = "http://code.jquery.com/jquery-latest.min.js";
document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0].appendChild(jq);
jQuery.noConflict();
</pre>


<p></p>

<p>And there you have it, the full power of jQuery at your fingertips</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
