<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: exam | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/exam/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-11T11:25:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend Certified Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/zend-certified-developers.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-25T11:24:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/zend-certified-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Edmonds Commerce employs a team of specialist PHP web developers who are all Zend Certified Engineers. This is a highly respected PHP qualification that ensures the highest standards of PHP development expertise. By achieving this certification we ensure that our developers have the kind of well rounded and deep understanding of the PHP language that can be utilised to achieve the highest quality production.</p>

<p>All of the e-commerce platforms, such as Magento and OpenCart are written in PHP and so the first thing to be sure of when you have a developer working on your projects is that they are very skilled in PHP itself as well as having an expert knowledge of the platform.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb3.png"></p>

<p>You can read all about the <a href="http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/" title="ZCE information" target="_blank">ZCE exam here</a>.</p>

<p>In a nutshell the exam is designed to test knowledge and skill that a professional PHP developer would need to tackle the kind of day to day issues they are likely to face. The exam covers a broad range of topics and really tests the in depth and broad knowledge of PHP that is required to really get the most out of the language and deliver the highest quality PHP development.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Certified Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-certified-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T15:18:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-certified-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/Magento-Certified-Developer.png"> I&rsquo;m really happy to announce that two of our team have now taken and passed the Magento Certified Developer exam. This means that they are now officially &ldquo;Magento Certified Developers&rdquo;.</p>

<p>What that means for you is that you can be assured that we have the in house skills and experience to work the right way with Magento and really help you get the most out of the platform.</p>

<p>The reason we finally put them forward for the exam is that, after working with the platform for a few years now, we have decided to go down the official Magento partner route and get all the qualification and assurance that you could ask for by becoming an Silver Magento Partner and employing developers who are not only <a href="http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/" title="Zend Certified Developer information" target="_blank">Zend Certified Engineer</a>s &ndash; a PHP qualification &ndash; but also Magento Certified Developers.</p>

<p>The exam asks questions on a wide range of Magento topics ranging from the basics through to layout, rendering and then more complex subjects such as the checkout, sales, API and more. You can download the official <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/certification/" title="Magento certification information" target="_blank">Magento Certified Developer study guide</a> to see the full details of the areas that are discussed though suffice to say it is really quite in depth and broad. You definitely need to know Magento well to pass the exam.</p>

<p>For those that care the passing mark for the exam is 37 out of 70 questions. Our devs passed with 54/70 and 52/70 so really nailed it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
