<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: live deployment | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/live-deployment/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-24T10:48:18+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quickly make a deploy folder from git]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/quickly-make-a-deploy-folder-from-git.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-14T17:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/quickly-make-a-deploy-folder-from-git</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>I needed to quickly generate a deploy folder that included all changes in the last two weeks. Using git and a little bit of bash magic I was able to put together a one liner to do this.</p>

<p>This works we use a public folder within our git structure which makes filtering the files easy, if you don&rsquo;t have this then you will have to change the grep filter to match your needs. Obviously you can change the since filter to get the files you need.</p>

<p><code>git log &mdash;since=&ldquo;2 weeks ago&rdquo; &mdash;name-status | grep public | sort | uniq | awk &lsquo;{print $2}&rsquo; | xargs -I % cp &mdash;parents % /path/to/deploy</code></p>

<p>Hope this helps in the future</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kevin Mayhew]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T14:24:14+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<h2>Magento Site Upgrade</h2>


<p>Kevin Mayhew Ltd. required their Magento site to be upgraded from Enterprise 1.7 to the current release. They are looking to do this because the current site is having problems with some of the functionality which can only be correct by upgrading an extension and the extensions latest version is not compatibility with 1.7. 1.7 is also preventing them from improving the site and adding functionality. This mainly involved updating their site templates to function correctly the the new release as well as resolving issues related to old/new extensions.</p>

<h3>Kevin Mayhew</h3>


<p>Kevin Mayhew is a Christian religious product and music retailer, Christian church resource supplier and Christian book publisher.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/kevinmayhew1-300x216.png"></p>

<p>This project went really well with the pushing to live been successful. With the site now running the latest version of Magento the company can look forward toward to expanding the functionality of the site as well as resolving issues the old site was having.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
