<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: remote | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/remote/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-14T17:47:11+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wget For Beginners]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/wget-for-beginners.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T08:02:25+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/wget-for-beginners</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>What is Wget in general ?</h3>


<p>Wget is a free utility for non-interactive download of file from the web. The user doesn’t need to login system every time <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/wget/" rel="nofollow">Wget</a> can download the entire web page or mirroring the entire web page. If download crashed or stop for various reason Wget will start download again from where it stopped. It is highly recommended for downloading file from web with slow network connections.</p>

<h2>How to Use Wget ? </h2>


<p>```php</p>

<p>wget -t 10 www.google.com</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If network connection fails Wget will to try to reconnect 20 times in default.With -t command we can specify how many times it need to  reconnect.</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>wget -p &mdash;convert-links -r www.google.com -o logfile</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This command will download the site -p and &mdash;convert will make sure all linked files are linked to downloaded document such as images and external links it enables complete offline viewing. Log file can be enabled with -O command to view the output message.</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>wget &mdash;spider &mdash;force-html www.google.com</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>&mdash;spider Will check the webpage is existent or not.
&mdash;force  It will enforce the file type that have to be downloaded.</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>wget -u mozilla www.google.com</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>some site access allowed to certain user <a href="http://www.user-agents.org/" rel="nofollow">agents</a>. So to access with certain user agent you can use this command.</p>

<p>Ftp connection download is achieved by</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>wget -r <a href="ftp://username:password@ftp.example.com">ftp://username:password@ftp.example.com</a></p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rsync For Beginners]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/rsync-for-beginners-2.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T16:42:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/rsync-for-beginners-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>What is Rsync in general ?</h3>


<p>Rsync works like the <a href="http://linux.about.com/od/commands/l/blcmdl1_rcp.htm" rel="nofollow">rcp</a> command in linux. It is used to copy files across machines. It uses efficient checksum algorithm that looks for modified files by time and size. It is used for two purposes:</p>

<h2>Backup</h2>


<p>Rsync is used to transfer file from the local to a remote machine. By default Rsync will use rsh, however you can instead use <a href="http://linux.about.com/od/commands/l/blcmdl1_ssh.htm" rel="nofollow">ssh</a> for high security. Compressed files are transferred to save file transfer time and reduce the load on the network. It helps to transfer bulk files in minutes.</p>

<h2>Mirroring</h2>


<p>Rsync can synchronize file between two servers location(i.e) local and remote. By using the checksum algorithm it updates local files only if it is updated in remote server.</p>

<h3>How to use Rsync</h3>


<p>
```php</p>

<p>rsync -avze ssh -p2020 root@server.com:/sitepath/files   /localdata</p>

<p>```
This command transfer files from remote server to local machine.</p>

<p>a  Archive. It is denotes all related files and documents.
v  Verbose.It will display status message as it is processing.
z  Compression.It achives better compression ratio.
e  It allows to chose alternative remote shell program for communication.</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>rsync -avze ssh -p2020 &mdash;exclude home/var/cache root@server.com:/sitepath/files /localdata</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This command will transfer files from remote server to local machine by excluding cache folder.</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>rsync -avz /sitepath/files root@server.com:/localdata</p>

<p>```
This command will  transfer all file from local to remote server. It is uses default remote shell protocol.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netbeans + Xdebug Not Highlighting Lines or Opening Files when Step Through Debugging + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/netbeans-xdebug-not-highlighting-lines-or-opening-files-when-step-through-debugging-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-14T10:27:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/netbeans-xdebug-not-highlighting-lines-or-opening-files-when-step-through-debugging-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you use Netbeans along with Xdebug to facilitate step through debugging when coding PHP then you may come across this issue.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s possible to get it into a semi working scenario where you can have working breakpoints and see variable values but you have no idea which bit of code you are actually stepped up to.</p>

<p>This can happen if your server path and project path are not correctly configured.</p>

<p>To resolve this simply go to your project properties, run configuration and then hit the advanced button.</p>

<p>The server path should be the absolute path to the project root on the server (eg /home/server/sites/blah/) and the project path should be the path on your local machine to the project files (eg /home/joseph/projects/blah/).</p>

<p>Stop any debugging sessions and then start another one up and if you have the paths set right, you should get the behaviour you expect where Netbeans highlights the current line of code and allows you to step through the code to figure out what&rsquo;s going on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy Filesharing in Linux (and Fast and Secure) using SSHFS]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/easy-filesharing-in-linux-and-fast-and-secure-using-sshfs.html"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T13:44:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/easy-filesharing-in-linux-and-fast-and-secure-using-sshfs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are frustrated with Samba and would like something a bit more solid and speedier whilst being very easy to set up, check out SSHFS.</p>

<p>To install it you simply need to do</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>sudo apt-get install sshfs</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Once that&rsquo;s done you can mount a remote filesystem in a very similar way to accessing a remote machine via SSH</p>

<p>eg</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>Mount</h1>

<p>sshfs  -p2020 -o idmap=user $USER@laptop.com:/home/joseph/Projects ~/Mounts/Laptop/Projects</p>

<h1>Unmount</h1>

<p>fusermount -u ~/Mounts/Laptop/Projects</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You need to have previously created the local folder you are going to mount to (in this case /home/joseph/Mounts/Laptop/Projects)</p>

<p>Note also I am using a non standard SSH port with the -p2020 bit (using port 2020). If you are using standard SSH ports you can remove this, or of course change the port number to whatever you prefer.</p>

<p><a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SSHFS"><a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SSHFS">https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SSHFS</a> for more info</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
