<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Retail on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/retail/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Retail on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:14:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/retail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Play.com to Go Marketplace Only - Abandoning Retail Completely</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most online merchants who are into multichannel selling (that&amp;rsquo;s all of you, right?) must have heard of Play.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never quite up there with Amazon and Ebay it was often the one that merchants asked us to integrate with once the two big ones were taken care of. Play was originally a pure online retailer but decided a few years ago to jump on the marketplace bandwagon like market leaders Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it seems Play have been bought out by a Japanese company and thanks to a lucrative VAT loophole being closed (and rightly so) they have now decided to abandon retail sales completely and concentrate purely on their marketplace business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about it here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042&#34;&gt;http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it might be worth checking out their current clearance for particularly good offers as well from a punters point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Mayhew</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 14:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magento Site Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Mayhew Ltd. required their Magento site to be upgraded from Enterprise 1.7 to the current release. They are looking to do this because the current site is having problems with some of the functionality which can only be correct by upgrading an extension and the extensions latest version is not compatibility with 1.7. 1.7 is also preventing them from improving the site and adding functionality. This mainly involved updating their site templates to function correctly the the new release as well as resolving issues related to old/new extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Kevin Mayhew&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Mayhew is a Christian religious product and music retailer, Christian church resource supplier and Christian book publisher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/kevinmayhew1-300x216.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project went really well with the pushing to live been successful. With the site now running the latest version of Magento the company can look forward toward to expanding the functionality of the site as well as resolving issues the old site was having.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dressnimpress - New Magento Based E-commerce Site Development</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/dressnimpress-new-magento-based-e-commerce-site-development.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 14:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/dressnimpress-new-magento-based-e-commerce-site-development.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are now working on developing a new Magento based e-commerce site for a UK based company called Dressnimpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client specialises in designer clothing for both male and female and will be targeting a world wide marketplace for selling designer clothes covering all the latests and famous brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site will be developed from scratch by implementing designs that have been provided to us by the client. Part of the development process will include building a number of custom extensions to fulfil specific features of the site, customizing specific areas or pages of the site as per design and it will also have to support multiple currencies for the world wide audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>