<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: wine | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/wine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-18T19:29:38+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify + Ubuntu Linux + Pulseaudio - No Sound + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/spotify-ubuntu-linux-pulseaudio-no-sound-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-06-18T10:51:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/spotify-ubuntu-linux-pulseaudio-no-sound-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you use Spotify (its awesome I&rsquo;m a big fan) but don&rsquo;t use one of their chosen operating systems (win/mac) and use Linux instead then you might think its unavailable to you.</p>

<p>In fact its fairly trivial to get it working.</p>

<p>First &ndash; follow the instructions on the spotify website to install Wine and install onto that.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.spotify.com/int/help/faq/wine/">http://www.spotify.com/int/help/faq/wine/</a></p>

<p>Note though, the instructions don&rsquo;t mention that you have to mark the spotify.exe file as executable before you can install it. (Dead easy, right click, properties, permissions, tick the box for allow executing as a programme).</p>

<p>Once its installed though, you might find that there is no sound. If like me you use Pulse Audio (is this actually standard with Ubuntu now, I&rsquo;m not sure &ndash; I&rsquo;ve been using it for a while) then you will need to take this extra step.</p>

<ol>
<li>In the command line, type:
<code>
padsp winecfg
</code></li>
</ol>


<p>This will bring up the Wine configuration controls. Make sure you have ticked the OSS audio driver box.</p>

<ol>
<li>In the Applications menu, go to Wine &ndash;> Programs then right click on the Spotify launcher and click &ldquo;add to panel&rdquo;</li>
</ol>


<p>This will then put a Spotify Icon on your panel which is a nice shortcut.</p>

<ol>
<li>On the panel, right click the new shortcut and select properties.</li>
</ol>


<p>In the command box, you should have something like this:</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>env WINEPREFIX=&ldquo;/home/#####/.wine&rdquo; wine &ldquo;C:\Program Files\Spotify\spotify.exe&rdquo;</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You just need to add padsp in front of the wine command, so it should look like this:</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>env WINEPREFIX=&ldquo;/home/#####/.wine&rdquo; padsp wine &ldquo;C:\Program Files\Spotify\spotify.exe&rdquo;</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
