<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expiry on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/expiry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expiry on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 14:17:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/expiry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysql Password Expiry - How to Resolve and Then Disable</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql-password-expiry---how-to-resolve-and-then-disable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 14:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql-password-expiry---how-to-resolve-and-then-disable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had the issue that the root user for a MySQL installation had their password expire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently this is a fairly new MySQL feature which is designed to improve security and assist with meeting PCI-DSS requirements. However for this development box, it is not really necessary so I would prefer to disable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue became apparent when trying to log into phpmyadmin and seeing the error message: &amp;ldquo;#1862 - Your password has expired. To log in you must change it using a client that supports expired passwords.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the command line the confusing thing is that you can log in, only when you run a query such as &lt;code&gt;show databases;&lt;/code&gt; do you then get the error message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mysql&amp;gt; show databases;
ERROR 1820 (HY000): You must reset your password using ALTER USER statement before executing this statement.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to fix this, firstly you can just reset your password back to the same one you were already using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;set password = password(&#39;mySecretPass&#39;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then to disable this you can use this query:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alter user &#39;root&#39;@&#39;localhost&#39; password expire never;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>