<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: e-commerce | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/e-commerce/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-28T13:35:12+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sylius E-Commerce based on Symfony]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/sylius-e-commerce-based-on-symfony.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-23T13:48:47+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/sylius-e-commerce-based-on-symfony</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As if there weren&rsquo;t enough!</p>

<p>There is a new contender for the open source e-commerce crown, a platform called <b><a href="http://sylius.com/features" target="_blank">Sylius</a></b>. The thing that makes this one especially interesting is that rather than being built from scratch it is based upon a very well established PHP framework called Symfony. Some would argue that Symfony is the &ldquo;other&rdquo; PHP framework alongside Zend Framework. In fact there are many frameworks however it would be fair to say that Symfony and Zend Framework are the most well established and up to date.</p>

<p>Basing an e-commerce platform upon an existing PHP framework has many advantages including transferrable skills, established best practice structure and also easier access to a wide range of functionality via library components and extensions.</p>

<p>There is another e-commerce platform based upon a PHP framework. It is based upon Zend Framework &ndash; you might have heard of it &ndash; Magento.</p>

<p>It does look very much like Sylius is still quite a new offering and it can not boast the level of maturity and establishment that Magento has achieved. That said, things move quickly in this industry and who knows what will be top dog in the next five years.</p>

<p>If you are considering Sylius for your e-commerce website and would like to find a UK Sylius developer to work with then do get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast E-Commerce Search Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/fast-e-commerce-search-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T10:59:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/fast-e-commerce-search-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the trickiest parts of any e-commerce store to get running quickly is the search results. The problem is compounded for large or complex stores where a database query based search for a multi word search phrase can become a real behemoth of a database query that has to search for each word in a multitude of database tables and columns. Then throw in other issues such as table locking and the performance issues can start to hurt the site as a whole.</p>

<h3>Caching for Performance</h3>


<p>One common solution to scaling up e-commerce stores is to use a variety of methods and levels of caching, from a database query cache right up to a full page caching system perhaps powered by Varnish. This solution works well for product and category pages for which there is a finite number. When it comes to search results pages though, each possible search phrase is a completely separate set of pages. You might be able to keep a warm cache for your most popular search phrases but anything else will be raw results. It will show your server at its worst performance.</p>

<h3>Alternative Enterprise Search Engine</h3>


<p>In this scenario it is time to start looking at other search solutions. If you want a turnkey professional solution then check out Google Commerce Search. This premium offering gives you a powerful search engine that is entirely outsourced and uses Google technology to deliver great quality results. As you can probably imagine though, this premium product comes with a premium and enduringly high subscription fee.</p>

<h3>Enterprise Open Source</h3>


<p>Instead what we are now recommending to our larger clients is to look at implementing the Solr search engine. <a href="http://lucene.apache.org/solr/" target="_blank">Apache Solr</a> is an enterprise level search engine. It is used in a wide variety of impressive sites &ndash; <a href="http://wiki.apache.org/solr/PublicServers" target="_blank">you can see a list here</a>. Names like Netflix, The Guardian and eBay really underline the fact that this is serious and powerful technology.</p>

<h3>Advanced Search Functionality</h3>


<p>The great thing is that it is also pretty easy to set up and get running. To get a basic search engine working is no more than a few hours of work. There are many possibilities with the search engine including spelling suggestions, parametric (faceted in Solr speak) search, synoyms, auto suggest and loads more. Depending on exactly how you want this to work will determine exactly how much work is involved.</p>

<p>Solr provides a huge amount of configurability and tuning. For this reason we would always expect a new install of Solr to be followed up with a bit of tweaking to make sure you are getting the right results. Once the right configuration has been determined we can then expect the engine to work tirelessly, serving up lightning fast and excellent quality results without any further investment from your business.</p>

<h3>Implement Solr Search Today</h3>


<p>If you would like your site to be fitted out with a Solr based search system by a professional UK based e-commerce web development agency then get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today. Simply fill out the form below and we will be in touch to discuss how we can take your web site search functionality to the next level.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Setup Balsamiq for Fast Mockup Process]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T11:12:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at Edmonds Commerce when we are working on Magento design projects we use <a href="http://www.balsamiq.com/" title="Balsamiq - Mockup tool" target="_blank">MyBalsamiq</a> on-line mockup tool which We&rsquo;ve found as one of the greatest in terms of support provided and especially for &ndash; live linking, which allows you to create live mockups in order to deliver the overall feel of navigation and User Experience to client more effectively. It has awesome sharing function as well &ndash; really easy to work and communicate ideas with clients, especially important in e-commerce projects where we like to test different approaches and see which could generate highest conversion rates.</p>

<p>However, nobody&rsquo;s perfect as well as Balsamiq. They don&rsquo;t have grid system integrated which makes mockup process messy as well as lacking some other essential forms and elements. The good news are that it&rsquo;s possible to Upload existing grid templates and add them to your mockup, whether they are created by Balsamiq, other users or you! I was lucky enough to find well designed Twitter Bootstrap Grid Template mockup on Balsamiq on-line resource <a href="https://mockupstogo.mybalsamiq.com/projects" title="Balsamiq Mockups">database</a> so I could really save time and concentrate on more important tasks.</p>

<p>After mockup is downloaded in .bmml format &ndash; it can be easily uploaded on the system here:
<img src="/assets/Upload_mockup-600x426.jpg"></p>

<p>Might be useful to create your own collection of most used elements and share with others! So Go ahead and create your own collection of most used elements to speed up your mock-up process and share with others. I will definitely create my own. See for updates from time to time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[E-Commerce Web Design Job Leeds Bradford]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/e-commerce-web-design-job-leeds-bradford.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T17:48:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/e-commerce-web-design-job-leeds-bradford</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/">Edmonds Commerce</a> are currently recruiting for a highly talented and creative web design professional to join our team.</p>

<p>You will be working with our core clients on a variety of design tasks including mailshots, banners and other related tasks. You will also be involved in creating brand new designs for clients looking to rebrand their existing sites or set up a whole new site.</p>

<p>We are based in Shipley which is very easy to get to from both Leeds and Bradford areas. It is also easy enough to get to from surrounding areas such as Huddersfield, Wakefield and Keighley thanks to having a well connected train station and easy road links. <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/find-us">You can read more about our location here</a>.</p>

<p>If you would like to join the team as a web designer please fill out the contact form below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento 2 Source Code Available on GitHub]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T07:37:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento version two is coming. For those of us who are eagerly awaiting the next major version of the most popular and powerful open source e-commerce platform, you can now see, track and download the code on GitHub.</p>

<p>Not had chance to have an in depth look as yet but we expect great things!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/magento/magento2"><a href="https://github.com/magento/magento2">https://github.com/magento/magento2</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
