<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: forum | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/forum/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-03T13:16:23+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Forum Spamming Goes Bad..]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/when-forum-spamming-goes-bad.html"/>
    <updated>2010-06-02T09:27:55+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/when-forum-spamming-goes-bad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Forum spammers beware &ndash; some times if you push it that bit too much then you might just find that you get the concerted effort of legitimate forum members to out SEO you and make the whole plan backfire.</p>

<p>Take this forum thread about <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739"><strong>Dallamore.com</strong></a> on the UKBusinessForums.co.uk</p>

<p>It seems that despite multiple bans etc they just kept on spamming, so in the end the forum members (some of which do really know their stuff with regards to SEO) decided they had had enough and would retaliate.</p>

<p>The result is that as I type this blog post, the number three position for searches on <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739">Dallamore</a>, <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&page=2">Dallamore.com</a> and for <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&page=3">Dallamore Spammers</a> they are getting number one. And it hasn&rsquo;t finished yet.</p>

<p>Its a nice reminder that forums, whilst they may have lots of tempting page rank and regular spidering making them excellent places to drop links, you have to consider the primary reason that forums exist &ndash; to give real people a forum for discussion on a particular subject. Get a few real people annoyed &ndash; especially ones with a bit of web savvy &ndash; and you might end up with more than you bargained for!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Questions?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-questions.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-11T13:36:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-questions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have any Magento related questions and are struggling to get help on the main forums, or you just fancy somewhere a bit quieter and possibly more UK focussed to ask your magento related questions, then check out this <a href="http://www.magento-forum.co.uk">UK Magento Forum</a>.</p>

<p>We have been heavily involved in it from the outset and are currently commited to answering any questions that come up as helpfully and promptly as possible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Forum]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-forum.html"/>
    <updated>2009-09-08T17:11:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-forum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After finding the main Magento forum a bit frustrating to use I have decided to launch our own Magento Forum.</p>

<p>Its totally empty at the moment but we will be keeping an eye on it and will try to answer any Magento questions that come up on the board.</p>

<p>We are finding that more and more people are launching new sites or migrating existing sites to the Magento platform. We are big believers in the platform and although it isn&rsquo;t perfect (what is) it has a hell of a lot going for it and is definitely the most exciting open source ecommerce platform out there right now, and we suspect for a good few years to come.</p>

<p>So feel free to drop by and start a thread. Don&rsquo;t be shy &ndash; take advantage of the quiet to get quick answers to your Magento questions in a convenient forum.</p>

<p><b><a href="http://magento-forum.co.uk">Magento Forum</a></b></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
