<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: 5 | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/5/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-07T11:18:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T17:36:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of our clients use <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.</p>

<p>The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.</p>

<p>The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.</p>

<p>The last release for PHP 5.2 was <a href="http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1" target="_blank">version 5.2.16 released back in 2010</a>. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.</p>

<p>You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php" target="_blank">this page</a>.</p>

<p>If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then <b><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today</a></b>.</p>

<p>Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> or <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/opencart">OpenCart</a>. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStorm 5 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T09:07:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Edmonds Commerce we were staunch Netbeans users for years but we always struggled with large scale projects (<a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento/" title="Magento Platform Overview">Magento</a> I&rsquo;m looking at you) meaning that Netbeans would sometimes really crawl as it tried to reindex thousands of PHP files.</p>

<p>After a recent upgrade of our Linux desktop environment to the Mate edition of Linux Mint 13, Netbeans seemed to perform even worse and had a few bugs as well. At the same time we had been evaluating other IDE options including Eclipse and Zend Studio (which we all have free licences for thanks to being Zend Certified Developers).</p>

<p>In the end though, the one we tried that really impressed was PHPStorm. It isn&rsquo;t free open source but it isn&rsquo;t too expensive, especially considering it is perhaps the single most important and highly used tool of a professional PHP developer.</p>

<p>Now a new version has come out. Downloading and upgrading took all of 5 minutes and we are now going to enjoy better performance and some nice new features. I have yet to really test out the new version so I can&rsquo;t really report on them but they look good. You can read about all the new features in version 5 <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/whatsnew/" title="PHPStorm 5 Features" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
