<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: oop | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/oop/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T18:59:40+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend Framework UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-01T16:34:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Currently working on a big Zend Framework project so I though I would have a breather and do a little blog post targeted at anyone looking for a UK based Zend Framework developer.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve built a few Zend Framework based systems and have found it a fun system to work with, especially on the more recent versions of the library. There have been a few hurdles along the way and I have definitely improved my object oriented PHP development skills a lot since I first had a go at the <a href="http://framework.zend.com">Zend Framework</a> quick start way back when.</p>

<p>I chose to learn <strong>Zend Framework</strong> primarily because Magento is based on it, and Magento is the ecommerce platform that I have chosen to specialise in. Since then though I have found that Zend Framework has a definite place for me, especially when coding more heavy duty data processing applications.</p>

<p>For simple web sites I would tend more towards using Symfony or my own lightweight MVC framework for very simple sites. For me Zend Framework really shines when you need to do something a little different that doesn&rsquo;t easily fit into the mold specified by the Symfony code creation tools.</p>

<p>So to conclude, if you are looking for a PHP web developer who specialises in Zend Framework and particularly if you would prefer a UK based Zend Framework specialist then <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-zend-framework.html">get in touch with us today</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
