<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edmondscommerce on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/edmondscommerce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edmondscommerce on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/edmondscommerce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Fedora 19 based PHP Development Installation</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/setting-up-a-fedora-19-based-php-development-installation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/setting-up-a-fedora-19-based-php-development-installation.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to switch from Debian/Ubuntu/Mint which has served me very well over the last few years and move towards more of a RedHat based distribution as it seems that servers these days are more commonly CentOS or RedHat based and I always like to keep my development environment as close as I can to the server environment for all kinds of reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I have decided that I really quite like Gnome Shell and it makes sense to pick a distribution that is properly bundled with Gnome Shell rather than bolting it into a distro after installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Install Apache and PHP 5.5&lt;/h3&gt;
You need to become root first, stay as root for the rest of the steps.

```bash

su
rpm -Uvh http://download1.rpmfusion.org/free/fedora/rpmfusion-free-release-stable.noarch.rpm 
rpm -Uvh http://download1.rpmfusion.org/nonfree/fedora/rpmfusion-nonfree-release-stable.noarch.rpm
rpm -Uvh http://rpms.famillecollet.com/remi-release-19.rpm
yum --enablerepo=remi install httpd php php-common
yum --enablerepo=remi install php-pecl-apc php-cli php-pear php-pdo php-mysqlnd php-pgsql php-pecl-mongo php-sqlite php-pecl-memcache php-pecl-memcached php-gd php-mbstring php-mcrypt php-xml

```

&lt;h3&gt;2. Set that to start up automatically (you are going to be developing none stop right?)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;service httpd start
systemctl &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;enable&lt;/span&gt; httpd.service
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Create a test PHP file to confirm thats all working&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra bit here, install &lt;a href=&#34;http://vim.spf13.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this version of Vim&lt;/a&gt;, its quite tasty:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;curl http://j.mp/spf13-vim3 -L -o - &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now create your PHP file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;vim /var/www/html/test.php
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May as well just throw a phpinfo() in there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;phpinfo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now check it: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/test.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/test.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;4. Finally lets get a MySQL version installed. Lets choose MariaDB&lt;/h3&gt;
I tried Percona but it does not have a proper Fedora version. Then I discovered that Fedora have adopted MariaDB which is fine by me, lets go with the flow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;yum install mariadb mariadb-server
systemctl start mysqld.service
systemctl &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;enable&lt;/span&gt; mysqld.service
/usr/bin/mysql_secure_installation
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it, next up is getting Java and PhpStorm installed and also phpMyAdmin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 Practices for Highly Effective Email Marketing</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/13-best-practices-to-highly-effective-newsletter.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 11:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/13-best-practices-to-highly-effective-newsletter.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each email email must have specific and measurable goals defined. For example - to read an article, sell a product or sign up for an event. It&amp;rsquo;s a Call to Action, a short but precise message which tells the recipient exactly what to do - no more, no less. The Call to Action is one of the most important email email elements; therefore it must be noticeable and inviting. This article will cover best practices on how to create a highly effective email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not sure on how to create a highly effective email that converts customers in to a successful sales leads, then here are the basic questions you need to ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What I want my recipients to do?&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;How will they know how to do it?&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;How will they benefit from doing what I want?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds dead easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s not that simple, because you don&amp;rsquo;t want to scare away your customers with an overly insisting tone. On the other hand, if you don&amp;rsquo;t give your recipient clear guidance on what to do it is most likely they will not do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the core principles on how to create a highly effective email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;1. The value of the email&lt;/h3&gt;
Your Call To Action must clearly communicate the benefits that the customer will receive. Benefits must be clearly visible, order them by priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2. Use simple and convincing language&lt;/h3&gt;
Remember that your recipients are wise and most likely - very busy people. Therefore make the message as clear and simple as possible. Don&amp;rsquo;t make their lives more complicated by using complex language and long paragraphs. Ease their decision and make the choice simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;3. Make the email urgent and limited&lt;/h3&gt;
When the message is urgent and somehow limited (for first 50 respondents or while product is in stock, etc), people are more motivated to act. Use words like Now, Today, Only, Limited, etc. Say why they must act now, explain the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;4. Catchy headlines&lt;/h3&gt;
Web users read by scanning the headlines, therefore they must be short, but catchy. The main point regarding the headline is not to sell the product (if you sell one), but to engage recipient to read the content of the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;5. Use numbers and make them meaningful&lt;/h3&gt;
Numbers deliver a clear message, they create an impression. However, numbers alone are meaningless, use them in context. For example, 4Gb of music storage is meaningless, say how many songs it can carry. Feel free to break it down even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;6. Ask questions&lt;/h3&gt;
Questions are great for attention grabbing. Especially, when you send a targeted email, you most likely know your audience and you know what they need. Make sure you ask. For example - Is your laptop too heavy? And follow with an immediate solution. Create questions so they are intriguing and recipients want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;7. Less is more. (Yes)&lt;/h3&gt;
Don&amp;rsquo;t include too many Call To Actions. Don&amp;rsquo;t over fill the email with products or offers. It is very easy for the recipient to get lost if there are too many adverts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;8. Call To Action placement&lt;/h3&gt;
Remember to place your Call To Action in a highly visible location. If you have multiple Calls to Action make sure that the supporting information is clearly grouped. The primary message has to be as close to the top as possible with supporting information or offers taking position below the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;9. Related design and style&lt;/h3&gt;
Your email email need to use represent your company and branding. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to use different design, colours and overall style in your email. Recipients remember who you are (or at least they should), changing email design will only bring in confusion and most likely dramatically reduce the conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;10. Use a consistent layout&lt;/h3&gt;
Your email must be well organized and content should be prioritized. Do this by placing elements within the layout. Once your email design is created, stick to it. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to use different sizes and colours, unless you are testing various variations for better conversion rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;11. Use white space&lt;/h3&gt;
White space is good. It&amp;rsquo;s not unused sales place. It actually helps the recipient to focus more on the proposal without distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;12. Send relevant content to the right audience&lt;/h3&gt;
Emails shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be generic. Most mistakes are made when a proposal is created that is very generic and sent out to everyone - it can apply to everybody on your list or none at all. Make sure that you know your audience and you send offers that are relevant to them. This can be done by automatically grouping customers by what they&amp;rsquo;ve browsed or bought recently. This is normally called List Segmentation for example only emailing people who have bought a blue widget in the last six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;13. Don&amp;rsquo;t send for the sake of it&lt;/h3&gt;
Add value to your emails. Send offers that are really beneficial to the target customer. Make them anticipate your offer. If you send overly frequent and generic emails, you risk simply loosing subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting a Magento Store Design Programatically in Installer using PHP</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/setting-a-magento-store-design-programatically-in-installer-using-php.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 12:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/setting-a-magento-store-design-programatically-in-installer-using-php.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed to set up a design change for a new store which I was programatically creating. One aspect which I was still doing manually was the design change. Lots of tutorials on the web suggest how to accomplish this in the Admin, but this wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I was after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done this by updating the store&amp;rsquo;s config as shown below. Hope it helps someone out there too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;$config = new Mage_Core_Model_Config();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;$config-&amp;gt;saveConfig(&amp;#39;design/theme/template&amp;#39;, &amp;lt;store name&amp;gt;, &amp;#39;websites&amp;#39;, storeId);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;$config-&amp;gt;saveConfig(&amp;#39;design/theme/layout&amp;#39;, &amp;lt;store name&amp;gt;, &amp;#39;websites&amp;#39;, storeId);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;$config-&amp;gt;saveConfig(&amp;#39;design/theme/skin&amp;#39;, &amp;lt;store name&amp;gt;, &amp;#39;websites&amp;#39;, storeId);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Upgrade to 1.7, Fix for Sales Order Tab Contents in Left Sidebar</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/magento-upgrade-to-1-7-fix-for-sales-order-tab-contents-in-left-sidebar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 14:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/magento-upgrade-to-1-7-fix-for-sales-order-tab-contents-in-left-sidebar.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If following an upgrade to Magento 1.7 you&amp;rsquo;re having a problem that the Sales Order View tab contents are stuck in the sidebar (see below) you&amp;rsquo;re likely ripping your hair out as to why this is happening
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/Sales-Order-View-Problem-502x600.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the page you&amp;rsquo;ll find a line of Javascript:
&lt;code&gt;sales_order_view_tabsJsTabs = new varienTabs(&amp;lsquo;sales_order_view_tabs&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;sales_order_view&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;sales_order_view_tabs_order_info&amp;rsquo;, []);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the javascript which renders the tabs on the page, moving the tab contents to the main content area once the page has loaded. The second parameter here is the destination element. The issue I was having was that the element with the id &amp;lsquo;sales_order_view&amp;rsquo; wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the HTML. This div is contained in app/design/adminhtml/default/default/template/sales/order/view/form.phtml, but this wasn&amp;rsquo;t being loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case this was a code/local overridden core class Mage_Sales_Model_Order. In Magento 1.7 the method canReorder() has been renamed to canReorderIgnoreSalable(). Renaming the overridden method fixed my problem&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Search</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/current-search.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 16:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/current-search.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dressnimpress - New Magento Based E-commerce Site Development</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/dressnimpress-new-magento-based-e-commerce-site-development.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 14:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/dressnimpress-new-magento-based-e-commerce-site-development.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are now working on developing a new Magento based e-commerce site for a UK based company called Dressnimpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client specialises in designer clothing for both male and female and will be targeting a world wide marketplace for selling designer clothes covering all the latests and famous brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site will be developed from scratch by implementing designs that have been provided to us by the client. Part of the development process will include building a number of custom extensions to fulfil specific features of the site, customizing specific areas or pages of the site as per design and it will also have to support multiple currencies for the world wide audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Design Brief</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/web-design-brief.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 15:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/web-design-brief.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
[contact-form 3 &amp;ldquo;Web Design Brief&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JsFiddle - Handy</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/jsfiddle-handy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 13:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/jsfiddle-handy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Check this out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jsfiddle.net/&#34;&gt;http://jsfiddle.net/&lt;/a&gt; - handy :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Format New Hard Drive</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-format-new-hard-drive.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 13:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-format-new-hard-drive.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you want to add another harddrive to your Ubuntu system, the easiest way to handle it is to use Gparted (think partition magic for Linux). You can install via the add applications menu in Applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you create your various partitions though, you might get confused because you can&amp;rsquo;t actually write to them. Gparted makes the partitions owned by root. You are not root so you can&amp;rsquo;t write to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do is open up terminal and do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
$ cd /media
$ ls

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now note down the name of the partition(s) you need to write enable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each one do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
$ sudo chown {yourlogin}:{yourlogin} {partion name}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;replacing the {bits like this} with the correct values for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Lunch Delivered Direct to your Desk - The Lunchbox Has Landed!</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/healthy-lunch-delivered-direct-to-you-desk-the-lunchbox-has-landed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/healthy-lunch-delivered-direct-to-you-desk-the-lunchbox-has-landed.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelunchboxhaslanded.com/offices/index.php&#34;&gt;The Lunchbox Has Landed&lt;/a&gt; is all about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelunchboxhaslanded.com/offices/goodreasons.html&#34;&gt;healthy options&lt;/a&gt; and convenience and pretty good value as well. No more queueing up at the supermarket for sweaty sandwiches and a packet of crisps. Instead get your lunch delivered direct to your desk so that you can enjoy the full length of your lunch break to relax. Alternatively for you focussed workaholics to gain an extra productive half an hour of the day with no compromise on your nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce have taken care of the technical development of The Lunchbox has Landed. The project&amp;rsquo;s main requirement was a&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelunchboxhaslanded.com/offices/samplemenu.html&#34;&gt; user friendly and intuitive ordering system&lt;/a&gt; allowing you to easily build up your personal selection of lunchbox ingredients and schedule your lunches in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project uses large amounts of Jquery for the Javascript, and a bespoke object oriented PHP framework for the business logic. The visual design has been taken care of by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.designermagic.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Designermagic&lt;/a&gt; who have worked closely with Edmonds Commerce to achieve the final cohesive, effective and intuitive result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
It has been a pleasure to work with the team at Edmonds Commerce. They have a thorough technical understanding of building e-commerce websites and we are delighted with the functionality of our site. We would certainly recommend them without hesitation. Stuart Haiz (CMO) – &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelunchboxhaslanded.com/offices/index.php&#34;&gt;theLunchboxhaslanded.com&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are looking for lunch delivered to your office, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelunchboxhaslanded.com/offices/index.php&#34;&gt;The Lunch Box Has Landed&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Easy MVC Framework for WYSIWYG Designers (and PHP developers)</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/new-easy-mvc-framework-for-wysiwyg-designers-and-php-developers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 08:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/new-easy-mvc-framework-for-wysiwyg-designers-and-php-developers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I seem to be incredibly busy this month&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managed to do a lot though. One cool thing is the creation of a shared hosting friendly (and also wysiwyg designer friendly) MVC framework. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require anything more fancy than PHP5 with PDO. No open base dir problems, no modifying the include path problems, no bloat problems, no excess complexity problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do a lot of subcontracting for design agencies and needed something that we could work on at the same time, with proper separation of visual design and logic. However the current big frameworks are all a bit too heavy duty so we have rolled our own small MVC system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses a lot of Jquery to create nice interactive forms and as much as possible auto generates forms etc from the database structure. Its all designed with a view to enabling us to achieve rapid application development whilst still being accessible to non technical (Dreamweaver) designers as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the template files are pure HTML files with no PHP logic in them what so ever. This means that the WYSIWYG designer can work comfortably in a way that is familiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim to release the framework as open source shortly, just need to go over the code and documentation to make sure that it is a good cohesive package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are designer looking to launch a bespoke site and would be interested in leveraging modern techniques and nice Jquery javascript to easily create a really professional quality product that isn&amp;rsquo;t going to break the bank, get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Toggle Checkboxes</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/javascript-toggle-checkboxes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 15:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/javascript-toggle-checkboxes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I seem to use this little snippet loads so I thought I would post it up for safe keeping:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toggling all checkboxes on a page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
function toggleCheckboxes() {
// written by Daniel P 3/21/07
// toggle all checkboxes found on the page
  	var inputlist = document.getElementsByTagName(&amp;quot;input&amp;quot;);
  	for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; inputlist.length; i++) {
   	if ( inputlist[i].getAttribute(&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;) == &#39;checkbox&#39; ) {	// look only at input elements that are checkboxes
			if (inputlist[i].checked)	inputlist[i].checked = false
			else								inputlist[i].checked = true;
		}
	}
}
&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;button onClick=&amp;quot;toggleCheckboxes();&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Toggle Enabled Fields&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t remember where I first found it. If you know where it originates please feel free to add a link in the comments&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Keyword Research</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/seo/google-keyword-research.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 12:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/seo/google-keyword-research.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Just came across another useful keyword research tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/insights/search/&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/insights/search/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a bit like the google trends tool but with more detailed information. Handy helping to choose which variations of a search term to go for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plesk Wildcard Subdomains</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/apache/plesk-wildcard-subdomains.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 11:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/apache/plesk-wildcard-subdomains.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Want to setup wildcard subdomains on a Plesk box?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rackerhacker.com/2007/08/10/using-wildcard-subdomains-in-plesk/&#34;&gt;http://rackerhacker.com/2007/08/10/using-wildcard-subdomains-in-plesk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed Up Gmail - Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ria/speed-up-gmail-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 10:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ria/speed-up-gmail-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If your Gmail is really slow, don&amp;rsquo;t forget you can always switch to basic HTML view. I suspect you will find that it works just as well and is blazingly fast compared to standard Gmail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its still running over HTTPS so there is no security concern. The only issue is that you will need to remember to manually refresh the page if you want to recheck your inbox. However if you use firefox you can simply install the checkgmail firefox addon which will let you know as soon as someone emails your gmail account anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well done to Google for giving the option of the basic HTML view. With all of this web 2.0 thin client revolution going on, I think performance has definitely taken a hit. Better browsers and faster internet will probably overcome all that in the future but for now its nice to be able to stay fast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>