<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uk on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uk on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:34:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP UK Conference In London</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/programming/usability/php-uk-conference-in-london.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/programming/usability/php-uk-conference-in-london.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you might be aware, the UK PHP Conference was held in London last weekend. Having been the lucky winner of a ticket from PHP NW I went along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Venue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference was held in The Brewery in London city centre, a well suited conference centre with a variety of different conference rooms. An old Whitbread brewery, it was modern and practical while still maintaining enough of its history to keep its character. Overall the venue was great and it was good to have the variety of different rooms for all of the different events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talks on offer were on a wide variety of subjects, varying from the very specific libraries to things of use to any PHP developer. Each of the talks was led by a volunteer giving up their time to speak about a subject for which they held a passion, it came across very well and as ever is good to hear from active members of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks I found to be of particular interest were
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future of the PHP Development Environment&lt;/strong&gt; A practical introduction to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vagrantup.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vagrant&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;, demonstrating its purpose in creating a reliable, predictable server environment. Covered was the installation, configuration and use of the software&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenStreetMap for the Web&lt;/strong&gt; An enthusiastic demonstration of the power of having openly accessible data of the world&amp;rsquo;s maps and the APIs which enable a plethora of different applications&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Hands-On Introduction to Writing Unit Tests Using PHPUnit&lt;/strong&gt; A very practical (with live coding and demonstration of the Unit Tests, a risky move that paid off) intro to unit tests in PHP. Aimed at the very beginner, it started slowly with very simple tests but showed the power of them in much bigger projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;In summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed the day, and would recommend anyone wanting to attend in future. The talks will be posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://phpconference.co.uk/schedule&#34; title=&#34;PHP UK Website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PHP UK website&lt;/a&gt; in the coming weeks so you should be able to get a sample of the events there&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Certified Developer UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-certified-developer-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 15:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-certified-developer-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/Magento-Certified-Developer.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to announce that two of our team have now taken and passed the Magento Certified Developer exam. This means that they are now officially &amp;ldquo;Magento Certified Developers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What that means for you is that you can be assured that we have the in house skills and experience to work the right way with Magento and really help you get the most out of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we finally put them forward for the exam is that, after working with the platform for a few years now, we have decided to go down the official Magento partner route and get all the qualification and assurance that you could ask for by becoming an Silver Magento Partner and employing developers who are not only &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/&#34; title=&#34;Zend Certified Developer information&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zend Certified Engineer&lt;/a&gt;s - a PHP qualification - but also Magento Certified Developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exam asks questions on a wide range of Magento topics ranging from the basics through to layout, rendering and then more complex subjects such as the checkout, sales, API and more. You can download the official &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/certification/&#34; title=&#34;Magento certification information&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Magento Certified Developer study guide&lt;/a&gt; to see the full details of the areas that are discussed though suffice to say it is really quite in depth and broad. You definitely need to know Magento well to pass the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that care the passing mark for the exam is 37 out of 70 questions. Our devs passed with 54/70 and 52/70 so really nailed it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart TV Developer UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/smart-tv-developer-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 13:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/smart-tv-developer-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Smart TVs are still quite a new concept to many people. At Edmonds Commerce we believe that Smart TVs and other smart appliances will be the future. As the television is already a screen based system it is really well suited to become a web enabled and smart device. Online streaming services such as the BBC&amp;rsquo;s iPlayer and platforms like NetFlix and LoveFilm are already well established as internet based media streaming platforms and many consumer televisions are already smart enough to consume these channels natively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real smart television revolution is going to be based around custom applications for the smart tvs, available via an app store. There is also many exciting opportunities for custom smart television applications for a wide variety of business applications including things like live information displays, connected messaging systems, warehouse management systems, live graphs and business information displays and all kinds of other ideas - the sky is the limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to discuss your smart tv app idea with a specialist development agency, give Edmonds Commerce a call today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Magento - Magento Developers UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/uk-magento-magento-developers-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 17:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/uk-magento-magento-developers-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a web development agency that specialises and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/product/community-edition&#34;&gt;Magento&lt;/a&gt; and only the most highly skilled, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/&#34;&gt;Zend Certified&lt;/a&gt; PHP developers and specialises entirely on ecommerce PHP development then you have come to the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce Ltd are a UK Magento specialist agency who have been working with Magento since the beginning. We can help you with all kinds of technical Magento requirements including Magento upgrades, custom Magento extensions, API integrations, bug fixing - you name it, we can (and probably already have) done it with Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get in touch today and speak to one of our Magento specialists to see how we can help you get the most out of Magento.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenERP UK - Open Source Enterprise Class ERP</title>
      <link>http://example.com/openerp/openerp-uk-open-source-enterprise-class-erp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 11:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/openerp/openerp-uk-open-source-enterprise-class-erp.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
OpenERP is a fully featured enterprise class open source ERP system that thanks to it&amp;rsquo;s modular structure can support all kinds of business models and requirements ranging from Retail to E-Commerce to Manufacturing to Services and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenERP is written in a language called Python, widely regarded as an excellent language thanks to it&amp;rsquo;s power, cross platform compatibility and ease of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to being open source, you can experiment or even implement OpenERP for you business without any up front costs, licence costs, vendor lock in or any of the other big drawbacks of standard paid for ERP packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you can dip your toe in the water initially and roll out further integration and functionality as you are ready for it and your business requires it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a wide global network of specialist agencies supporting the OpenERP package and at it&amp;rsquo;s centre is a large development house based in Belgium that is entirely devoted to the platform. This kind of business backed open source package is great news for you because it ensures that there will be professional support and training available and you can expect the platform to continue developing in the future, making it an excellent platform to invest into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is similar to the way that Magento, our most highly recommended open source ecommerce package, is backed by Varien - a large and well funded company that is pushing the platform and really making it an enterprise class platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the logical best of breed combination is to use the awesome front end functionality of Magento for your e-commerce stores and hook this into OpenERP&amp;rsquo;s excellent business management functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to discuss OpenERP or Magento or of course both for your business, get in touch today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Developer UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/python/python-developer-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 16:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/python/python-developer-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Looking for UK based Python development services, you have come to the right place. Edmonds Commerce can help you with your Python requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python is an excellent choice of language for anything from simple scripts up to large scale applications. Python applications can be fast and yet easy to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of excellent Python based applications out there such as OpenERP and the Django web framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get in touch with Edmonds Commerce about Python today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony Training UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/symfony/symfony-training-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 11:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/symfony/symfony-training-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
After a few enquiries, we are looking into the possibility of setting up a Symfony training course based in Leeds in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present this is not a firm plan but we are definitely looking into it and would really like some feedback on what kind of Symfony Training course you would like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course would likely be an introduction to the Symfony PHP framework, possibly going through the Jobeet sample site documentation which represents an excellent training framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage it is not totally clear what we would need to include in the course, especially if we can expect candidates to already be familiar and confident with object oriented PHP. One option is that we do another course which is purely focussed on the object oriented aspects of PHP, like a crash course of OO PHP for coders who have no or little experience of this style of coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested and would like to share with us your ideas and expectations for a UK Symfony course please do get in touch. We will take your ideas on board and keep your info on file so we can let you know as and when the course goes live.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using *Proper* UK Keyboard with Mac</title>
      <link>http://example.com/mac/using-proper-uk-keyboard-with-mac.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 12:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/mac/using-proper-uk-keyboard-with-mac.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Contiuing my project to get my Mac to feel like a proper PC and not cause me mental strain every time I switch to it from Ubuntu, I have started using a proper UK keyboard and have now found out how to make it have the correct keymapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For full details go here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gyford.com/phil/writing/2005/11/20/using_a_british.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.gyford.com/phil/writing/2005/11/20/using_a_british.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;download this file:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gyford.com/phil/writing/resources/2005/11/20/british-windows-3.keylayout.gz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.gyford.com/phil/writing/resources/2005/11/20/british-windows-3.keylayout.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then unzip it and put it in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/Users/{yourname}/Library/Keyboard Layouts/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then go to System Preferences -&amp;gt; International -&amp;gt; Input Menu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you should see just below british something called British 3. Tick that box and also ensure the box at the bottom is ticked (&amp;lsquo;Show input menu in menu bar&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then restart the machine and you should have proper UK keyboard, with an easily accessible # key - woot! :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Questions?</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-questions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 13:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-questions.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have any Magento related questions and are struggling to get help on the main forums, or you just fancy somewhere a bit quieter and possibly more UK focussed to ask your magento related questions, then check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magento-forum.co.uk&#34;&gt;UK Magento Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been heavily involved in it from the outset and are currently commited to answering any questions that come up as helpfully and promptly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Framework UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/zend-framework/zend-framework-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/zend-framework/zend-framework-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Currently working on a big Zend Framework project so I though I would have a breather and do a little blog post targeted at anyone looking for a UK based Zend Framework developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve built a few Zend Framework based systems and have found it a fun system to work with, especially on the more recent versions of the library. There have been a few hurdles along the way and I have definitely improved my object oriented PHP development skills a lot since I first had a go at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://framework.zend.com&#34;&gt;Zend Framework&lt;/a&gt; quick start way back when.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to learn &lt;strong&gt;Zend Framework&lt;/strong&gt; primarily because Magento is based on it, and Magento is the ecommerce platform that I have chosen to specialise in. Since then though I have found that Zend Framework has a definite place for me, especially when coding more heavy duty data processing applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For simple web sites I would tend more towards using Symfony or my own lightweight MVC framework for very simple sites. For me Zend Framework really shines when you need to do something a little different that doesn&amp;rsquo;t easily fit into the mold specified by the Symfony code creation tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to conclude, if you are looking for a PHP web developer who specialises in Zend Framework and particularly if you would prefer a UK based Zend Framework specialist then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-zend-framework.html&#34;&gt;get in touch with us today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Leeds</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-leeds.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 19:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-leeds.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce have been specialising in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/&#34;&gt;Magento&lt;/a&gt; for a while now. We have been involved in numerous Magento sites doing things ranging from setting up entire stores (including multi store) through to developing custom Magento modules for specific client requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/php/magento-uk/&#34;&gt;Magento Developer&lt;/a&gt; based in the UK, particularly the &lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;strong&gt;Bradford&lt;/strong&gt; area of &lt;strong&gt;West Yorkshire&lt;/strong&gt; then definitely get in touch with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010 has seen the full launch of our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/magento/magento-training-uk/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magento Training Courses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which are running in Leeds. The first was in early January and we now have two more dates lined up so if you are looking for Magento training then give us a buzz about that and we can give you all the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think Magento is great and we are really happy to be helping more and more UK ecommerce businesses to migrate or establish themselves on this excellent open source ecommerce platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony Developer UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/symfony/symfony-developer-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/symfony/symfony-developer-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are looking for a freelance PHP developer or company to help you create or maintain your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symfony-project.org/&#34;&gt;Symfony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; based PHP application then you have come to the right place. Edmonds Commerce specialise exclusively in PHP web development and are able to assist you with all kinds of Symfony requirements from editing or extending existing sites through to creating new Symfony based web sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symfony is an excellent choice as a PHP framework for building secure, scalable web sites to meet all kinds of different requirements. Utilising best practices, design patterns and the latest Object Oriented features of PHP 5, Symfony is a delight to work with and enables us to deliver high quality web applications in a fraction of the time required for a fully bespoke development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to conclude - if you are looking for a UK based &lt;strong&gt;Symfony Developer&lt;/strong&gt;, or any kind of PHP developer then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-symfony.html&#34;&gt;get in touch today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Training UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-training-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 15:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-training-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To find out about our Magento Training - please &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html&#34;&gt;Get in Touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are pleased to announce our new venture in offering professional training on the Magento open source ecommerce platform. We are firm believers in the Magento platform, but we realise that for many new or even established businesses running on Magento, the system can seem a bit daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many great features built into Magento as standard that it really does make sense to make sure you are utilising them all to their fullest potential. This is why we have established this training programme - to help ecommerce business owners and their staff learn how to use Magento to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To deliver the course, we have partnered up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ntileeds.co.uk/&#34;&gt;NTI&lt;/a&gt; who are based in Leeds City Centre. It has great accessibility from all parts of the country thanks to excellent road, rail and air connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we are still discussing the final details for the course and are definitely interested in hearing what you the public would like to see on that course. If you have any comments or would like to register your interest please get in touch about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training-uk.html&#34;&gt;Magento Training UK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>phpuk2009 Tomorrow</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/phpuk2009-tomorrow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 09:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/phpuk2009-tomorrow.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m going down to London tonight because tomorrow is the PHP UK Conference of 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to it :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phpconference.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.phpconference.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/ecommerce/magento/magento-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 15:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/ecommerce/magento/magento-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce specialise in &lt;strong&gt;Magento Ecommerce&lt;/strong&gt; and are available for &lt;strong&gt;Freelance Magento&lt;/strong&gt; projects and installations. If you are looking to set up a new ecommerce venture and are considering using Magento - get in touch today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magento is certainly making waves. For those of you who haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it, Magento is looking likely to become the successor to osCommerce as the most popular open source ecommerce platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things which make Magento a much better option than osCommerce. However for some people the tried and tested, &amp;lsquo;better the devil you know&amp;rsquo;, huge knowledge, customisation and support base of osCommerce  makes it the platform they would still prefer to put their development investment into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These justifications are valid to a point, however I now believe that the time is right to move into Magento and whilst I am not certain that it is worth worrying about upgrading if you already have a perfectly functional osCommerce site, I would recommend anyone looking to set up a new ecommerce site takes a close look at Magento.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>