<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: zend framework | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/zend-framework/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-17T15:03:36+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Admin Menu not working after Upgrade]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-menu-not-working-after-upgrade.html"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T09:39:07+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-menu-not-working-after-upgrade</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wondering why your Magento admin menu is not showing up after upgrading your live Magento store?</p>

<p>If all attempts to get to a particular admin page with the exception of the dashboard proved abortive, this could be because there is a conflict between the Magento function that merges all Javascript files and the Apache URL rewrite.  This could be fixed by turning off this Magento function, and your can run the script below to do this.</p>

<p>```sql</p>

<p>UPDATE  <code>[your_magento_database_name]</code>.<code>core_config_data</code> SET  <code>value</code> =  &lsquo;0&rsquo; WHERE  <code>core_config_data</code>.<code>path</code> =<code>dev/js/merge_files</code>;</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enable Category Pages to Display Subcategories]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/enable-category-pages-to-display-subcategories.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-01T15:12:22+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/enable-category-pages-to-display-subcategories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking of being able to set different Magento Categories to display its sub-categories which can be controllable in the Magento admin i.e. <img src="/assets/Screenshot-New-Category-Manage-Categories-Categories-Catalog-Magento-Admin-Chromium-150x150.png">
</p>
You might be interested in using or viewing the zipped file here;<a href='http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/subcat.zip'>subcat</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Display out-of-stock products part of a Configurable Product]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/display-out-of-stock-products-part-of-a-configurable-product.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-31T16:39:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/display-out-of-stock-products-part-of-a-configurable-product</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a situation where you want Magento to display out of stock product options of a configurable products, overriding getAllowProducts() function in Mage_Catalog_Block_Product_View_Type_Configurable is where you should be looking, change
```php</p>

<p>if ($product->isSaleable())
{</p>

<pre><code>     $products[] = $product;
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p><code>
to
</code>php
$products[] = $product;
```</p>

<p>Bingo!!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using TCPDF with Magento]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-tcpdf-with-magento.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T13:46:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-tcpdf-with-magento</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento&rsquo;s Zend extension for creating pdfs could take massive amount of time to customize, I would say customizing the code to make it do what you want is not the best the way to go when an entire layout changes is to be made to probably for invoice, packing slip etc. I found an extension that you could add to Magento to make things a lot easier by creating pdf&rsquo;s from html called TCPDF. There exist other extension that could do the same thing e.g. DOMPDF, when I tried incorporating DOMPDF with Magento, it broke my browser and won&rsquo;t generate anything. Dompdf could actually still work with Magento but I didnt have the time to probe into what could be wrong.</p>

<p>So I settled into using TCPDF which worked beautifully with Magento in minutes. You can incorporate it easily into Magento by following the steps below;
1. Download TCPDF from <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/tcpdf/files/">http://sourceforge.net/projects/tcpdf/files/</a>
2. Change the name of the file root directory after extraction to TCPDF
3. Inside this directory, there is a tcpdf.php file, change the name to TCPDF
4. Open the file and change the class name from tcpdf to TCPDF_TCPDF, am very sure those that are really familiar with Magento will know why.
5. Copy the files into your Magento &ldquo;lib&rdquo; folder in the root Magento installation directory.
6. And you have successfully incorporated TCPDF with Magento, from anywhere in Magento, you can call this class by  $tcpdf = new TCPDF_TCPDF(), you can find the constructor parameters for this class in the example files in the TCPDF directory.</p>

<p>I hope this helps someone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend Framework Error Invalid bind-variable name + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-error-invalid-bind-variable-name-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-03T12:55:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-error-invalid-bind-variable-name-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you encounter the error :</p>

<p><strong>Invalid bind-variable name xxxxxx</strong></p>

<p>When trying to use named bound parameters with Zend Framework, then you are probably using the Mysqli adapter. Unfortunately this doesn&rsquo;t actually support named parameters, but the Exception message isn&rsquo;t really clear on that, despite being thrown in this block of code:</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p> } else if ($val[0] == &lsquo;:&rsquo;) {</p>

<pre><code>if ($this-&gt;_adapter-&gt;supportsParameters('named') === false) {
    /**
     * @see Zend_Db_Statement_Exception
     */
    require_once 'Zend/Db/Statement/Exception.php';
    throw new Zend_Db_Statement_Exception("Invalid bind-variable name '$val'");
}
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>The Exception should really say:</p>

<p><strong>You are trying to use named parameters with an adapter that doesn&rsquo;t support them</strong></p>

<p>The solution is easy, just switch your adapter from Mysqli to Pdo_Mysql</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
