<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: queries | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/queries/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-17T13:09:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responsive Web Design for Mobile and Tablet Optimised Web Sites]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T17:42:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are at all involved or exposed to the world of web design and web development then you have no doubt heard of the phrase &ldquo;responsive&rdquo; web design. If you browse the popular theme sites for themes for platforms like WordPress and Magento then you can see responsive themes becoming more popular.</p>

<p>So what does it mean and how does it work?</p>

<h3>What does Responsive Web Design Mean?</h3>


<p>Responsive designs change the layout and visible content on a page depending on the width, height and other factors of the device or window rendering the page. You can generally test out responsive designs by simply unmaximising a browser window and then resizing it down to smaller sizes such as 320 pixels wide. On a normal design you would be quite lucky if the site still rendered in a readable way at that width. More than likely you will only be able to see a fraction of the page and would have to sideways scroll to see the rest of it.</p>

<p>On a responsively designed site, the layout would change as the screen width gets smaller. It might hide certain elements such as side columns and may make things rearrange in a more vertical way to allow them to be displayed without the need for side scrolling.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, this is what responsive web design means.</p>

<h3>How Does Responsive Web Design Work?</h3>


<p>Responsive web design works by using a CSS3 technique called <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/" title="W3C Media Queries Information" target="_blank">Media Queries</a>.</p>

<p>CSS has had the concept of media specific style sheets for quite some time. Traditionally though this was limited to print and screen, allowing for example to remove background images from a page when printing and perhaps adjust font family and size for better printing results.</p>

<p>The media queries functionality extends this concept significantly, allowing custom style rules to be applied based upon a range of differnt media options. The most commonly used of these for responsive web design are width and height.</p>

<p>The full list of properties that can be utilised with media queries include:</p>

<blockquote>width
height
device-width
device-height
orientation
aspect-ratio
device-aspect-ratio
color
color-index
monochrome
resolution
scan
grid</blockquote>




<h3>Get Your Web Site Working Responsively</h3>


<p>If you want to upgrade your web site to use responsive design techniques to better support the wide range of internet devices in use today then <strong><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch</a></strong> with Edmonds Commerce today to discuss how we can help you.</p>

<h3>Some Useful and Interesting Links</h3>


<p><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/ " target="_blank"><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/">http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/</a></a>
<a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/" target="_blank"><a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/">http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/</a></a>
<a href="http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries" target="_blank"><a href="http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries">http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries</a></a>
<a href="http://mediaqueri.es/" target="_blank"><a href="http://mediaqueri.es/">http://mediaqueri.es/</a></a>
<a href="http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/" target="_blank"><a href="http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/">http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend Framework Easy SQL Info]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-easy-sql-info.html"/>
    <updated>2009-07-13T13:47:52+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-easy-sql-info</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you develop using Zend Framework you will know that it is sometimes tricky to see exactly whats going on in terms of SQL queries. After trying a few different ideas including subclassing the database classes or other complex systems, the easiest I have found is this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Edit your app.ini config file and add a line:
```</li>
</ol>


<p>db_profiling_enabled = false</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Then in your development section in your ini file, set the same value to true</p>

<ol>
<li>Add the following lines to your bootstrap.php after the database adapter setup.</li>
</ol>


<p>```php</p>

<p>// DATABASE ADAPTER &ndash; Setup the database adapter
// Zend_Db implements a factory interface that allows developers to pass in an
// adapter name and some parameters that will create an appropriate database
// adapter object.  In this instance, we will be using the values found in the
// &ldquo;database&rdquo; section of the configuration obj.
$dbAdapter = Zend_Db::factory($configuration->database);
//$dbAdapter = new EC_Db_Mysqli($configuration->database->params);</p>

<p>if($configuration->db_profiling_enabled){</p>

<pre><code>// create a new profiler
$profiler = new Zend_Db_Profiler_Firebug('EdmondsCommerce DB Queries Debug');
// enable profiling (this is only recommended in development mode, disable this in production mode)
$profiler-&gt;setEnabled(true);
// add the profiler to the database object
$dbAdapter-&gt;setProfiler($profiler);
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Note you may need to move this chunk above the database adapter section:
```php</p>

<p>// CONFIGURATION &ndash; Setup the configuration object
// The Zend_Config_Ini component will parse the ini file, and resolve all of
// the values for the given section.  Here we will be using the section name
// that corresponds to the APP&rsquo;s Environment
$configuration = new Zend_Config_Ini(</p>

<pre><code>APPLICATION_PATH . '/config/app.ini', 
APPLICATION_ENVIRONMENT
</code></pre>

<p>);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This is based on a modified quickstart layout for a project. If you have decided to use an alternative layout, you should be able to tell where the relevant code should be.</p>

<p>You will need to have the Firebug firefox extension to view this output. If you also install the FirePHP extension for firebug then there are even more cool things that you can do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
