<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: trade | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/trade/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T17:30:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kevin Mayhew]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T14:24:14+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<h2>Magento Site Upgrade</h2>


<p>Kevin Mayhew Ltd. required their Magento site to be upgraded from Enterprise 1.7 to the current release. They are looking to do this because the current site is having problems with some of the functionality which can only be correct by upgrading an extension and the extensions latest version is not compatibility with 1.7. 1.7 is also preventing them from improving the site and adding functionality. This mainly involved updating their site templates to function correctly the the new release as well as resolving issues related to old/new extensions.</p>

<h3>Kevin Mayhew</h3>


<p>Kevin Mayhew is a Christian religious product and music retailer, Christian church resource supplier and Christian book publisher.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/kevinmayhew1-300x216.png"></p>

<p>This project went really well with the pushing to live been successful. With the site now running the latest version of Magento the company can look forward toward to expanding the functionality of the site as well as resolving issues the old site was having.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
