<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: blog | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-03T12:36:28+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress auto building the site locally for one blog post]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Octoress/octopress-auto-building-the-site-locally-for-one-blog-post.html"/>
    <updated>2013-12-03T17:47:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Octoress/octopress-auto-building-the-site-locally-for-one-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Setting up a blog post using Octopress involves writing up your Markdown content, building the site, and previewing it.</p>

<p>This can be time-consuming when writing posts, having to run several commands repeatedly. Here&rsquo;s a few lines you can put into a bash script and run once each time:</p>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>!/bin/bash</h1>

<p>PATHTOLATEST=<code>ls -t source/_posts | head -1</code>;
echo $PATHTOLATEST
bundle exec rake isolate[$PATHTOLATEST];
bundle exec rake generate;
bundle exec rake preview;</p>

<p>```</p>

<ol>
<li>The PATHTOLATEST variable finds the latest post</li>
<li>echo the variable for debugging purposes</li>
<li>rake isolate instructs octopress to build the site with only the latest blog post</li>
<li>rake generate builds the site</li>
<li>rake preview initialises the web server</li>
</ol>


<p>From then you can make changes to your post, and the site will be automatically regenerated. This uses a file watcher so it&rsquo;s helpful to keep the terminal open to watch for it building, or having errors</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SEO Blog Setup and Blog Article Writing Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/seo/seo-blog-setup-and-blog-article-writing-service.html"/>
    <updated>2009-11-11T16:48:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/seo/seo-blog-setup-and-blog-article-writing-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>We are big believers in the power of blogs and regular blog posts to boost the SEO performance of sites. Especially ecommerce style sites that can sometimes struggle to get the kind of SEO focus that is required to rank at the top of the search engine results pages.</p>

<p>For this reason we have recently launched our new <b>SEO Blog Service</b>.</p>

<p>There are lots of options and we will tailor a package to suit your specific requirements and budget starting from £120 per month for a minimum of 6 months.</p>

<p>You will get high quality totally original blog stories written on the key themes, words and phrases that you want to promote. If you get us to install the blog for you, we will preconfigure it to get the maximum SEO benefit and will also link it up to a Twitter account so that you can push your message to the widest audience possible.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t have a blog, or you have one but you never find the time or ideas to write quality blog stories &ndash; we really do receommend you give us a call to discuss this exciting proposal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
