<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: google | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/google/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-09T19:04:45+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First Thing You Should Read on SEO]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/SEO/the-first-thing-you-should-read-on-seo.html"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T12:16:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/SEO/the-first-thing-you-should-read-on-seo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is so much information about SEO out there and so many things that used
to be true but are no longer that it really has become a bit of a minefield.</p>

<p>For the average web master who simply wants to rank reasonably well and make sure that they are doign all of the basic things required to do so then this is the document you should read.</p>

<p>It is written by the company that are almost synonymous with the word search engine. In fact their company name has now become a verb meaning &lsquo;to use a search engine&rsquo;. It is of course Google.</p>

<p>You can read the official google SEO guidelines <a href="http://static.googleusercontent.com/media/www.google.co.uk/en/uk/webmasters/docs/search-engine-optimization-starter-guide.pdf">here</a></p>

<p>It is not a huge document and should be well within the technical understanding of the average webmaster.</p>

<p>I suggest you read it today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add Jquery to Any Page via Console]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/add-jquery-to-any-page-via-console.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T18:44:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/add-jquery-to-any-page-via-console</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you might want to do a little on the fly DOM editing using your favourite Javascript library &ndash; jQuery.</p>

<p>To do this you might need to include jQuery on the page, you can do this by pasting these lines into your console in Chrome or Firebug in Firefox.</p>

<pre class="lang:js decode:true " title="Run this in your console" >var jq = document.createElement('script');
jq.src = "http://code.jquery.com/jquery-latest.min.js";
document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0].appendChild(jq);
jQuery.noConflict();
</pre>


<p></p>

<p>And there you have it, the full power of jQuery at your fingertips</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrate to Google Apps - Google Apps Reseller]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T14:21:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are big fans of Google Apps and have built a large portion of our business processes around the system. For this reason we have absolutely no problem recommending the service to our clients and have assisted numerous clients with a migration to the system.</p>

<p>The first benefit you will get is your emails migrated over and a much better email service. You have the option of using normal IMAP access so you can continue to use your preferred desktop application however we suspect that you will start to use the web interface as it is really quite powerful with some unique features that you can not access on a normal desktop client.</p>

<p>Along with this you have great support of mobile devices, especially if you opt for Android with powerful and free native apps meaning that you can have all the access to your emails that could possibly wish for.</p>

<p>Along with the really excellent email functionality you also have powerful online documents giving you the basic office application functionality along with really powerful collaboration features allowing multiple people to be working on the same document simultaneously from geographically separate locations. This can be great when putting together proposals, specifications etc.</p>

<p>Now called Google Drive, the documents system has grown from managing purely office documents into a fully featured online file store that can be used to store and share all kinds of files across your organisation and with third parties.</p>

<p>Finally the calendar functionality is great. If you have never used Google Calendar then I suspect the first things you will notice is the abilty to easily drag and drop appointments around when reorganising your schedule. The ability to quickly create appointments using natural language such as &ldquo;call steve at 11am&rdquo; is really nice. A full barrage of reminders can be set up if you wish including on screen, SMS and emails meaning you should never miss an appointment again.</p>

<p>All in all we think Google Apps is great and would love to help you move your organisation across to the system. If you would like to discuss this in more detail please do <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us"><b>get in touch today</b></a>.</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce are a Google Apps Reseller.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Disable the Default DuckDuckGo Seach Engine in Firefox on Linux Mint?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux%20mint/how-to-disabled-the-default-duckduckgo-seach-engine-in-firefox-on-linux-mint.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T15:12:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux%20mint/how-to-disabled-the-default-duckduckgo-seach-engine-in-firefox-on-linux-mint</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are using Firefox browser on Linux Mint you might have notice that the default search engine is not Google but DuckDuckGo.</p>

<p>DuckDuckGo are presenting themselves as the biggest threat to Google search engine bringing as the main advantage more privacy than what Google currently offer.</p>

<p>If you are happy with it than you are fine but if you feel like me that DuckDuckGo might have some interesting features, it does not bring the same result or way of using internet than Google search engine then you might want to come back to Google then please follow the below step by step procedure:</p>

<pre><code>Type about:config in the location bar and press Enter

Type keyword.URL in filter

Change the keyword.URL value to:

http://www.google.co.uk/search?ie=UTF-8&amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;sourceid=navclient&amp;gfns=1&amp;q=
</code></pre>

<p>Hope that help.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Drops Google Apps Free Tier]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/google-drops-google-apps-free-tier.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T14:19:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/google-drops-google-apps-free-tier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a move that will hurt a lot of small businesses and especially startups, Google have withdrawn their free Google Apps for Domains which has been slowly reducing in number of users from 50, to 10 to now 0 (almost).</p>

<p>They are keeping the existing accounts open so if you have Google Apps already, don&rsquo;t panic yet, your data is still there.</p>

<p>For one-man-band startups apparently there is the option of creating a single-user apps account still apparently, according to Greg D'Alesandre of Google.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
