<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet Explorer on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/internet-explorer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet Explorer on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 16:16:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/internet-explorer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading JSON without Reading JSON!</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/programming/reading-json-without-reading-json.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 16:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/programming/reading-json-without-reading-json.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JSON is a well structure interoperable way of passing data between systems. It&amp;rsquo;s a good way of passing large amount of data into a web page for JavaScript to process and between system on the internet regardless of there architecture or programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON is one of the hardest data structure to read directly as a human in it&amp;rsquo;s RAW format compared to other formal grammars such as XML, YAML or ini.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately there is an easy trick that you can do with Chrome, Firefox with Firebug and even Opera and IE9!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the JSON you have, wrap it in &amp;ldquo;eval()&amp;rdquo; the same as you would if you where writing a web page (because it is just JavaScript after all) run it and every modern browser this was tested with should allow you to inspect the resulting data structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example JSON:
&lt;code&gt;
{&amp;ldquo;glossary&amp;rdquo;:{&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;example glossary&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;GlossDiv&amp;rdquo;:{&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;GlossList&amp;rdquo;:{&amp;ldquo;GlossEntry&amp;rdquo;:{&amp;ldquo;ID&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;SGML&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;SortAs&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;SGML&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;GlossTerm&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;Standard Generalized Markup Language&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Acronym&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;SGML&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Abbrev&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;ISO 8879:1986&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;GlossDef&amp;rdquo;:{&amp;ldquo;para&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;A meta-markup language, used to create markup languages such as DocBook.&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;GlossSeeAlso&amp;rdquo;:[&amp;ldquo;GML&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;XML&amp;rdquo;]},&amp;ldquo;GlossSee&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;markup&amp;rdquo;}}}}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Firefox with Firebug:
![Image](/images/firefoxjson-600x328.png)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Chrome:
![Image](/images/chromejson-600x313.png)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Opera:
![Image](/images/bhtAjti.png)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Internet Explorer 9:
Note: To see this structure you need to click the &#34;Add watcher&#34; link displayed upon running the code.
![Image](/images/ie9json.png)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu &#43; VirtualBox &#43; XP = Easy</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-virtualbox-xp-easy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 08:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-virtualbox-xp-easy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I have recently had the misfortune of stepping out of my usual developers bubble and having to do a bit of graphic web design. Of course that means that not only did I have to try to make something look good with my meagre design skills, but then I had to worry about making sure it worked in IE&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web Designers&amp;hellip; I FEEL YOUR PAIN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I only use Ubuntu or Mac&amp;rsquo;s, testing in IE is not exactly easy. Or at least it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I decided to take the plunge and set up XP as a virtual machine. It&amp;rsquo;s really really easy on Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to the Applications-&amp;gt;Add / Remove system&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;type virtualbox in the searchbox&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install VirtualBox OSE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to the Applications-&amp;gt;Accessories menu and launch VirtualBox OSE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hit the blue New icon in the top left&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Follow the wizard. I used the following settings:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.a name: xp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.b: memory: 192mb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the boot disk stage, you need to hit the New button to create and install a new &amp;lsquo;boot disk&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whack your XP CD in the drive and install it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default the right hand ctrl key is your key for escaping out of your virtual machine. This means that if you click on your virtual machine with your mouse (for example to go through to multiple steps required to tell XP that you want English UK keyboard, and surprise surprise an English Keyboard layout and furthermore you don&amp;rsquo;t really need to install English US as a separate language)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note - to access your Ubuntu environment you will need to have folder sharing set up, the virtual machine will see the host Ubuntu like another computer on a network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If like me you need to edit the hosts file to point a dummy domain to your local development environment, the IP address you need to use is 10.0.2.2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Internet Explorer under Ubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-development/linux/ubuntu/web-design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 16:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-development/linux/ubuntu/web-design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Ubuntu Linux is undoubtedly the most successful desktop version of linux available today. It has managed to tempt across many dedicated windows users with its easy installation procedure, comprehensive bundle of applications including open office and firefox, its greater security and reduced vulnerability to internet viruses and malware. And of course the fact that it is free to download and install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a web designer, it is nice to have a sleek desktop environment to code in whilst being able to run a full LAMP stack web server as the localhost - meaning that designing and developing web sites is a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are times when you simply need to check that a design is going to work with Internet Explorer. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Internet Explorer web browser is bundled with windows and is therefore the most popular web browser at the moment. However as a web designer it causes problems as it often behaves erratically or unexpectedly. For this reason a web designer always needs to make sure that they check their designs in Internet Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason that Ubuntu users may need to use Internet Explorer is to log into certain sites which are not compatible with anything other than Internet Explorer. This is a real pet hate as it is real sign of laziness on the part of the web designers not to ensure that their web sites are accessible by all web browsers. Unfortunately the sites that tend to be like this are the ones that you really need, such as online banking sites. Its probably something to do with sloppy handling of ssl secure and insecure content, but I am not sure on that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway - to save you having to maintain a windows installation and reboot everytime you need to check something in Internet Explorer - there is the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IEs 4 Linux package&lt;/a&gt;. This great package allows you to easily install Internet Explorer under Ubuntu (or any other version of Linux).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have WINE installed and working, and also have the cabextractor working. Both of these packages are available in the syntaptic package manager in Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>