<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: cms | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/cms/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-11T10:08:38+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concrete5 Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/concrete5/concrete5-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T16:48:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/concrete5/concrete5-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.concrete5.org/">Concrete5</a> is a CMS system based on Zend Framework that uses Jquery for it&rsquo;s Javascript layer. Both of these are very popular and powerful frameworks that are really great to work with.</p>

<p>The thing that users really love though is the ability to edit Concrete5 pages on the fly making it very easy to use by non techies.</p>

<p>You can see the real ethos of the platform (from our techie point of view) <a href="http://www.concrete5.org/about/blog/client-work/an-open-letter-to-php-developers-about-concrete5/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you are looking for some expert PHP developers to help you get your Concrete5 site off the ground then <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calling Methods from a Magento Static Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/calling-methods-from-a-static-block.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T11:47:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/calling-methods-from-a-static-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had to develop a bespoke CMS within magento.</p>

<p>One of the requirements was that the system should be very easy to customise, and should use the existing Pages and Static blocks functionality within magento.</p>

<p>I wanted the ability to call a block that I had created from with a static block. Magento allows you to do this using the code below
<code>

</code></p>

<p>The issue that I came across if you need to call a method on the block before it is rendered. If I was calling the block using XML I could use the action tag, but that is not avalible here.</p>

<p>However, it is possible to call certain methods using the code above. The magento parser takes each of the pair values and calls a set method on them, so for example template=&lsquo;path&hellip;&rsquo; actually calls the setTemplate method on your block.</p>

<p>This means that you can create a set method and trigger it from with in the static block like so</p>

<p><code>

</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento HomePage Layout All Messed Up + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-homepage-layout-all-messed-up-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-12-01T11:47:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-homepage-layout-all-messed-up-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are making some design changes to your store and all of a sudden your home page has gone totally messed up then this might be your solution.</p>

<p>When working with designs and design packages in Magento you must remember that design packages are referenced not only in the System->Configuration or System->Design sections, but also on a per product or per CMS page basis as well.</p>

<p>So if you remove, rename or otherwise alter a design package then its going to cause problems.</p>

<p>If you are having issues &ndash; remember to not just look at the layout files etc, but also look in the admin CMS section and check what design package settings you have there.</p>

<p>This one is very simple to fix once you have figured out what&rsquo;s causing it, but can take hours of frustration if you get rail roaded into examining the files for the issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Remove Hard Coded URLs from Theme]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-remove-hard-coded-urls-from-theme.html"/>
    <updated>2010-09-02T14:14:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-remove-hard-coded-urls-from-theme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are working on a theme, you may find that there are hard coded links dotted all over the place.</p>

<p>This can make testing a site offline (and thereby not on the same URL) a bit of a pain.</p>

<p>Here is a quick fix for you:</p>

<ol>
<li>Remove all hard coded links from the CMS section:</li>
</ol>


<p>```sql</p>

<p>update cms_block set content = replace(content, &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com/">http://www.domain.com/</a>&rsquo;, &lsquo;&rsquo;);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>```sql</p>

<p>update cms_page set content = replace(content, &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com/">http://www.domain.com/</a>&rsquo;, &lsquo;&rsquo;);</p>

<p>```</p>

<ol>
<li>Remove all hard coded links from the theme files.</li>
</ol>


<p>This is a command line one using grep and sed.</p>

<p>Firstly, cd into the root theme folder</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>cd app/design/frontent/default/hardtheme</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Now find files with hard coded links</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>grep -rl &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com">http://www.domain.com</a>&rsquo; ./</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Now to automatically remove all those,</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>grep -rl &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com">http://www.domain.com</a>&rsquo; ./ | xargs sed -i &rsquo;s/<a href="http://domain.com//">http://domain.com//</a>&lt;?php echo Mage::getBaseUrl(Mage_Core_Model_Store::URL_TYPE_WEB);?>/'</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drupal Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/drupal/drupal-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2009-07-07T10:07:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/drupal/drupal-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>For content or community driven websites I definitely recommend taking a close look at the PHP based open source package <b>Drupal</b>. Like other successful open source packages, one of it&rsquo;s key strengths is in the tremendous breadth of additional modules that are available allowing you to create your custom mixture of features specific to your site requirements.</p>

<p>A lot of very cool modules are available allowing you to put together a comprehensively fully featured site without requiring any real custom development work. Also applying a custom design to Drupal is really quite easy. For you this all means that Drupal represents a comparitively low cost option for a powerful, custom content based web site.</p>

<p>If you need some freelance Drupal development do get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
