<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Load on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/load/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Load on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 11:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/load/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Admins Black Friday Survival Public Service Announcement</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento-admins-black-friday-survival-public-service-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 11:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento-admins-black-friday-survival-public-service-announcement/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;magento-site-being-flooded-with-buyers-struggling-with-server-load&#34;&gt;Magento Site Being Flooded with Buyers, Struggling with Server Load?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your Magento site is currently being flooded with orders and visitors and the server is struggling to cope then I have one simple and easy to action tip for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-as-little-as-possible-in-the-admin&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do as little as possible in the admin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that every time you update product details and other wise change things in the admin then you are likely to cause one or both of the indexes and caches to require a flush?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In normal operation that is not a big deal, but if your server is being maxed out then you really don&amp;rsquo;t want to force it to stop serving requests and spend precious seconds rebuilding caches and indexes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the admin is in itself a heavy beast that your webserver has to do a lot of work to prepare each page load. As a total &lt;em&gt;finger in the air estimate&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d say a single admin page view is worth around &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt; front end page views. If you are making good use of caching then that could be more like &lt;em&gt;100&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that if you want your site to continue working on the front end through Black Friday then I really suggest you restrict admin usage to the minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stuck-for-something-to-do&#34;&gt;Stuck for something to do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not fire up Google Analytics real time stats, put your feet up and drink tea whilst watching people flood through your checkout process :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;commercial-bit&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Commercial Bit:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you are realising that you really could have been better prepared for today&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That you are losing sales because your site and server are not performing at their best..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are starting to think that you could do with some high quality professional Magento expertise&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then why not get in touch with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Edmonds Commerce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0044 113 880 5654&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Apache JMeter For Load Testing</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/load-testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 13:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/load-testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Load testing is something that you really need a decent solution for. A simple tool such as Apache Bench (ab) is overly simplistic for todays web applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some research I decided to use Apache Jmeter as the tool of choice. It is written in Java so easy enough to run on any platform.
It features a GUI which is ideal for creating your tests, then a command line version which is what you should use to run your tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my purposes I wanted to feed in a large list of URLs, for that I followed these instructions:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows you to create a csv file with your choice of URLs. It was actually quite hard to find a decent and succint guide to getting this set up but thankfully that page fitted my requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I started to run the test I quickly realised that my system was grinding to a halt with out of memory errors. A bit more searching yielded this page which advises on how to properly run Jmeter including the fact that you really should run it on the command line for proper testing.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Profiler Improved - Aoe_Profiler by Fabrizio Branca</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Magento profiler is useful when you are trying to discover what potential bottlenecks are in place in a specific Magento implementation that are slowing down the performance of the site. Often when doing this kind of analysis you might find that a particular block or extension is responsible for more than 70% of the total page load time. At this point you would choose to either optimise, cache or disable the block altogether to remove this performance bottleneck and improve page speed significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever tried to use Magento&amp;rsquo;s built in profiler you will no doubt agree with Fabrizio&amp;rsquo;s comments that, when you have it working, the output is hard to read and not really very useful in terms of seeing what is actually going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To aid with this process and give us a nice colourful and friendly user interface to the Magento profiler, Fabrizio has built a Magento module that extends the default profiler and makes it a much more useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the extension from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fbrnc/Aoe_Profiler&#34; title=&#34;Magento Aoe Profiler on Git Hub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;git hub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full blog story &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabrizio-branca.de/magento-profiler.html&#34; title=&#34;Fabrizio Branch blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like some help optimising the performance of your Magento store, feel free to get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today and we can assist in getting the very best performance from your Magento web site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>