<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Certification on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/certification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Certification on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 11:24:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/certification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Certified Developers</title>
      <link>http://example.com/featured/zend-certified-developers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 11:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/featured/zend-certified-developers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce employs a team of specialist PHP web developers who are all Zend Certified Engineers. This is a highly respected PHP qualification that ensures the highest standards of PHP development expertise. By achieving this certification we ensure that our developers have the kind of well rounded and deep understanding of the PHP language that can be utilised to achieve the highest quality production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the e-commerce platforms, such as Magento and OpenCart are written in PHP and so the first thing to be sure of when you have a developer working on your projects is that they are very skilled in PHP itself as well as having an expert knowledge of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/screenshot-thumb3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read all about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/&#34; title=&#34;ZCE information&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ZCE exam here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell the exam is designed to test knowledge and skill that a professional PHP developer would need to tackle the kind of day to day issues they are likely to face. The exam covers a broad range of topics and really tests the in depth and broad knowledge of PHP that is required to really get the most out of the language and deliver the highest quality PHP development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Partners UK - Silver Partners</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-partners-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 15:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-partners-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/bage-solution-silver.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
Magento have a partner programme which agencies such as ourselves can register with to become partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are Silver Magento Partners. This means that we specialise in both Magento Community and Magento Enterprise projects for clients ranging from SME to PLC level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to discuss your Magento requirements with a Magento Partner agency then &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/contact-us&#34;&gt;get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the full details of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.magento.com/rs/magentocommerce/images/Magento_Solution_Patner_Program_Overview.pdf&#34;&gt;Magento Partner Program here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a Magento project that requires highly skilled and experienced &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/&#34;&gt;Zend Certified Engineers&lt;/a&gt; (an actual PHP qualification that assures of skill in the PHP programming language itself that Magento is written in) then do &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>