<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: responsive | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/responsive/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-01T12:08:44+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Great Way of Cross-platform Prototyping - Invisionapp]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:16:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at Edmonds Commerce we are always looking for new techniques and tools that allow to speed up and ease our internal work-flow which results in faster and more<a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/web-project-management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow/" title="Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management" target="_blank"> effective project planning</a>, management and development. We love to involve and closely collaborate with our clients as much as possible.</p>

<p>Just found this awesome c<a href=" http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="Invisionapp - cross platform prototyping tool" target="_blank">ross-platform mockup and interactive prototyping tool &ndash; Invision</a> &ndash; which has an amazing feedback feature which could replace long email conversations. It is filled with lots of  active guides and how-to&rsquo;s which makes it really understandable for clients. Actually, I find this part the most important about all the application. So far there have been a serious struggle with this particular phase &ndash; work showoff, iterations and final sign off. That is a long journey for traditional email conversations.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/InvisionApp-Design.png"> InvisionApp interface</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent just a few moments with it, but it looks like 135.004 people in 70 countries aren&rsquo;t trusting this awesome tool just for fun. (as it is stated on <a href="http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="invisionapp homepage" target="_blank">invisionapp homepage</a> when writing this post) Feels like I&rsquo;ve finally found a well designed tool which has the most of the essential features.</p>

<p>Looking forward to take our clients on the journey of designing and iterating on their projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating & Testing a Responsive Design Has Never Been Easier]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:02:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/Reflow.png"></p>

<p>Got my hands on these two marvellous responsive design tools from Adobe &ndash; <a href="http://www.adobe.com/EdgeReflow" title="Adobe Edge Reflow Homepage" target="_blank">Edge Reflow</a> and <a href="http://www.adobe.com/EdgeInspect‎" title="Adboe Edge Inspect" target="_blank">Edge Inspect</a>.</p>

<p>Although Reflow is still in Beta, it has brilliant concept. Never the less <u>it has a potential to redefine the way of how we create and test responsive designs</u> once and for all. A much more effective way. It actually allows you to visualise everything blazing fast by adding different break points and adjusting the layout and design for each of them. Going further &ndash; you can test that right away on most of the devices with Edge Inspect. It&rsquo;s that dead easy &ndash; just install the app and connect your phone or tablet with your computer to see how the design actually works on the target device.</p>

<p>There are plenty of good resources available that will get you started in no time. The effort of learning it is definitely worth every minute you spend. The most useful resource that I&rsquo;ve found so far is the <a href="http://http://www.adobe.com/devnet/edge-reflow/articles/edge-reflow-getting-started.html" title="Edge Reflow Guide for Beginners" target="_blank">original Edge Reflow guide from Adobe itself</a> It is a beginner level guide. Once you understand the core principles everything else is dead easy.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/reflow_inspect.png"></p>

<p>Remember, that it is still in beta. Let&rsquo;s help Adobe team to create more remarkable products and post our ideas of improvements it <a href="http://forums.adobe.com/community/edge_reflow_preview?view=idea" title="Edge Reflow Forum" target="_blank">Edge Reflow forum.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox and Responsive Web Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/firefox-and-responsive-web-design.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-10T12:16:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/firefox-and-responsive-web-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Responsive web design is an excellent way to make a site work really well for a variety of different screen sizes without having to serve more than one design to users. Responsive web design does pose additional challenges however.</p>

<p>Some of the challenges for you, as the developer, are being able to implement, test and debug the design implementation. Fortunately built in to Firefox&rsquo;s arsenal of developer tools is an interface for exactly that!</p>

<p>Lets take a website that uses a responsive design:
<img src="/assets/large-no-tools-600x396.png">
Here is the &lsquo;mobile&rsquo; view:<img src="/assets/small-no-tools.png"></p>

<p>So every thing is normal you can use the developer tools and Firebug or whatever. If you then need to make changes to the smaller version and use Firebug you would have to pop out Firebug (which may or may not be to your preference) then resize the main window. This works ok but Firebug currently isn&rsquo;t great for working with responsive designs as it doesn&rsquo;t show you all the rules that might apply based on the screen size and other conditions. This is one area that the Firefox built in tools beat Firebug. The styles editor shows you all rules that could apply and their conditions.</p>

<p>To activate Firefox&rsquo;s responsive design view press Ctrl + Shift + M. You can open the inspector and stlyes by pressing Ctrl + Shift + I. You can also access the responsive design view by going to Tools > Web Developer. With responsive design view enabled you can still use Firebug without a problem, unless you enable the built in element inspector then you kind of lose loads of screen space.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/small-tools-600x447.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responsive Web Design for Mobile and Tablet Optimised Web Sites]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T17:42:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are at all involved or exposed to the world of web design and web development then you have no doubt heard of the phrase &ldquo;responsive&rdquo; web design. If you browse the popular theme sites for themes for platforms like WordPress and Magento then you can see responsive themes becoming more popular.</p>

<p>So what does it mean and how does it work?</p>

<h3>What does Responsive Web Design Mean?</h3>


<p>Responsive designs change the layout and visible content on a page depending on the width, height and other factors of the device or window rendering the page. You can generally test out responsive designs by simply unmaximising a browser window and then resizing it down to smaller sizes such as 320 pixels wide. On a normal design you would be quite lucky if the site still rendered in a readable way at that width. More than likely you will only be able to see a fraction of the page and would have to sideways scroll to see the rest of it.</p>

<p>On a responsively designed site, the layout would change as the screen width gets smaller. It might hide certain elements such as side columns and may make things rearrange in a more vertical way to allow them to be displayed without the need for side scrolling.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, this is what responsive web design means.</p>

<h3>How Does Responsive Web Design Work?</h3>


<p>Responsive web design works by using a CSS3 technique called <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/" title="W3C Media Queries Information" target="_blank">Media Queries</a>.</p>

<p>CSS has had the concept of media specific style sheets for quite some time. Traditionally though this was limited to print and screen, allowing for example to remove background images from a page when printing and perhaps adjust font family and size for better printing results.</p>

<p>The media queries functionality extends this concept significantly, allowing custom style rules to be applied based upon a range of differnt media options. The most commonly used of these for responsive web design are width and height.</p>

<p>The full list of properties that can be utilised with media queries include:</p>

<blockquote>width
height
device-width
device-height
orientation
aspect-ratio
device-aspect-ratio
color
color-index
monochrome
resolution
scan
grid</blockquote>




<h3>Get Your Web Site Working Responsively</h3>


<p>If you want to upgrade your web site to use responsive design techniques to better support the wide range of internet devices in use today then <strong><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch</a></strong> with Edmonds Commerce today to discuss how we can help you.</p>

<h3>Some Useful and Interesting Links</h3>


<p><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/ " target="_blank"><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/">http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/</a></a>
<a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/" target="_blank"><a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/">http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/</a></a>
<a href="http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries" target="_blank"><a href="http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries">http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries</a></a>
<a href="http://mediaqueri.es/" target="_blank"><a href="http://mediaqueri.es/">http://mediaqueri.es/</a></a>
<a href="http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/" target="_blank"><a href="http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/">http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
