<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: marketing | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/marketing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-29T12:54:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edmonds Commerce successfully implements marketing firesale on Buckley Jewellery]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T12:41:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The idea</h2>


<p><a href="http://www.buckleylondon.com/">Buckley Jewellery</a> approached us with an idea they had for setting up a promotion to go viral. Their idea was to pick one of their products which they were already selling and literally give it away.</p>

<h2>The problems</h2>


<p>The initial requirement was fairly straightforward &ndash; we&rsquo;d set up a Shopping Cart Price Rule with a coupon code to give a 100% discount on the product price if the specific SKU was in the basket. But it then became apparent that there were various problems here.</p>

<p><strong>Free Shipping Calculations:<strong> Although we&rsquo;d set it up so that only one of the items were discounted, all items were still factored in when Magento attempted to calculate the shipping costs, so their Free UK Delivery Over &pound;30 policy took effect when two of the item were present</p>

<p><strong>Different shipping for the free product:<strong> Buckley have shipping rates tailored to a more bulky package, but obviously these free earrings were quite small, and charging upwards of &pound;10 for EU shipping wasn&rsquo;t going to work. We had to find a way to keep their &pound;3.50, &pound;12.50 and &pound;19 shipping for their products, but for the free earrings have an exception &ndash; &pound;2.99, &pound;3.99 and &pound;4.99.</p>

<h2>The solutions</h2>


<p>We spent much time with Buckley discussing how to get their requirements to work and went down a few threads of thought</p>

<p>The core discount is a Shopping Cart Price Rule setting a 100% price discount applied only to one of the specific SKU, one per customer, with a coupon code.</p>

<p>To solve the different shipping for different products we decided to leverage products' weights to vary the shipping. Having to work around their MatrixRates extension&rsquo;s limitation to only vary by weight OR basket total vs destination we implemented a standard weight across the board, and changed only the free earrings to be less &lsquo;heavy&rsquo;. We then implemented shipping rules such that if the basket came to a weight less than 1kg (which could only mean it was just the free earrings) the lower shipping rates are applied, otherwise the greater costs</p>

<p>We then reimplemented the free shipping over &pound;30 (at the last minute!) as another Shopping Cart Price Rule so that we could still maintain the free shipping, without having to pay to upgrade their MatrixRates extension</p>

<h2>On the day</h2>


<p>The promotion did go viral &ndash; it ended up on various social media, as well as being featured on MoneySavingExpert, with them promising to send it out on their monthly newsletter</p>

<p>The earrings sold out in less than two hours, with people flocking to the site to get their hands on them. Of course, many customers also purchased other items while on the site and they&rsquo;ve increased their customer base, while also getting their name out there.</p>

<p>They&rsquo;re now looking to switch over their hosting so that they can stand up to bigger and better promotions in the future</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Adwords Edit Tool and Bulk Adwords Campaigns]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/adwords/google-adwords-edit-tool-and-bulk-adwords-campaigns.html"/>
    <updated>2009-08-11T17:40:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/adwords/google-adwords-edit-tool-and-bulk-adwords-campaigns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>I have recently been working on shoehorning a large amount of data into a Google Adwords account for a client. Looking at setting up unique ads for around 50k products (targeting in stock products only so this is just a slice of the full catalogue size). I have managed to figure my way around the various Adwords limits and decided to use the adwords tool (running on a VirtualBox XP machine) to handle the bulk uploading.</p>

<p>I took a brief look at the API and then realised that you have to actually pay to use it! Forget that, already paying Google enough..</p>

<p>Anyway, now using the Adwords Edit Tool to upload the data and my god is it slow. I wonder if the API is as slow?</p>

<p>For the record &ndash; I found out that you can only have 25 campaigns. Each campaign can have up to 2000 ad groups inside it. Each ad group can contain an as yet undetermined amount of ads and keywords. You can&rsquo;t determine which keywords are displayed with which ad, but you can use dynamic keywords to allow you to effectively have one ad displaying a large number of keywords each with their own unique(ish) ad. Variable keyword lengths though cause pain with this approach.</p>

<p>Ultimately I have found making adwords do exactly what I want it to do to be an excercise in flexible, lateral thinking and generally working around the system rather than with it. That&rsquo;s never really as much fun and the whole thing has given me a new found respect for Amazons AMTU system. The real achilles heel of the Adwords Edit Tool is that you are going to need to manually run it every time, and if it runs this slow then forget about keeping a large amount of ads updated on a regular basis.</p>

<p>I am sure there are some hardcore Adwords abusers who could shed light on a few more sneaky tricks. I suspect a lot involve setting up multiple adwords accounts and that is something that I might consider.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
