<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: business | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/business/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-29T12:54:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Document Change Tracking in Javascript]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/document-change-tracking-in-javascript.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-14T08:19:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/document-change-tracking-in-javascript</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just found this really rather nice looking JavaScript change tracking system.</p>

<p>Lawyers using email take note, Office + email is archaic</p>

<p>If you won&rsquo;t use Google Docs for privacy reasons (fair enough) then would you like us to build you your own document tracking client system?</p>

<p><a href="http://nytimes.github.com/ice/demo/"><a href="http://nytimes.github.com/ice/demo/">http://nytimes.github.com/ice/demo/</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating to Google Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2010-06-10T07:48:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>We recently decided to give Google Apps a try, mainly due to the requirement for some decent webmail and it being a brilliant webmail system at the unbeatable price of free.</p>

<p>Here is my quick guide to migrating easily:</p>

<p>Migrating emails &ndash; sign up to the free trial of the premier edition and use the IMAP migration system. It is by far the slickest option and will faithfully and accurately import all of your emails across. Best, you can set it going and then shut down your local machine, its all handled server side, so no requirement to shunt emails up from your desktop or anything like that.</p>

<p>Nested Folders &ndash; if you do the above and have a lot of nested folders, you will notice a pretty ugly massive list of tags with forward slashes in. To get back your nested sub folder like functionality you need to go to settings, then labs and then enabled the nested tags extension. This will give you a sub folder like interface for your tags and tidy the whole thing up.</p>

<p>Turn off those adds at the top &ndash; If you notice adds being displayed at the top and would like to get rid, its easy &ndash; Gmail calls them web clips and you can turn them off in the settings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Block Google Analytics Cookies to Stop Staff Contaminating your Data]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/block-google-analytics-cookies-to-stop-staff-contaminating-your-data.html"/>
    <updated>2008-11-25T16:10:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/block-google-analytics-cookies-to-stop-staff-contaminating-your-data</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>Many webmasters use Google Analytics to track their web traffic. This is a good idea and can be really useful in helping you to optimise your site and maximise your conversions.</p>

<p>However if your staff are constantly browsing your site, they will totally contaminate the data.</p>

<p>It is easy to block this though. All you need to do is add the following line to your HOSTS file</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>[Google Inc]</h1>

<p>127.0.0.1 www.google-analytics.com</p>

<p>```</p>

<p><b>Finding Your HOSTS file</b>
The hosts file is located in different locations in different operating systems and even in different Windows versions:</p>

<ul>
    <li> Windows NT/2000/XP/2003/Vista: %SystemRoot%\system32\drivers\etc\ is the default location, which may be changed. The actual directory is determined by the Registry key \HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Services\Tcpip\Parameters\DataBasePath.
   <li> Windows 95/98/Me: %WinDir%\
    <li> Linux and other Unix-like operating systems (including iPhone OS): /etc
    <li> Mac OS 9 and earlier: System Folder: Preferences or System folder (format of the file may vary from Windows and Linux counterparts)
   <li> Mac OS X: /private/etc (uses BSD-style Hosts file)
    <li> OS/2 and eComStation: "bootdrive":\mptn\etc\
   <li> Symbian 1st/2nd edition phones: C:\system\data\hosts
    <li> Symbian 3rd edition phones: C:\private\10000882\hosts, only accessible with file browsers with AllFiles capability, most are not. 
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Business Tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/online-business-tools.html"/>
    <updated>2008-11-14T11:49:41+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/online-business-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>Check out this huge list of online business tools!</p>

<p><a href="http://mashable.com/2008/09/21/270-online-business-tools/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://mashable.com/2008/09/21/270-online-business-tools/">http://mashable.com/2008/09/21/270-online-business-tools/</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
