<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: upholstered headboards | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/upholstered-headboards/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-25T15:37:55+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upholstered Headboards UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/upholstered-headboards-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-05-17T14:50:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/upholstered-headboards-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Upholstered Headboards.co.uk specialises in manufacturing, supplying and distributing quality designer upholstered headboards to both the commercial and domestic markets.</p>

<p>We built this project from ground up. The website is based on Magento e-commerce platform.</p>

<p>We implemented design for this website from PSD files sent to us by the client&rsquo;s designer. The implementation was quite fun as we had to utilize a variety of tools to get everything absolutely perfect.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.upholsteredheadboards.co.uk/"><img alt="Upholstered Headboards" src="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/07/uph_home.png" title="Upholstered Headboards" width="650" height="624" /></a></p>

<p>The website supports multiple store (two at the moment with a view of increasing it to 5) with  a  single checkout. To get the both stores to channel all checkout transactions to one secure checkout URL was a bit of fun. We were forced to think out of the box to come up with a concrete and stable solution as Magento didn&rsquo;t support the requirements quite well.</p>

<p>We also implemented some nice custom select options to simply usability. Below is an example of a
pop up select box displaying fabric options for user to select from.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.upholsteredheadboards.co.uk/"><img alt="Lightbox" src="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/07/lightbox.png" title="Lightbox" class="alignnone" width="650" height="624" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
