<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: erp | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/erp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-07T10:56:25+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smart TV Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/smart-tv-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T13:20:23+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/smart-tv-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Smart TVs are still quite a new concept to many people. At Edmonds Commerce we believe that Smart TVs and other smart appliances will be the future. As the television is already a screen based system it is really well suited to become a web enabled and smart device. Online streaming services such as the BBC&rsquo;s iPlayer and platforms like NetFlix and LoveFilm are already well established as internet based media streaming platforms and many consumer televisions are already smart enough to consume these channels natively.</p>

<p>The real smart television revolution is going to be based around custom applications for the smart tvs, available via an app store. There is also many exciting opportunities for custom smart television applications for a wide variety of business applications including things like live information displays, connected messaging systems, warehouse management systems, live graphs and business information displays and all kinds of other ideas &ndash; the sky is the limit.</p>

<p>If you would like to discuss your smart tv app idea with a specialist development agency, give Edmonds Commerce a call today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenERP UK - Open Source Enterprise Class ERP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/openerp/openerp-uk-open-source-enterprise-class-erp.html"/>
    <updated>2011-01-07T11:49:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/openerp/openerp-uk-open-source-enterprise-class-erp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>OpenERP is a fully featured enterprise class open source ERP system that thanks to it&rsquo;s modular structure can support all kinds of business models and requirements ranging from Retail to E-Commerce to Manufacturing to Services and beyond.</p>

<p>OpenERP is written in a language called Python, widely regarded as an excellent language thanks to it&rsquo;s power, cross platform compatibility and ease of development.</p>

<p>Thanks to being open source, you can experiment or even implement OpenERP for you business without any up front costs, licence costs, vendor lock in or any of the other big drawbacks of standard paid for ERP packages.</p>

<p>This means you can dip your toe in the water initially and roll out further integration and functionality as you are ready for it and your business requires it.</p>

<p>There is a wide global network of specialist agencies supporting the OpenERP package and at it&rsquo;s centre is a large development house based in Belgium that is entirely devoted to the platform. This kind of business backed open source package is great news for you because it ensures that there will be professional support and training available and you can expect the platform to continue developing in the future, making it an excellent platform to invest into.</p>

<p>This is similar to the way that Magento, our most highly recommended open source ecommerce package, is backed by Varien &ndash; a large and well funded company that is pushing the platform and really making it an enterprise class platform.</p>

<p>Of course the logical best of breed combination is to use the awesome front end functionality of Magento for your e-commerce stores and hook this into OpenERP&rsquo;s excellent business management functionality.</p>

<p>If you would like to discuss OpenERP or Magento or of course both for your business, get in touch today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
