<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: error | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/error/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-10T14:18:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[During git pull: error: RPC failed; result=56, HTTP code = 200 [x] KiB/s       fatal: The remote end hung up unexpectedly]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/during-git-pull-error-rpc-failed-result56-http-code-200-x-kibs-fatal-the-remote-end-hung-up-unexpectedly.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-16T15:07:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/during-git-pull-error-rpc-failed-result56-http-code-200-x-kibs-fatal-the-remote-end-hung-up-unexpectedly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you receive this series of errors during a git pull (after the Receiving Objects stage):</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>$ git pull
Password for &lsquo;<a href="https://xxxxxxxxxx@bitbucket.org">https://xxxxxxxxxx@bitbucket.org</a>&rsquo;:
remote: Counting objects: 1011, done.
remote: Compressing objects: 100% (394/394), done.
error: RPC failed; result=56, HTTP code = 200 51 KiB/s    <br/>
fatal: The remote end hung up unexpectedly
fatal: early EOF
fatal: index-pack failed</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>a quick solution is to use ssh to pull rather than the https protocol</p>

<p>Hope this helps</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ERROR 1062 (23000) at line [Line No]: Duplicate entry for key '[Key Name]']]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/error-1062-23000-at-line-line-no-duplicate-entry-for-key-key-name.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-02T14:09:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/error-1062-23000-at-line-line-no-duplicate-entry-for-key-key-name</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Importing a database dump from one location using mysqldump, and them importing it into a blank database I received this error:</p>

<p>ERROR 1062 (23000) at line [Line No]: Duplicate entry for key &lsquo;[Key Name]&rsquo;</p>

<p>The issue here is that a constraint is set up to prevent two rows containing the same value. Although key checks are disabled, it still can&rsquo;t add the rows. Sometimes as a useful technique to just get it running locally (obviously there&rsquo;s an issue here which does need resolving), simply change the &ldquo;INSERT INTO&rdquo; statement to &ldquo;INSERT IGNORE INTO&rdquo;, which will skip that entry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prestashop Debug Mode using the Magento Environment Variable Method]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/prestashop-debug-mode-using-the-magento-environment-variable-method.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T10:14:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/prestashop-debug-mode-using-the-magento-environment-variable-method</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento developers are no doubt familiar with the concept of defining a server environment variable MAGE_IS_DEVELOPER_MODE so that when running Magento locally it is always in developer mode but there is no chance of accidently deploying a live site in developer mode.</p>

<p>This little trick will allow you to use the same environment variable to also have the same effect when working with PrestaShop.</p>

<p>To explain &ndash; developer mode generally means that things like error messages and debugging information are displayed clearly in the browser which makes things much easier when you are developing, to see what is going wrong.</p>

<p>On a live site you want to keep error information hidden and generally display to the customer a more friendly error message screen that perhaps helps them find their way back to a functional section of the site or gives them information to contact the site owner directly for assistance.</p>

<p>Anyway, to put PrestaShop in debug mode locally but have no risk of deployign this to live you can alter the file: config/defines.inc.php</p>

<p>from
```php</p>

<p>define(&lsquo;<em>PS_MODE_DEV</em>&rsquo;, false);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>to
```php</p>

<p>define(&lsquo;<em>PS_MODE_DEV</em>&rsquo;, isset($_SERVER[&lsquo;MAGE_IS_DEVELOPER_MODE&rsquo;]));</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Mod Rewrite Escaped Slashes Problem + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/apache/apache-mod-rewrite-escaped-slashes-problem-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-11T11:05:20+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/apache/apache-mod-rewrite-escaped-slashes-problem-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of our Magento SEO service, the first thing we do is to make sure there are no issues with the crawlability and general health of the clients web site.</p>

<p>Whilst working on the Google Webmaster Tools crawl errors for a client I noticed one specific and intruiging problem for which I couldn&rsquo;t immediately see the reason, everything looked to be set up perfectly.</p>

<p>Certain URLs were getting 404 responses. The URL was being parsed by mod_rewrite but everything looked fine so why was apache giving a 404?</p>

<p>The problem turns out to be that the URLs contain escaped slashes (eg search/KTA-mb667k2%2F2g),</p>

<p>The problem is that Apache actually handles the escaped slash and helpfully converts it to a real slash. That then means that it is trying to look in a sub folder that does not exist and hence the 404.</p>

<p>Chances are you don&rsquo;t want escaped slashes to really be thought of as real directory separating slashes, especially if you are using mod_rewrite.</p>

<p>The answer is a simple one liner to be added to your vhost.conf or httpd.conf.</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>AllowEncodedSlashes On</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solution - Can't Log in to Magento Admin - No Error]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/solution-cant-log-in-to-magento-no-error.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T14:35:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/solution-cant-log-in-to-magento-no-error</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you pull down a <a title="Magento" href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/platforms/Magento">Magento</a> site to a local machine, and change the database core_config table to point to the local machine, and it appears to work fine until you try to login to the site admin, there can be many issues.</p>

<p>One of the most common ones though is not having a period (dot) in the host name &ndash; e.g. localhost/admin or martyn-desktop/admin &ndash; if you don&rsquo;t have the period, the cookies don&rsquo;t work properly and you end up in a login loop.</p>

<p>To fix it, make sure your machine is accessible via a domain with a period &ndash; e.g. martyn-desktop.local &ndash; by either editing your hosts file (/etc/hosts) or check your router &ndash; it possibly already adds a domain name like .config and set your path in core_config to the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
