<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: migration | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/migration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-08T12:55:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cPanel Download Site Files and Database]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/cpanel/cpanel-download-site-files-and-database.html"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T18:03:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/cpanel/cpanel-download-site-files-and-database</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Often a client won&rsquo;t have access to SSH, or won&rsquo;t be able to provide you with some of the more specifics such as FTP, PHPMyAdmin etc. All they know to give you is access to their cPanel. Through this there&rsquo;s various tools at your disposal.</p>

<h2>Try SSH</h2>

<p>Your cPanel login is actually a Linux user login, which cPanel&rsquo;s FTP hooks into. The first step is to navigate in your cPanel to FTP Accounts and click Configure FTP client on a user. These are SFTP details and can very often provide you with SSH shell access, unless the host has disabled this.</p>

<p>Simply try <code>ssh user@host -p 1234</code>, where the user, host and password are your cPanel login, and the port displayed on the FTP Accounts page.</p>

<p>From here you&rsquo;re free to use <code>tar</code>, <code>gzip</code>, <code>mysqldump</code> etc to acquire the files and database.</p>

<h2>If SSH isn&rsquo;t enabled</h2>

<p>Sometimes the host disables SSH access, only allowing its use for SFTP. There are still many ways to acquire the site&rsquo;s files and database:</p>

<h3>Getting hold of the files</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong>Plain old FTP</strong> &ndash; You can just use an FTP client such as Filezilla to access and download the site&rsquo;s files using FTP or SFTP. This is the simplest way, but can take a long time because of the amount of files involved</li>
<li><strong>File Manager Web UI</strong> &ndash; compressing the site&rsquo;s files obviously shrinks the download size, but also vastly reduces the amount of connections you need to make, leading to a faster download speed.

<ol>
<li> Navigate to the File Manager section (remember to tick &ldquo;Show hidden files&rdquo; to pick up .htaccess files)</li>
<li>Browse to the web root folder, select all the files and folders you want using Ctrl+Click. Remember to exclude unnecessary large files such as sql dumps, media folders and the var folder</li>
<li>Click Compress from the toolbar</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3>Getting hold of the database</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong>PHPMyAdmin</strong> &ndash; PHPMyAdmin offers an array of options for dumping your database. You should start by checking the database&rsquo;s size and considering excluding the dump of tables such as <code>log_url</code>, <code>log_url_info</code>, <code>log_visitor</code>, <code>log_visitor_info</code>, <code>report_viewed_product_index</code>

<ol>
<li> Navigate to the PHPMyAdmin area of cPanel and locate the database in use (check your <code>app/etc/local.xml</code> if you&rsquo;re not sure which</li>
<li>Click the Export tab</li>
<li>Select Custom: here&rsquo;s where you can selectively export information</li>
<li>Tick &lsquo;Disable foreign key checks&rsquo; and set &lsquo;Dump table&rsquo; to &lsquo;structure&rsquo;. This will have PHPMyAdmin set up only the tables' columns but no data (we&rsquo;ll get to that)</li>
<li>Click Go</li>
<li>Once this is complete, navigate back to the Export page and click Custom again.</li>
<li>Deselect (ctrl+click) any tables which are unnecessary</li>
<li>Tick &lsquo;Disable foreign key checks&rsquo; and set &lsquo;Dump table&rsquo; this time to &lsquo;data&rsquo;</li>
<li>This will provide you with two files representing the database. Import first the Structure one, and then the Data one (or concatenate the two together)</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magmi]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magmi.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T13:39:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magmi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It used to be that importing products into Magento was incredibly time consuming and difficult to handle. Whilst recent updates to Magento has improved the Dataflow process it is still not a perfect solution.</p>

<p>To help get round this a project was set-up called <a href="http://sourceforge.net/apps/mediawiki/magmi/index.php?title=Main_Page" title="Magmi">Magmi</a> which allowed products to be imported directly, rather than using the Magento ORM. As this evolved it added more useful features and is now the only way that I handle importing products into Magento.</p>

<p>There are a couple of steps that need to be carried out before the system can be used properly. After it has been installed the first thing that needs to be done is to secure the web interface. This can be done using Basic Auth or IP restrictions in Apache. To generate a basic auth password for a .htaccess file you can use this <a href="http://tools.dynamicdrive.com/password/">handy tool</a>.</p>

<p>Once you have it secured the next step is to install some extensions to allow you to use some of the more advanced features. To install plugins you download them from here:<a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/magmi/files/magmi-0.7/plugins/individual/">http://sourceforge.net/projects/magmi/files/magmi-0.7/plugins/individual/</a> and then extract them into the plugins folder.</p>

<p>Or you can use plugin packages and you can actually install these directly from the web interface if your server supports it (Thanks Dweeves).</p>

<p>The plugins are really what makes MAGMI so great as they allow you to do things like handle configurable products, categories and other things that standard dataflow and import/export are no where near being able to offer.</p>

<p>For advanced purposes it is possible to leverage the power of MAGMI in your own custom import purposes as part of a bespoke application using <a href="http://sourceforge.net/apps/mediawiki/magmi/index.php?title=Magmi_Datapump_API">MAGMI datapump</a>. We have used this technique for numerous clients when building a direct import from supplier feeds etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Magento Database Migrations to Track Configuration Changes]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-database-migrations-to-track-configuration-changes.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-21T09:11:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-database-migrations-to-track-configuration-changes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Often when working on a Magento site, there is a requirement to build custom functionality or implement new themes etc but to finish the job, the final step will be to perform some admin configuration.</p>

<p>This manual step can introduce the possiblity of human error if a step is missed or not performed exactly correctly.</p>

<p>Also if the configuration is to be applied multiple times across staging, pre production and final production then these risks increase.</p>

<p>The only sure way to make sure that the correct configuration is applied and also to provide a proper audit trail for configuration changes is to use Magento&rsquo;s database migrations &ndash; install and upgrade scripts &ndash; to update the database programmatically with the required configuration changes.</p>

<p>To assist with this, there is a nice simple module you can find on Git Hub:</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/danslo/MigrationHelper"><a href="https://github.com/danslo/MigrationHelper">https://github.com/danslo/MigrationHelper</a></a></p>

<p>This module will automatically create the migration files for you which can be a real time saver.</p>

<p>I would always suggest you create your own custom namespaced configuration migration module that is purely to track these configuration changes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ongoing Magento Support and Consultation]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T15:52:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.buckleylondon.com">Buckley</a> is a UK based company that prides itself on designing and manufacturing high quality fashion &amp; costume jewellery at competitive prices since its inception in 1989. The company has rapidly expanded into a worldwide brand with jewellery collections available to a vast market of over 200 stores including more than 60 Duty Free shops and 120 airlines . We are glad to hear that Buckley has contributed over US$3 million to the funding of the Royal British Legion through the sale of its elegant Buckley Poppy.</p>

<h3>The development idea:</h3>


<p>Buckley Jewellery was initially launched using Wordpress and used an ecommerce package called ShopperPress. As the company grew and they started to expand their business to Duty Free shops and airlines, it became apparent that WordPress could not provide enough support for their complex modifications and customisations. This is when the idea of re-building the site in Magento was suggested.</p>

<p>We started working with Buckley in 2011 and have been providing them with continuous support since then. Some of the main requirements were broadly to do the following:</p>

<h3>1. Magento implementation and migration from previous platform</h3>


<p>We installed and configured Magento onto Buckley’s chosen hosting platform and installed the essential extensions such as shipping and payment gateways including PayPal and SagePay. We also migrated all of their products, customers and orders database from the previous platform into Magento. A clean and clear design was created and customised to their specification and we have been tweaking it per their needs and requirements ever since.</p>

<h3>2. Magento training</h3>


<p>After successfully migrating the site to Magento, we did an <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-course-details/">on-site one day introduction course</a> with Buckley, where we gave them the background understanding and some useful skills required to get the most out of their new Magento store.
Here is a quote from Mark at Buckley Jewellry: “<em>The day was extremely useful with just the right amount of content to set us on our way</em>.”</p>

<h3>3. Magento upgrade and Magento security patch applied</h3>


<p>It is important to make sure that your Magento site is up to date. We have done two upgrades for Buckley so far and they all went really well.The upgrades were done in three separate phrases &ndash; exploratory upgrade, bugs fixing and deployment to live. We hit a few bugs but managed to fix them within hours.
Around mid July 2012, a serious security hole was found in Zend Framework which allow hackers to gain access to mysql server credentials. A patch was quickly applied to Buckley live store using a nice Bash script we put together. We offered this free security patching service to all Magento sites with a voluntary charity donation and had a lot of sites take us up on this offer.</p>

<h3>4. Ongoing support</h3>


<p>Buckley have joined our retainer scheme where we provide them with daily maintenance supports, bugs fixing and consultation services. Various <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery/">firesale promotions</a>, extensions and marketing exercises were installed and configured into their website.
Recently we had migrated Buckley and its sister site <a href="http://www.attwoodandsawyer.com">Attwood &amp; Sawyer</a> to a dedicated server, which is faster, more secured and gives them better control over the sites.
Buckley also engages in designing beautiful vintage inspired pieces in the silver <a href="http://www.bouton.co.uk/">Bouton</a> rages and we are currently managing the merger process of Bouton into Buckley main sites.</p>

<h3>Testimonial</h3>


<p>Here is a quote from Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery:</p>

<p><em>“Buckley Jewellery originally approached <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk">Edmonds Commerce</a> to take our existing site and develop it onto a <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/platforms/magento/">Magento platform</a>. Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp; expand our ecommerce business. The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design. I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice”. </em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb1.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrate to Google Apps - Google Apps Reseller]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T14:21:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are big fans of Google Apps and have built a large portion of our business processes around the system. For this reason we have absolutely no problem recommending the service to our clients and have assisted numerous clients with a migration to the system.</p>

<p>The first benefit you will get is your emails migrated over and a much better email service. You have the option of using normal IMAP access so you can continue to use your preferred desktop application however we suspect that you will start to use the web interface as it is really quite powerful with some unique features that you can not access on a normal desktop client.</p>

<p>Along with this you have great support of mobile devices, especially if you opt for Android with powerful and free native apps meaning that you can have all the access to your emails that could possibly wish for.</p>

<p>Along with the really excellent email functionality you also have powerful online documents giving you the basic office application functionality along with really powerful collaboration features allowing multiple people to be working on the same document simultaneously from geographically separate locations. This can be great when putting together proposals, specifications etc.</p>

<p>Now called Google Drive, the documents system has grown from managing purely office documents into a fully featured online file store that can be used to store and share all kinds of files across your organisation and with third parties.</p>

<p>Finally the calendar functionality is great. If you have never used Google Calendar then I suspect the first things you will notice is the abilty to easily drag and drop appointments around when reorganising your schedule. The ability to quickly create appointments using natural language such as &ldquo;call steve at 11am&rdquo; is really nice. A full barrage of reminders can be set up if you wish including on screen, SMS and emails meaning you should never miss an appointment again.</p>

<p>All in all we think Google Apps is great and would love to help you move your organisation across to the system. If you would like to discuss this in more detail please do <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us"><b>get in touch today</b></a>.</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce are a Google Apps Reseller.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
