<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: baildon physion | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/baildon-physion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-11T11:25:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baildon Physiotherapy]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/baildon-physiotherapy.html"/>
    <updated>2010-05-17T14:39:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/baildon-physiotherapy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Baildon Physiotherapy is a sports injury clinic based in Baildon, bradford leeds. They offer expert treatment of a wide variety of musculoskeletal problems.</p>

<p>We have created their new look website from ground up based on client&rsquo;s specification. The website is based on WordPress. We had to customize the look and feel so the website appears as a standard CMS website while utilizing the power of WordPress blog alongside.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.baildonphysio.com/"><img alt="Baildon Physio" src="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/07/baildonphysio.png" title="Baildon Physio" /></a></p>

<p>Another cool feature we did for this project was to successfully integrate the booking sytem and a contact form. When clients make an appointment as shown on the figure below, the site administrator will automatically be notified as well as the record will appear on the pending list on the booking system in the back-end. The feature was critical for this project.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.baildonphysio.com/appointments/"><img alt="Baildon Physio" src="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/07/baildon_appt.png" title="Baildon Physio" width="650" height="492" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
