<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: login | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/login/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T13:25:53+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Admin Login Not Working in Some Browsers + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-login-not-working-in-some-browsers.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T16:17:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-login-not-working-in-some-browsers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are tearing your hair out trying to figure out why you are not able to log into the Magento admin on some browsers then this might be your solution.</p>

<p>This solution will apply particularly if you are setting up Magento on a brand new server or VPS as you will see.</p>

<p>The problem is actually that the server time is wrong. The server time is used for generating cookies and the fact that the time is wrong means that cookies become invalidated immediately. Some browsers will deal with this in a less aggressive way than others and might actually let the cookie work, others will go for hard line security and will make the whole thing break.</p>

<p>The way to check this is to SSH into the server and check the time:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>date</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If the time is wrong then you need to do the following to fix it:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>yum install ntp
chkconfig ntpd on
ntpdate pool.ntp.org
/etc/init.d/ntpd start</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>The above will install NTP, make it run on startup, will update the time and will set it running so the time should stay up to date from here on.</p>

<p>To check that has worked simply check the time again:
```bash</p>

<p>date</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Then finally flush your Magento cache and sessions</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>rm -rf var/cache/<em>
rm -rf var/sessions/</em></p>

<p>```</p>

<p>And you should be good to go</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C-Panel Access using WHS/Root Password]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/server/c-panel-access-using-whsroot-password.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T15:29:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/server/c-panel-access-using-whsroot-password</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever wondering how you could gain access into any Control panel(c-panel) account when you confidently know only the username of the c-panel account. I tried doing this by actually using the Web host manager (WHS) password, and it worked brilliantly for any c-panel user account.</p>

<p>But the only gotcha I found out  was that I could not use Phpmyadmin. Nevertheless, you could still find a way around this by adding a PHP database management file on the web root directory which installs an alternative database management User interface which provides functions similar to Phpmyadmin.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CentOS Very Slow SSH Password Prompt]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/centos-very-slow-ssh-password-prompt.html"/>
    <updated>2011-02-24T17:49:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/centos-very-slow-ssh-password-prompt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are finding it takes ages for a password prompt to come up when trying to connect to a CentOS server (and possibly others) this is a solution.</p>

<p>The cause is that your IP address does not have the correct reverse DNS etc settings.</p>

<p>You can of course try to fix all that but if you need a quick fix, you can edit the sshd configuration and disable</p>

<p>GSSAPIAuthentication yes</p>

<p>to: GSSAPIAuthentication no</p>

<p>and</p>

<p>UseDNS yes</p>

<p>to: UseDNS no</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
