<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: zend | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/zend/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-16T11:42:51+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[White Blank Page when Printing Packing Slips from Magento Admin]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/white-blank-page-when-printing-packing-slips-from-magento-admin.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-01T14:21:49+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/white-blank-page-when-printing-packing-slips-from-magento-admin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re having trouble printing packing slips, receiving a white blank page when selecting Print Packingslips from the Actions menu in Magento&rsquo;s Sales Orders page, then it&rsquo;s likely you&rsquo;re having the same issue I&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<p>I found that having error_reporting enabled wasn&rsquo;t enough</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>error_reporting(E_ALL | E_STRICT);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You&rsquo;ll also need to add this to your index.php:</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>ini_set(&lsquo;display_errors&rsquo;, 1);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You&rsquo;ll then be shown the following fatal error:</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Fatal error: Declaration of Zend_Pdf_FileParserDataSource_File::<strong>construct() must be compatible with Zend_Pdf_FileParserDataSource::</strong>construct() in /home8/stonecr2/public_html/newsite/lib/Zend/Pdf/FileParserDataSource/File.php on line 41</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>The issue here is that the contructor of Zend_Pdf_FileParserDataSource_File requires a single paramter, $filePath, whereas its abstract class&rsquo;s constructor does not. To resolve this, we need to make sure the abstract class matches its implementation, so make the following change</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>//from
abstract public function __construct();</p>

<p>//to
abstract public function __construct($filePath);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Test your printing, and you should be provided with a PDF file.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ongoing Magento Support and Consultation]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T15:52:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.buckleylondon.com">Buckley</a> is a UK based company that prides itself on designing and manufacturing high quality fashion &amp; costume jewellery at competitive prices since its inception in 1989. The company has rapidly expanded into a worldwide brand with jewellery collections available to a vast market of over 200 stores including more than 60 Duty Free shops and 120 airlines . We are glad to hear that Buckley has contributed over US$3 million to the funding of the Royal British Legion through the sale of its elegant Buckley Poppy.</p>

<h3>The development idea:</h3>


<p>Buckley Jewellery was initially launched using Wordpress and used an ecommerce package called ShopperPress. As the company grew and they started to expand their business to Duty Free shops and airlines, it became apparent that WordPress could not provide enough support for their complex modifications and customisations. This is when the idea of re-building the site in Magento was suggested.</p>

<p>We started working with Buckley in 2011 and have been providing them with continuous support since then. Some of the main requirements were broadly to do the following:</p>

<h3>1. Magento implementation and migration from previous platform</h3>


<p>We installed and configured Magento onto Buckley’s chosen hosting platform and installed the essential extensions such as shipping and payment gateways including PayPal and SagePay. We also migrated all of their products, customers and orders database from the previous platform into Magento. A clean and clear design was created and customised to their specification and we have been tweaking it per their needs and requirements ever since.</p>

<h3>2. Magento training</h3>


<p>After successfully migrating the site to Magento, we did an <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-course-details/">on-site one day introduction course</a> with Buckley, where we gave them the background understanding and some useful skills required to get the most out of their new Magento store.
Here is a quote from Mark at Buckley Jewellry: “<em>The day was extremely useful with just the right amount of content to set us on our way</em>.”</p>

<h3>3. Magento upgrade and Magento security patch applied</h3>


<p>It is important to make sure that your Magento site is up to date. We have done two upgrades for Buckley so far and they all went really well.The upgrades were done in three separate phrases &ndash; exploratory upgrade, bugs fixing and deployment to live. We hit a few bugs but managed to fix them within hours.
Around mid July 2012, a serious security hole was found in Zend Framework which allow hackers to gain access to mysql server credentials. A patch was quickly applied to Buckley live store using a nice Bash script we put together. We offered this free security patching service to all Magento sites with a voluntary charity donation and had a lot of sites take us up on this offer.</p>

<h3>4. Ongoing support</h3>


<p>Buckley have joined our retainer scheme where we provide them with daily maintenance supports, bugs fixing and consultation services. Various <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery/">firesale promotions</a>, extensions and marketing exercises were installed and configured into their website.
Recently we had migrated Buckley and its sister site <a href="http://www.attwoodandsawyer.com">Attwood &amp; Sawyer</a> to a dedicated server, which is faster, more secured and gives them better control over the sites.
Buckley also engages in designing beautiful vintage inspired pieces in the silver <a href="http://www.bouton.co.uk/">Bouton</a> rages and we are currently managing the merger process of Bouton into Buckley main sites.</p>

<h3>Testimonial</h3>


<p>Here is a quote from Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery:</p>

<p><em>“Buckley Jewellery originally approached <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk">Edmonds Commerce</a> to take our existing site and develop it onto a <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/platforms/magento/">Magento platform</a>. Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp; expand our ecommerce business. The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design. I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice”. </em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb1.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend Certified Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/zend-certified-developers.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-25T11:24:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/zend-certified-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Edmonds Commerce employs a team of specialist PHP web developers who are all Zend Certified Engineers. This is a highly respected PHP qualification that ensures the highest standards of PHP development expertise. By achieving this certification we ensure that our developers have the kind of well rounded and deep understanding of the PHP language that can be utilised to achieve the highest quality production.</p>

<p>All of the e-commerce platforms, such as Magento and OpenCart are written in PHP and so the first thing to be sure of when you have a developer working on your projects is that they are very skilled in PHP itself as well as having an expert knowledge of the platform.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb3.png"></p>

<p>You can read all about the <a href="http://www.zend.com/services/certification/php-5-certification/" title="ZCE information" target="_blank">ZCE exam here</a>.</p>

<p>In a nutshell the exam is designed to test knowledge and skill that a professional PHP developer would need to tackle the kind of day to day issues they are likely to face. The exam covers a broad range of topics and really tests the in depth and broad knowledge of PHP that is required to really get the most out of the language and deliver the highest quality PHP development.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concrete5 Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/concrete5/concrete5-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T16:48:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/concrete5/concrete5-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.concrete5.org/">Concrete5</a> is a CMS system based on Zend Framework that uses Jquery for it&rsquo;s Javascript layer. Both of these are very popular and powerful frameworks that are really great to work with.</p>

<p>The thing that users really love though is the ability to edit Concrete5 pages on the fly making it very easy to use by non techies.</p>

<p>You can see the real ethos of the platform (from our techie point of view) <a href="http://www.concrete5.org/about/blog/client-work/an-open-letter-to-php-developers-about-concrete5/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you are looking for some expert PHP developers to help you get your Concrete5 site off the ground then <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend framework 2.0 released - now stable!]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/zend-framework-2-0-released-now-stable.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T10:11:04+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/zend-framework-2-0-released-now-stable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Exciting times in the php world, Zend Framework 2.0 stable has been released!</p>

<p>Magento is currently based on the 1.x branch of Zend, and Magento 2 is aiming to be on Zend Framework 2 (ZF2) so this puts the world one step closer to Magento 2.0.</p>

<p>The full announcement is <a href="http://framework.zend.com/blog/zend-framework-2-0-0-stable-released.html" title="Zend Framework 2 Release Blog Post">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
