<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oscommerce System Requirements on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/oscommerce-system-requirements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oscommerce System Requirements on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 09:28:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/oscommerce-system-requirements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce Version 3 System Requirements</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-version-3-system-requirements.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 09:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-version-3-system-requirements.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Harald has released some info about the minimum requirements of osCommerce version 3 alpha on the osCommerce blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.oscommerce.com/2009/03/16/minimum-requirements-for-oscommerce-online-merchant-v30-alpha-5/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It requires PHP 5.2 as a minimum (though I would personally recommend avoiding version 5.2.0 and going for the latest version if at all possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major reasons for this are the requirement for the object oriented mysqli interface for PHP and MySQL. It also requires PHP&amp;rsquo;s JSON encode functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON is a javascript data format a bit like XML or similar. It is used a lot of Web 2.0 style projects with a lot of asynchronous data transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This indicates that we can expect some nice Javascript based asynchronous tools that will hopefully be faster and easier to use than the current osCommerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;osCommerce is without a doubt one of the most popular open source ecommerce platforms and it is going to be really interesting to see how this new version compares with Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a long time user, hacker and fan of osCommerce I really wish them all the best of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>