<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Page on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Page on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:31:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Profiler Improved - Aoe_Profiler by Fabrizio Branca</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Magento profiler is useful when you are trying to discover what potential bottlenecks are in place in a specific Magento implementation that are slowing down the performance of the site. Often when doing this kind of analysis you might find that a particular block or extension is responsible for more than 70% of the total page load time. At this point you would choose to either optimise, cache or disable the block altogether to remove this performance bottleneck and improve page speed significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever tried to use Magento&amp;rsquo;s built in profiler you will no doubt agree with Fabrizio&amp;rsquo;s comments that, when you have it working, the output is hard to read and not really very useful in terms of seeing what is actually going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To aid with this process and give us a nice colourful and friendly user interface to the Magento profiler, Fabrizio has built a Magento module that extends the default profiler and makes it a much more useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the extension from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fbrnc/Aoe_Profiler&#34; title=&#34;Magento Aoe Profiler on Git Hub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;git hub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full blog story &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabrizio-branca.de/magento-profiler.html&#34; title=&#34;Fabrizio Branch blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like some help optimising the performance of your Magento store, feel free to get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today and we can assist in getting the very best performance from your Magento web site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got the Insecure Content on a Secure HTTPs Page Problem - Easy Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/got-the-insecure-content-on-a-secure-https-page-problem-easy-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 12:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/got-the-insecure-content-on-a-secure-https-page-problem-easy-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often you will see SSL warnings or errors related to insecure content being displayed on a secure page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be as simple as one javascript file or image that is being included via http rather than https, though some times this can be a bit tricky to track down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest solution is to hit this site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whynopadlock.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.whynopadlock.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will give you a clear report of the problems and should help you quickly find and fix them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively if you use Chrome you may see the details in the Javascript console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you know what elements are being called by http as opposed to https, you simply need to make them use https or remove them altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP DomPDF Bug - page_cache.cls.php on line 66 dompdf &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-dompdf-bug-page_cache-cls-php-on-line-66-dompdf-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 15:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-dompdf-bug-page_cache-cls-php-on-line-66-dompdf-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are struggling with a weird bug with DomPDF, something about it trying to connect to a postgres database..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well here is the solution that will get you up and running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;open the file and make the init method just return false&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;class Page_Cache {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    const DB_USER = &amp;quot;dompdf_page_cache&amp;quot;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    const DB_PASS = &amp;quot;some meaningful password&amp;quot;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    const DB_NAME = &amp;quot;dompdf_page_cache&amp;quot;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    static private $__connection = null;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    function init() {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        return false;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        if (is_null(self::$__connection)) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;            $con_str = &amp;quot;host=&amp;quot; . DB_HOST .&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;                    &amp;quot; dbname=&amp;quot; . self::DB_NAME .&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;                    &amp;quot; user=&amp;quot; . self::DB_USER .&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;                    &amp;quot; password=&amp;quot; . self::DB_PASS;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;            if (!self::$__connection = pg_connect($con_str))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;                throw new Exception(&amp;quot;Database connection failed.&amp;quot;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure really why this is trying to do this, obviously some kind of hard coded postgres caching system but anyway this fixed it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TkMan Linux Man Pages GUI Tool</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/tkman-linux-man-pages-gui-tool.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 07:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/tkman-linux-man-pages-gui-tool.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Want to browse your man pages but not in the console?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can of course hit the search engines but its got to be better to be looking at your own man pages so you know the instructions are for your machine, version etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
sudo apt-get install tkman

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you have a simple but useful man page reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to get dropped into the applications menu so you can add it manually by right clicking the Applications menu, selecting Edit Menus then go to System Tools and then hit the Add Item button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the title to Man Page Reader and the command as tkman. You can choose whatever icon you prefer by clicking the springboard icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you launch it, I found it a lot nicer to switch the fonts to arial and normal weight across the board. Its worth messing around with the other options as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento HomePage Layout All Messed Up &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-homepage-layout-all-messed-up-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 11:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-homepage-layout-all-messed-up-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are making some design changes to your store and all of a sudden your home page has gone totally messed up then this might be your solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working with designs and design packages in Magento you must remember that design packages are referenced not only in the System-&amp;gt;Configuration or System-&amp;gt;Design sections, but also on a per product or per CMS page basis as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you remove, rename or otherwise alter a design package then its going to cause problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are having issues - remember to not just look at the layout files etc, but also look in the admin CMS section and check what design package settings you have there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is very simple to fix once you have figured out what&amp;rsquo;s causing it, but can take hours of frustration if you get rail roaded into examining the files for the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>