<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: jaunty | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/jaunty/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-10T18:00:44+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Jaunty Filezilla]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-jaunty-filezilla.html"/>
    <updated>2009-06-24T09:49:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-jaunty-filezilla</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>This is as much a note to self plus anyone else googling for the words <b>Ubuntu</b> <i>Jaunty</i> and <b>Filezilla</b></p>

<p>The version that&rsquo;s in the repositories is a bit old and missing some cool features like synchronised browsing.</p>

<p>The latest version is available from GetDeb &ndash; <a href="http://www.getdeb.net/app/FileZilla"><a href="http://www.getdeb.net/app/FileZilla">http://www.getdeb.net/app/FileZilla</a></a></p>

<p>If you have already installed a version from the repos, totally remove it using syntaptic package manager. Then download the main filezilla package and the filezilla-common package from GetDeb. Install the filezilla-common package first and then the Filezilla package itself.</p>

<p>Sorted.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jaunty Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/jaunty-released.html"/>
    <updated>2009-04-23T20:14:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/jaunty-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been using the beta of Ubuntu Jaunty for about a month now and its been great. I&rsquo;m now upgrading my standard Ubuntu installs with this latest edition which went live today.</p>

<p>Many thanks to all the team at Canonical for continuing to produce an excellent open source desktop environment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could I Be Converted to a Mac User?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mac/could-i-be-converted-to-a-mac-user.html"/>
    <updated>2009-04-03T08:37:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mac/could-i-be-converted-to-a-mac-user</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Perhaps it&rsquo;s the 30" monitor that is seducing me, or the cute way windows can pop open and closed. Maybe it&rsquo;s the fact that as a Linux user I see a lot of things that I recognise thanks to OSX being a unix based OS.</p>

<p>Now that I have my Ubuntu Jaunty laptop and the Macs talking to each other I can use my laptop as a mobile web server and the Mac as my internet browsing and now that I am setting up some IDE&rsquo;s, possibly even my coding station.</p>

<p>On the downside though I am stuggling with the lack of right click, the US keyboard layout with the &ldquo; and @ switched round and the cramped [apple]+[c], [apple]+[v] copy and paste.</p>

<p>Still its interesting to finally get to play around on a Mac after hearing and reading all the hype and the almost evangelical Mac users. I have to admit they do have a point &ndash; its very slick.</p>

<p>I do love Ubuntu though, and Jaunty has proved an even nicer refinement of an already awesome OS. Plus the fact that I can run Ubuntu on commodity hardware and expect excellent performance, security and stability as standard.</p>

<p>I suspect (though I haven&rsquo;t done the sums) that value for money wise a Ubuntu based system will give me more for the same price when compared to a Mac. They aint cheap and that&rsquo;s for sure!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
