<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: extension | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/extension/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-10T18:00:44+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome AutoCorrect for Gmail (and Google Apps)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T13:54:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you use Gmail (also bundled with Google Apps) for your business then you probably write a lot of emails directly into the gmail interface. If you are like me you probably make teh the mistakes all teh time. (See what I did there!)</p>

<p>As the MD of Edmonds Commerce I probably write more emails than most people with everything from <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento">Magento</a> quotes, client communications, enquiries and maybe even the occasional personal email. At a guess I would say I write a good few thousand words per day. I should calculate that one day.</p>

<p>Well help is at hand with this wonderful chrome extension that will auto correct common typos as you type them in gmail. For me this is a real productivity booster as I type fast but badly and this really tidies up a lot of my common mistakes meaning less <em>backspace</em> and more <em>getting stuff done</em>.</p>

<p>You can grab the extension <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ezautocorrect-for-gmail/fholdolknchpdbajhpdenookmikblmda/related" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>I hope you find it useful. On another note, if you aren&rsquo;t currently using Google Apps (its free you know) and would like to look at transitioning your business to the system then get in touch with us and we would be happy to help you with it. I can not recommend the service enough to be honest, even if you go for the paid version the cost is negligible really. Smaller companies should be find with the free version though which you really can&rsquo;t argue with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Auto Populate Form Fields - Form Fuzzer]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-auto-populate-form-fields-form-fuzzer.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T10:42:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-auto-populate-form-fields-form-fuzzer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you ever used Webmaster Tools in Firefox but have now switched to using Chrom(e|ium) instead then you probably miss the form filler &ndash; especially if you ever need to test checkouts or other form intensive web site user stories.</p>

<p>A nice little extension that I just discovered takes care of this, <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/cbpplldpcdcfejdaldmnfhlodoadjhii" target="_blank">Chrome Form Fuzzer</a>.</p>

<p>You can configure it for simple form filling or with a little creative configuration it could easily be used for security testing and more in depth testing to ensure that input is being sanitised and filtered properly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Aliases for Bookmarks/Links Extension - Great Timesaver]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-aliases-for-bookmarkslinks-extension-great-timesaver.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T10:50:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-aliases-for-bookmarkslinks-extension-great-timesaver</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a few URLS you are constantly going to and you would prefer a quick keyboard based way of going to them without having to type full URLs then this little extension could be for you.</p>

<p>The concept is very simple. You can create an alias word (eg phpmyadmin) which then redirects to your full phpmyadmin URL.</p>

<p>When you first install it you might set up some aliases and try to use them but get redirected to the google search results pages for that word instead. The extension author has worked around this behaviour by requiring you to put an &ldquo;a &rdquo;, the letter a followed by a space, before your alias.</p>

<p>Setting up the aliases is simple and I can already see this becoming one of my must have extensions.</p>

<p>Check it out for yourselves:
<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hnmffkbofelpmfnimaicmkdhimnaegla" title="Chrome Link Alias" target="_blank"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hnmffkbofelpmfnimaicmkdhimnaegla">https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hnmffkbofelpmfnimaicmkdhimnaegla</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Custom Product Type as Configurable Product]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-custom-product-type-as-configurable-product.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-20T15:36:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-custom-product-type-as-configurable-product</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have created a new product type and need to enable it to be included with configurable products you need to let Magento know that it should allow your product type to work with configurable products. To do this open your config xml and add the following xml.</p>

<p>```xml</p>

<p><config></p>

<pre><code>&lt;global&gt;
    &lt;catalog&gt;
        &lt;product&gt;
            &lt;type&gt;
                &lt;configurable translate="label" module="catalog"&gt;
                    &lt;allow_product_types&gt;
                        &lt;custom_type_name/&gt;
                    &lt;/allow_product_types&gt;
                &lt;/configurable&gt;
            &lt;/type&gt;
        &lt;/product&gt;
    &lt;/catalog&gt;
&lt;/global&gt;
</code></pre>

<p></config></p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This tells Magento to include your product type for use with configurable products.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento and eBay integration now Free]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-and-ebay-integration-now-free.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-11T12:46:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-and-ebay-integration-now-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the acquisition of Magento by eBay, one of the major extension developers, Ess, now has an agreement with eBay/Magento to provide their integration extension free.</p>

<p><a href="http://m2epro.ess-ua.com/">Here&rsquo;s their site</a> and <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/magento-connect/ebay-magento-integration-order-importing-and-stock-level-synchronization.html">here&rsquo;s the extension on Magento Connect</a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also worth knowing that the extension is avaiable on Magento Go, so if you&rsquo;re looking for hosted-only, management-free eCommerce with integration with eBay, that might be an option.  Remember that Magento Go is not extendable by third parties though as it is a locked-down solution.</p>

<p>Anyway, some of the features of the extension are :&ndash;</p>

<ul>
<li>Stock Level Synchronisation between eBay and Magento Stores</li>
<li>Create eBay listing templates which can create eBay listings direct from your Magento products</li>
<li>Multiple eBay accounts per store</li>
<li>Automatically leave feedback</li>
<li>eBay transaction and order import</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
