<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: internet explorer | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/internet-explorer/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-15T18:49:34+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Browsers Currently Supported By Google]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/browsers/browsers-currently-supported-by-google.html"/>
    <updated>2013-12-06T18:49:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/browsers/browsers-currently-supported-by-google</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Apps, such as Gmail, Calendar, Docs etc lean heavily on Javascript to create fluid web applications. Naturally this requires up to date browsers to take advantage of functionality and technologies.</p>

<p>Google&rsquo;s policy on browser support is quite strict, especially where Internet Explorer is concerned. <strong>For Chrome only the latest version is supported because of its auto-update policy. Internet Explorer, Firefox and Safari are supported in the most recent, and previous version.</strong> The third most recent browser is no longer supported as soon as a new one is released. No official support is offered for Opera.</p>

<p>This is particularly strict for Internet Explorer, since its versioning is vastly different from that of Chrome and Firefox, with the latter incrementing the version for much smaller changes, and being more frequent. Another effect is that ruling out what is currently IE9 rules out both Windows XP and Windows Vista &ndash; both OSs currently supported by Microsoft.</p>

<p>Naturally this doesn&rsquo;t mean that the products won&rsquo;t work, anjd in many cases they were developed before support was dropped for specific versions. In some cases however it does enforce a more simplistic UI, such as redirecting very old browsers to a Basic HTML view for Gmail</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading JSON without Reading JSON!]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/programming/reading-json-without-reading-json.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T16:16:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/programming/reading-json-without-reading-json</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>JSON is a well structure interoperable way of passing data between systems. It&rsquo;s a good way of passing large amount of data into a web page for JavaScript to process and between system on the internet regardless of there architecture or programming language.</p>

<p>JSON is one of the hardest data structure to read directly as a human in it&rsquo;s RAW format compared to other formal grammars such as XML, YAML or ini.</p>

<p>Fortunately there is an easy trick that you can do with Chrome, Firefox with Firebug and even Opera and IE9!</p>

<p>Take the JSON you have, wrap it in &ldquo;eval()&rdquo; the same as you would if you where writing a web page (because it is just JavaScript after all) run it and every modern browser this was tested with should allow you to inspect the resulting data structure.</p>

<p>Example JSON:
<code>
{&ldquo;glossary&rdquo;:{&ldquo;title&rdquo;:&ldquo;example glossary&rdquo;,&ldquo;GlossDiv&rdquo;:{&ldquo;title&rdquo;:&ldquo;S&rdquo;,&ldquo;GlossList&rdquo;:{&ldquo;GlossEntry&rdquo;:{&ldquo;ID&rdquo;:&ldquo;SGML&rdquo;,&ldquo;SortAs&rdquo;:&ldquo;SGML&rdquo;,&ldquo;GlossTerm&rdquo;:&ldquo;Standard Generalized Markup Language&rdquo;,&ldquo;Acronym&rdquo;:&ldquo;SGML&rdquo;,&ldquo;Abbrev&rdquo;:&ldquo;ISO 8879:1986&rdquo;,&ldquo;GlossDef&rdquo;:{&ldquo;para&rdquo;:&ldquo;A meta-markup language, used to create markup languages such as DocBook.&rdquo;,&ldquo;GlossSeeAlso&rdquo;:[&ldquo;GML&rdquo;,&ldquo;XML&rdquo;]},&ldquo;GlossSee&rdquo;:&ldquo;markup&rdquo;}}}}}
</code></p>

<table>
<tr>
<td>
Firefox with Firebug:
<img src="/assets/firefoxjson-600x328.png">
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Chrome:
<img src="/assets/chromejson-600x313.png">
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Opera:
<img src="/assets/bhtAjti.png">
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
Internet Explorer 9:
Note: To see this structure you need to click the "Add watcher" link displayed upon running the code.
<img src="/assets/ie9json.png">
</td>
</tr>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freely Available Windows Virtual Machines for Testing IE]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/freely-available-windows-virtual-machines-for-testing-ie.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-13T18:06:26+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/freely-available-windows-virtual-machines-for-testing-ie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you need to test your code against the (ahem) interesting interpretations of the various iterations of Internet Explorer then this is a great resource for you.</p>

<p>Turns out Microsoft have thrown web devs a bone by offering free virtual machine images with the various IE/OS flavours for you to test on. You can download them <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/download/en/details.aspx?id=11575">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you use VirtualBox and also a *nix based operating system such as Linux or OSX then you can use <a href="https://github.com/xdissent/ievms">this, frankly awesome, bash script</a> to automatically download one or all of these machines and fully set them up in VirtualBox for you.</p>

<p>VirtualBox, if you are not aware, is a freely available Virtualisation platform allowing you to run other operating systems on your desktop. On todays powerful machines its perfectly easy to run Linux as your core operating system and then for either running windows only apps or for testing dodgy browsers, you can fire up one of these VMs.</p>

<p>Bear in mind that they are not for keeps, you will need to reset them every 30 days due to the fact that they can not be activated. For our purposes though this is not really a problem.</p>

<h2>Usage</h2>


<p>Please note all of this has been copied and pasted from <a href="http://www.webupd8.org/2011/09/test-websites-in-internet-explorer-9-8.html">here</a>. Posted here for reference only, all original attribution and credit goes to webupd8.</p>

<ol>
<li>Before proceeding, make sure you have the latest VirtualBox installed &ndash; you can find Ubuntu installation instructions HERE. You&rsquo;ll also need &ldquo;curl&rdquo; (for both Linux and OSX) and &ldquo;unrar&rdquo; (Linux only). In Ubuntu, install them using the command below:
```</li>
</ol>


<p>sudo apt-get install curl unrar</p>

<p>```</p>

<ol>
<li>To download and run the CODE, use the following command in a terminal:
```</li>
</ol>


<p>curl -s <a href="https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh">https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh</a> | bash</p>

<p>```
If you want to check out the bash source before running it, you can find it @ GitHub.</p>

<p>The above command will download Windows WHDs for IE7, IE8 and IE9. If you only need one Internet Explorer version, you can run:
```</p>

<p>curl -s <a href="https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh">https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh</a> | IEVMS_VERSIONS=&ldquo;9&rdquo; bash</p>

<p>```
Where &ldquo;9&rdquo; is the IE version you want (you can also add two versions here, like &ldquo;7 9&rdquo;).</p>

<p>At this point, the download should start and it will take a while so be patient.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu + VirtualBox + XP = Easy]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-virtualbox-xp-easy.html"/>
    <updated>2009-06-26T08:39:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-virtualbox-xp-easy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>I have recently had the misfortune of stepping out of my usual developers bubble and having to do a bit of graphic web design. Of course that means that not only did I have to try to make something look good with my meagre design skills, but then I had to worry about making sure it worked in IE&hellip;</p>

<p>Web Designers&hellip; I FEEL YOUR PAIN</p>

<p>As I only use Ubuntu or Mac&rsquo;s, testing in IE is not exactly easy. Or at least it wasn&rsquo;t until I decided to take the plunge and set up XP as a virtual machine. It&rsquo;s really really easy on Ubuntu.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Go to the Applications->Add / Remove system</p></li>
<li><p>type virtualbox in the searchbox</p></li>
<li><p>Install VirtualBox OSE</p></li>
<li><p>Go to the Applications->Accessories menu and launch VirtualBox OSE</p></li>
<li><p>Hit the blue New icon in the top left</p></li>
<li><p>Follow the wizard. I used the following settings:</p></li>
</ol>


<p>6.a name: xp</p>

<p>6.b: memory: 192mb</p>

<ol>
<li><p>At the boot disk stage, you need to hit the New button to create and install a new &lsquo;boot disk&rsquo;.</p></li>
<li><p>Whack your XP CD in the drive and install it.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>By default the right hand ctrl key is your key for escaping out of your virtual machine. This means that if you click on your virtual machine with your mouse (for example to go through to multiple steps required to tell XP that you want English UK keyboard, and surprise surprise an English Keyboard layout and furthermore you don&rsquo;t really need to install English US as a separate language)</p>

<p>Note &ndash; to access your Ubuntu environment you will need to have folder sharing set up, the virtual machine will see the host Ubuntu like another computer on a network.</p>

<p>If like me you need to edit the hosts file to point a dummy domain to your local development environment, the IP address you need to use is 10.0.2.2</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Internet Explorer under Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20development/linux/ubuntu/web%20design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux.html"/>
    <updated>2008-02-19T16:20:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20development/linux/ubuntu/web%20design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Ubuntu Linux is undoubtedly the most successful desktop version of linux available today. It has managed to tempt across many dedicated windows users with its easy installation procedure, comprehensive bundle of applications including open office and firefox, its greater security and reduced vulnerability to internet viruses and malware. And of course the fact that it is free to download and install.</p>

<p>For a web designer, it is nice to have a sleek desktop environment to code in whilst being able to run a full LAMP stack web server as the localhost &ndash; meaning that designing and developing web sites is a breeze.</p>

<p>However, there are times when you simply need to check that a design is going to work with Internet Explorer. Microsoft&rsquo;s Internet Explorer web browser is bundled with windows and is therefore the most popular web browser at the moment. However as a web designer it causes problems as it often behaves erratically or unexpectedly. For this reason a web designer always needs to make sure that they check their designs in Internet Explorer.</p>

<p>Another reason that Ubuntu users may need to use Internet Explorer is to log into certain sites which are not compatible with anything other than Internet Explorer. This is a real pet hate as it is real sign of laziness on the part of the web designers not to ensure that their web sites are accessible by all web browsers. Unfortunately the sites that tend to be like this are the ones that you really need, such as online banking sites. Its probably something to do with sloppy handling of ssl secure and insecure content, but I am not sure on that one.</p>

<p>Anyway &ndash; to save you having to maintain a windows installation and reboot everytime you need to check something in Internet Explorer &ndash; there is the excellent <a href="http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page" target="_blank">IEs 4 Linux package</a>. This great package allows you to easily install Internet Explorer under Ubuntu (or any other version of Linux).</p>

<p>You need to have WINE installed and working, and also have the cabextractor working. Both of these packages are available in the syntaptic package manager in Ubuntu.</p>

<p><strong>Related Resources</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/">http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/</a></a></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux">http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux</a></a></p>

<p><a href="http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/">http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/</a></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux/" rel="nofollow"><a href="http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux">http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
