<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: modifications | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/modifications/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-01T12:08:44+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce Essential Modifications]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/oscommerce/web%20development/php/programming/web%20design/oscommerce-essential-modifications.html"/>
    <updated>2008-02-21T16:09:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/oscommerce/web%20development/php/programming/web%20design/oscommerce-essential-modifications</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>osCommerce is an awesome ecommerce package. It has many critics and this is mainly due to the fact that unlike many modern open source packages it is not really ready to run &ldquo;out of the box&rdquo;. That is a drawback, however it is not really so much of a drawback when you take into account that anyone that would want to establish an ecommerce presence is going to be very keen to modify the package to make the site look and feel unique.</p>

<p>This is where osCommerce really shines as it is very easy to modify and there is a huge user base with literally thousands of plugin modifications or &ldquo;contributions&rdquo; in osCommerce speak which can help you to make your store work in exactly the way you want.</p>

<p>There are some things though that are highly recommened for every osCommerce store though:</p>

<p><strong>1. Search Engine Optimisation</strong></p>

<p>As standard, osCommerce really is not very search engine friendly. Search engine friendliness is the first step towards search engine optimisation. This of course means that there are a fair few things you need to do to your store to make it truly search engine optimised. However, they are worth the hassle (especially if you get us to do it for you) and once you have some SEO modifications implemented, you will be able to start to get indexed and gaining visitors from the search engines without having to pay per click.</p>

<p><strong>2. Speed</strong></p>

<p>There are a few key things that every store should really do to speed up osCommerce. If however you expect your store to have a lot of visitors and/or display a lot of products and categories then you will really benefit from giving the front end of the site a bit of an overhaul in certain areas. The speed improvements possible are really quite dramatic and can make the difference between your visitors sailing through the site straight to the page or product they want or them getting bogged down, bored and finally leaving before they even get where they want to be.</p>

<p><strong>3. Security</strong></p>

<p>osCommerce is pretty secure out of the box. The admin side obviously needs some password protection and can be made more secure if it is felt neccessary. An easy modification is to simply rename the admin folder into something that only you know.</p>

<p><strong>4. User Friendly</strong></p>

<p>The osCommerce ecommerce system is fairly user friendly from the outset. One area that many people prefer to modify though is the checkout procedure which can be a bit long winded for some.</p>

<p><strong>5. Easy Administration</strong></p>

<p>Admin side there is a whole host of things that you can do to make your and your employees' lives easier. For example adding products one by one using the admin tool can be a bit tedious and slow. Easypopulate is an awesome addition to any osCommerce store allowing easy population and editing of the product catalogue using your favourite spreadsheet program. We like Open Office for this task.</p>

<p>Part of the joy of running your own web site is that you are free to edit, change, personalise and improve it to your hearts content. Some things you will add because they make a real difference to your bottom line and some things you will add just because you think its a good idea or will be cool. The great thing with osCommerce is that you can edit it and make it work the way you want.</p>

<p>If you are not confident with PHP or the change you want to make is a bit more complex than you can handle, then we are more than happy to get in there and give you a hand!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
