<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: paypal | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/paypal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-27T12:35:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comixininos]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/comixininos.html"/>
    <updated>2011-08-05T15:25:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/comixininos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<h2> PayPal Problems </h2>


<p><a href="http://www.comixininos.com/index.php/">Comixininos</a> currently face problems with paypal as confirmations are not being sent through when payments are made. We are fixing this so that customers can clearly see when payments have gone through so that they are not confused at which step of the process they are on.</p>

<h3> Football Fantasy In Spain </h3>


<p>Comixininos are e-commerce Spanish retailers that specialise in selling products from a fantasy football range. They sell small figures which can be used to play games for children or to be brought as collectable items.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Golferwithin.com - One Page Magento Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/one-page-magento-store.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T16:57:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/one-page-magento-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Single Page Magento Store With Affiliate Program and PayPal Link</h2>


<p>The aim of this project was to condense a Magento store into a single page, offering both product information and payment options. The system is to integrate with PayPal and a custom affiliate system.</p>

<h3>Golfer Within</h3>


<p>Run by Roseanna Leaton, one of the leading practitioners of self-improvement. A keen 9-handicap golfer, Roseanna combined her knowledge of the game and the mind mechanism to create the acclaimed Golfer Within recordings which enable any player to <a href=”http://www.golferwithin.com/”>lower their handicap</a></p>

<p><img src="/assets/golferwithin.jpg"></p>

<p>This project asked for a one click option method linking Magento to PayPal and then back again, without having to use the normal checkout pages. This required creating custom magento controllers so the method wouldn&rsquo;t interfere with the other stores running off the same back end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Paypal Transactions not Appearing + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-paypal-transactions-not-appearing-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-11-19T10:59:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-paypal-transactions-not-appearing-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are scratching your head trying to figure out why your paypal transactions are not showing up in your Magento admin despite everything being set up perfectly then this may well be your solution.</p>

<p>As recently discussed on the unofficial <a href="http://www.magento-forum.co.uk" title="magento forum">magento forum</a>, the paypal email address is <strong>case sensitive</strong>, so if the case on either paypal and Magento do not perfectly match then things won&rsquo;t work.</p>

<p>Double check the email address in both places and then ensure they match up.</p>

<p><a href="http://magento-forum.co.uk/viewtopic.php?f=3&t=520&p=1808">Heres the full post on the forum</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
