<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pci on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/pci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pci on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 10:20:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/pci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Stratus - Magento Going into the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-stratus-magento-going-into-the-cloud.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 10:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-stratus-magento-going-into-the-cloud.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its an old battle on forums all over the web - which is better, a hosted solution or hosting your own solution on your own server, based on a platform such as Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well a recent new development from Magento indicates that this distinction is about to get a lot more blurry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/stratus&#34;&gt;http://www.magentocommerce.com/stratus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magento’s Project Stratus is the next evolution in eCommerce; an on-demand platform more powerful and flexible than any other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the Full FAQ:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Project Stratus FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What is Magento project Stratus?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Stratus is Magento&amp;rsquo;s next-generation on-demand eCommerce platform. At its core, Stratus is an online version of our award-winning eCommerce platform. Everything you already know and love about the Magento platform is available with this hosted service. Stratus creates more choice for merchants to select the product and platform that best fits their needs. Stratus will empower merchants and developers to customize, modify, extend and integrate a hosted store as if it were their own code running on their own servers &amp;hellip; an unprecedented capability in the market today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I did not receive a registration key, how can I request one?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the request an invite key link and complete the request form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What happens after I apply to join the beta?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Magento team will review your application.  Once you are accepted, you will receive an email with a unique link to complete your registration and activate your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How long will the beta program run?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beta will run into early 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What happens at the end of the beta program?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the conclusion of the beta program, the service will convert to a generally available, paid-service.  Your account/store will automatically convert into a production account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How is this different from other Magento versions?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This service will provide the same core eCommerce functionality as on-premise versions.  However, rather than downloading the software and running it on your own hardware, Magento provides the software to you as a service.  You&amp;rsquo;ll simply log in to your web-based control panel to manage your account and your store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How much will the service cost once the beta is complete?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magento is still determining the pricing for the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What type of support and SLA do you offer during the beta?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Beta period merchants can expect that there will be periods when the site might not be available as we work to improve the offering based upon your feedback.  Magento will strive to make sure any outages occur at off-hours and will notify our merchants in case of an expected outage.  During the Beta period, merchants will be provided email and phone based support at no additional cost.  Once the platform becomes generally available, support will be available on a tiered basis depending upon the needs of our merchants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Is the Beta PCI compliant&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the beta service is PCI compliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento PCI Compliance and PA-DSS</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-pci-compliance-and-pa-dss.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 11:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-pci-compliance-and-pa-dss.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across a forum post which I would like to quote here as I think it sums things up nicely. You can see the original post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nublue.co.uk/forums/post/622/#p622&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Community edition has not been verified as PA-DSS compliant, which is not the same as PCI-DSS compliancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PCI-DSS is the compliancy of your online environment, practices, software etc.  That is the standard that is required to be able to process on-site payments.
PA-DSS is not the same, it is part of PCI-DSS.  It&amp;rsquo;s a standard for the software that you are using for processing payments, just as PCI-DSS is the standard for the merchants processing payments on-site.  PA-DSS is the standard whereby the software provider subjects the software to a rigorous set of standards, tests and development practices (all viewable on the PA DSS Website) to confirm that the PA-DSS requirements are entirely met.
Anyone using Community edition has 2 options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 - use an off-site payment gateway, so none of this matters (the gateway will be PA-DSS software running in a PCI-DSS environment and PCI-DSS is not therefore required) - this is by far the easiest option available!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 - verify the software as PA-DSS compliant yourself by going through the PCI-DSS questionnaire and confirming the relevant data.
There is nowhere in the PCI-DSS questionnaire that says, &amp;ldquo;if your payment software has not been certified as PA-DSS compliant, you cannot be PCI-DSS compliant&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the basic tenets of PA-DSS compliancy is an essential part of becoming PCI-DSS compliant.
The only thing that PA-DSS provides, is a guarantee that any part of the compliancy questionnaire related to PA-DSS requirements (encryption of card #&amp;rsquo;s, cardholder data etc) is a certified yes, that does not require any investigation and confirmation from the client first.  These areas are all listed within the PCI-DSS SAQ (Self Assessment Questionnaire).  There is also a lengthy PA-DSS document on the website that lists the requirements of PA-DSS - the community edition, presumably, doesn&amp;rsquo;t meet these requirements, as it is a hook for paying for the Professional or Enterprise editions, as they have in turn paid and worked on having those editions verified, but don&amp;rsquo;t see the benefits to implementing this for the Community edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas the Pro/Enterprise editions will include certain best-practice features (such as auto-expiring passwords for instance) and of course are PA-DSS compliant, it&amp;rsquo;s also worth mentioning while we&amp;rsquo;re on the subject that they do not anywhere explicitly state that the Community edition is not PA-DSS compliant&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really means the PCI-DSS responsibility is further placed on the clients&amp;rsquo; shoulders; PA-DSS means you have one less thing to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>