<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: web design | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/web-design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-05T20:04:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is User Experience & Why Bother?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/what-is-user-experience-why-bother.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:50:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/what-is-user-experience-why-bother</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are running an E-Commerce store then you&rsquo;ve probably received various offers to improve the online shopping experience, optimize conversion rate and so on. All these offers are a part of a user experience. For example &ndash; if you receive an offer to improve your online store&rsquo;s shopping experience then most likely the service provider will go thorough the sales funnel, get some valuable input by <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/conversion-rate-optimization/using-advanced-analytics-to-improve-conversion-rates/" title="Using Advanced Analytics to Improve Conversion Rates" target="_blank">setting up and analysing your website metrics</a>, conduct a user survey by online forms and ask directly to the customers via email or even give them a private call.
All of the above is necessary to really understand how your users (customers) interact with your site, how:</p>

<ul>
    <li>valuable</li>

    <li>findable</li>

    <li>usable</li>

    <li>desirable</li>

    <li>accessible</li>

    <li>credible</li>
</ul>


<p>they found your site or offer to be. As for those who need a definition &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_experience" title="User Experience - Wikipedia" target="_blank">here&rsquo;s what wikipedia says about user experience</a> &ndash; <em>User experience (UX) involves a person&rsquo;s emotions about using a particular product, system or service. User experience highlights the experiential, affective, meaningful and valuable aspects of human-computer interaction and product ownership. Additionally, it includes a person’s perceptions of the practical aspects such as utility, ease of use and efficiency of the system. User experience is subjective in nature because it is about individual perception and thought with respect to the system. User experience is dynamic as it is constantly modified over time due to changing circumstances and new innovations.</em></p>

<h2>So, what elements the user experience should contain?</h2>


<p><img src="/assets/UserExperience.png"></p>

<h3>Valuable</h3>


<p>The solution must deliver measurable value for site owners or interested group. It can be conversions, leads, subscriptions, etc.</p>

<h3>Findable</h3>


<p>Make it easy to find what your target audience is looking for, not only by optimizing search engines but focusing on internal navigation</p>

<h3>Usable</h3>


<p>Ease of use is extremely important; it must be intuitive and fluid. You need to create a funnel that leads your audience to your goal effectively</p>

<h3>Desirable</h3>


<p>Your target audience must have a strong desire to use your solution whether it’s for content, experience or emotions</p>

<h3>Accessible</h3>


<p>The solution must be easily accessible for your target audience – whether it’s technological requirements or people with disabilities</p>

<h3>Credible</h3>


<p>Your solution must be credible by all means. It has to build trust in your particular target audience by including important credibility factors</p>

<h2>What’s In It For You?</h2>


<p>The benefits are pretty obvious. In this stage we help you to identify your market and learn about your target audience behavior and needs as much as possible. These real world insights are extremely valuable and perform a key role in a project life-cycle. In short – careful planning allows you to focus on most beneficial features first and drive more revenue with minimum effort.</p>

<h2>Why Plan?</h2>


<p>When embarking on a project to launch or relaunch an e-commerce web site it can seem like a daunting and overwhelming prospect. The danger is that without <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/web-project-management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow/" title="Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management" target="_blank">proper planning and project management</a>, the final outcome can be much less effective and efficient than if proper planning and preliminary research is used to define clear goals and then ensure these are met</p>

<h2>Why Work With Us?</h2>


<p>Edmonds Commerce is specifically focused on E-Commerce projects. We have experienced and professional team of certified Magento and Zend developers, User Experience, Design and Strategy experts. We tend to become partners and build a lasting business relationship which is proven by our long term clients of some of most promising UK’s e-commerce stores and businesses all over the Europe.</p>

<h2>What’s Next?</h2>


<p>We are happy to hear more about your upcoming or existing e-commerce project. Please get in touch with us and explain your vision, goals, requirements and deadlines. Discover how we can help you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Great Way of Cross-platform Prototyping - Invisionapp]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:16:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at Edmonds Commerce we are always looking for new techniques and tools that allow to speed up and ease our internal work-flow which results in faster and more<a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/web-project-management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow/" title="Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management" target="_blank"> effective project planning</a>, management and development. We love to involve and closely collaborate with our clients as much as possible.</p>

<p>Just found this awesome c<a href=" http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="Invisionapp - cross platform prototyping tool" target="_blank">ross-platform mockup and interactive prototyping tool &ndash; Invision</a> &ndash; which has an amazing feedback feature which could replace long email conversations. It is filled with lots of  active guides and how-to&rsquo;s which makes it really understandable for clients. Actually, I find this part the most important about all the application. So far there have been a serious struggle with this particular phase &ndash; work showoff, iterations and final sign off. That is a long journey for traditional email conversations.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/InvisionApp-Design.png"> InvisionApp interface</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent just a few moments with it, but it looks like 135.004 people in 70 countries aren&rsquo;t trusting this awesome tool just for fun. (as it is stated on <a href="http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="invisionapp homepage" target="_blank">invisionapp homepage</a> when writing this post) Feels like I&rsquo;ve finally found a well designed tool which has the most of the essential features.</p>

<p>Looking forward to take our clients on the journey of designing and iterating on their projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating & Testing a Responsive Design Has Never Been Easier]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:02:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/Reflow.png"></p>

<p>Got my hands on these two marvellous responsive design tools from Adobe &ndash; <a href="http://www.adobe.com/EdgeReflow" title="Adobe Edge Reflow Homepage" target="_blank">Edge Reflow</a> and <a href="http://www.adobe.com/EdgeInspect‎" title="Adboe Edge Inspect" target="_blank">Edge Inspect</a>.</p>

<p>Although Reflow is still in Beta, it has brilliant concept. Never the less <u>it has a potential to redefine the way of how we create and test responsive designs</u> once and for all. A much more effective way. It actually allows you to visualise everything blazing fast by adding different break points and adjusting the layout and design for each of them. Going further &ndash; you can test that right away on most of the devices with Edge Inspect. It&rsquo;s that dead easy &ndash; just install the app and connect your phone or tablet with your computer to see how the design actually works on the target device.</p>

<p>There are plenty of good resources available that will get you started in no time. The effort of learning it is definitely worth every minute you spend. The most useful resource that I&rsquo;ve found so far is the <a href="http://http://www.adobe.com/devnet/edge-reflow/articles/edge-reflow-getting-started.html" title="Edge Reflow Guide for Beginners" target="_blank">original Edge Reflow guide from Adobe itself</a> It is a beginner level guide. Once you understand the core principles everything else is dead easy.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/reflow_inspect.png"></p>

<p>Remember, that it is still in beta. Let&rsquo;s help Adobe team to create more remarkable products and post our ideas of improvements it <a href="http://forums.adobe.com/community/edge_reflow_preview?view=idea" title="Edge Reflow Forum" target="_blank">Edge Reflow forum.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Prototype For Mobile Devices Fast & Easy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/how-to-prototype-for-mobile-devices-fast-easy.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-29T11:29:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/how-to-prototype-for-mobile-devices-fast-easy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/ProtoIO.png"></p>

<p>As a designer who is keen on usability and user centric, well tested web systems I was in a desperate need of silly fast and useful mobile prototyping system. Up until recently I’ve used paper prototyping and later uploading images on various smart phones (always struggling with inaccurate representation of actual interface size, look and feel of the interactions).</p>

<p>Thankfully, that is the past and the future holds much brighter and functional solution for <a href="https://proto.io/" title="Proto.io - Rapid fast mobile prototyping" target="_blank">rapid fast mobile prototyping thanks to Proto.io </a></p>

<p>I see that they have been around for a while, which only brings lots of benefits to us – usability testers and designers. Prototyping application interface is improved and it has some really good functionality, although there is still room to grow like to support keyboard commands, more tutorials and find a way of making the overall work flow more intuitive as I found it hard to get into. Thankfully, proto.io team has created video tutorials for some of the most important questions.</p>

<p>Once I got the basic idea and figured out some work-arounds, I was able to upload my mobile site design in the application and create a working prototype. It is awesome, how fast and easy it is to test the prototypes on various devices. The most important feature I found is that I can access the fully working prototype from whatever device.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responsive Web Design for Mobile and Tablet Optimised Web Sites]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T17:42:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are at all involved or exposed to the world of web design and web development then you have no doubt heard of the phrase &ldquo;responsive&rdquo; web design. If you browse the popular theme sites for themes for platforms like WordPress and Magento then you can see responsive themes becoming more popular.</p>

<p>So what does it mean and how does it work?</p>

<h3>What does Responsive Web Design Mean?</h3>


<p>Responsive designs change the layout and visible content on a page depending on the width, height and other factors of the device or window rendering the page. You can generally test out responsive designs by simply unmaximising a browser window and then resizing it down to smaller sizes such as 320 pixels wide. On a normal design you would be quite lucky if the site still rendered in a readable way at that width. More than likely you will only be able to see a fraction of the page and would have to sideways scroll to see the rest of it.</p>

<p>On a responsively designed site, the layout would change as the screen width gets smaller. It might hide certain elements such as side columns and may make things rearrange in a more vertical way to allow them to be displayed without the need for side scrolling.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, this is what responsive web design means.</p>

<h3>How Does Responsive Web Design Work?</h3>


<p>Responsive web design works by using a CSS3 technique called <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/" title="W3C Media Queries Information" target="_blank">Media Queries</a>.</p>

<p>CSS has had the concept of media specific style sheets for quite some time. Traditionally though this was limited to print and screen, allowing for example to remove background images from a page when printing and perhaps adjust font family and size for better printing results.</p>

<p>The media queries functionality extends this concept significantly, allowing custom style rules to be applied based upon a range of differnt media options. The most commonly used of these for responsive web design are width and height.</p>

<p>The full list of properties that can be utilised with media queries include:</p>

<blockquote>width
height
device-width
device-height
orientation
aspect-ratio
device-aspect-ratio
color
color-index
monochrome
resolution
scan
grid</blockquote>




<h3>Get Your Web Site Working Responsively</h3>


<p>If you want to upgrade your web site to use responsive design techniques to better support the wide range of internet devices in use today then <strong><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch</a></strong> with Edmonds Commerce today to discuss how we can help you.</p>

<h3>Some Useful and Interesting Links</h3>


<p><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/ " target="_blank"><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/">http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/</a></a>
<a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/" target="_blank"><a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/">http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/</a></a>
<a href="http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries" target="_blank"><a href="http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries">http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries</a></a>
<a href="http://mediaqueri.es/" target="_blank"><a href="http://mediaqueri.es/">http://mediaqueri.es/</a></a>
<a href="http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/" target="_blank"><a href="http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/">http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
