<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extensions on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/extensions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extensions on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 13:51:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/extensions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase the Stabilty of your Magento cron</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/increase-the-stabilty-of-your-magento-cron.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 13:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/increase-the-stabilty-of-your-magento-cron.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when your cron process in Magento seems to not be working it is worth doubling up the ways it gets executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason for this is various extensions (notably EERP from boostmyshop) set up an override to ensure that the same cron task is not run a second time if it&amp;rsquo;s still running when the first run happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the cli setup for php is not configured with the same timeouts etc. that the web setup is.  Therefore one thing that can make your cron more &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; is to use wget or curl to fetch the cron.php file rather than (or as well as) running the cron.sh script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what to add to the server&amp;rsquo;s crontab (/etc/crontab or crontab -e) to use wget to fire off the cron :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
* * * * * /usr/bin/wget -O- www.mycoolsite.com/cron.php &amp;gt; /dev/null 2&amp;gt; /dev/null

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That of course needs the url changing to match your domain.  It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that having output and stderror piped to /dev/null in a crontab is probably not the best practice but given that any module can create cron tasks that output stuff, your sysadmin might dislike getting that emailed to them!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Handy Extensions</title>
      <link>http://example.com/chrome/chrome-handy-extensions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 09:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/chrome/chrome-handy-extensions.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you use Google Chrome then you might like this list of 10 decent Chrome extensions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://webdesignledger.com/tools/10-time-saving-google-chrome-extensions&#34;&gt;http://webdesignledger.com/tools/10-time-saving-google-chrome-extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see if Chrome goes the way of Firefox with an over abundance of plugins gradually eroding the performance of the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>