<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Static Blocks on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/static-blocks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Static Blocks on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 11:47:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/static-blocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Methods from a Magento Static Block</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/calling-methods-from-a-static-block.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 11:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/calling-methods-from-a-static-block.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had to develop a bespoke CMS within magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the requirements was that the system should be very easy to customise, and should use the existing Pages and Static blocks functionality within magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted the ability to call a block that I had created from with a static block. Magento allows you to do this using the code below
&lt;code&gt;
{{block type=&amp;lsquo;companyname/path_to_block&amp;rsquo; name=&amp;lsquo;custom.block&amp;rsquo; template=&amp;lsquo;path/to/template/file.phtml&amp;rsquo;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue that I came across if you need to call a method on the block before it is rendered. If I was calling the block using XML I could use the action tag, but that is not avalible here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is possible to call certain methods using the code above. The magento parser takes each of the pair values and calls a set method on them, so for example template=&amp;lsquo;path&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; actually calls the setTemplate method on your block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that you can create a set method and trigger it from with in the static block like so&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
{{block type=&amp;lsquo;companyname/path_to_block&amp;rsquo; name=&amp;lsquo;custom.block&amp;rsquo; template=&amp;lsquo;path/to/template/file.phtml&amp;rsquo; methodName=&amp;ldquo;3&amp;rdquo;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>