<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: scraping | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/scraping/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-25T09:21:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple PHP Scraping with jQuery Like Selectors using Simple HTML Dom]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/scraping/simple-php-scraping-with-jquery-like-selectors-using-simpledom.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T18:29:43+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/scraping/simple-php-scraping-with-jquery-like-selectors-using-simpledom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you need to do some HTML parsing, scraping etc then you generally have the choice of using the DOM approach to parse the HTML or using regex to pull bits out. I quite like both approaches, there are pros and cons to both so having both options available is the best to ensure you use the right tool for the job on a case by case basis.</p>

<p>Recently though I discovered Simple HTML Dom. This makes the DOM based approach almost ridiculously easy, especially if you are comfortable with jQuery like selectors for pulling out specific DOM nodes.</p>

<p>You can read all about it here:
<a href="http://simplehtmldom.sourceforge.net/manual.htm" title="Simple HTML Dom" target="_blank"><a href="http://simplehtmldom.sourceforge.net/manual.htm">http://simplehtmldom.sourceforge.net/manual.htm</a></a></p>

<p>First impressions are really good, its very easy and the lead in time from installation to using is really fast. I like that, never been much of a fan of having to RTFM for everything!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Product Information Scraper]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/product-information-scraper.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T14:25:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/product-information-scraper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<h2>Bespoke Object-Oriented PHP Automated Scraping System</h2>


<p>The aim of this project is to put together an automated price retrial system, capable of running on its own. The system will collect general information for general products as well as more detailed information for named products.</p>

<h3>Discs Like New</h3>


<p>Discs Like New  offer a professional, effective and affordable <a href=”http://www.discslikenew.com/”>disc repair service </a>to business customers throughout the UK and Europe.</p>

<p><h3>
<img src="/assets/code_snippet.jpg">
The project is interesting as it wants to be run from both a web browser, so it can be set up and product files can be uploaded; and from the command line so it can quietly run in the background. This means that it will have to detect this state and modify what it outputs accordingly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce Easypopulate File Creator Class]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/ecommerce/product%20catalogue/oscommerce-easypopulate-file-creator-class.html"/>
    <updated>2008-09-10T14:30:04+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/ecommerce/product%20catalogue/oscommerce-easypopulate-file-creator-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>When doing spidering projects or other bulk catalogue management projects for osCommerce sites, I tend to finish by creating easypopulate format files so that the store owner can do any last minute edits and upload the products manually using the easypopulate system.</p>

<p>Creating easypopulate format files can be a bit of a chore, especially as every site seems to be slightly different with different columns etc.</p>

<p>For this reason, I have created a very easy to use easypopulate file creation class. You can read more about the class <a href="http://www.phpclasses.org/browse/package/4782.htm">here</a>.</p>

<p>I have numerous clients who are now enjoying much, <i>much</i> easier management of their product catalogues including fully automated spidering systems that grab all details from supplier web sites and format it correctly to be uploaded to their store.</p>

<p>If you want to discuss ways that Edmonds Commerce can save you time and money whilst boosting your business &ndash; get in touch today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
