<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hosts File on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/hosts-file/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hosts File on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 17:11:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/hosts-file/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain Names and HOSTS File</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/hosting/domain-names-and-hosts-file.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 17:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/hosting/domain-names-and-hosts-file.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you have recently bought a domain name and updated the nameservers to point to your new hosting, or if you are moving hosts and have update the nameservers for your existing domain name then for a period of up to 48 hours people who type in your domain name into their web browser might get directed to the old server or the new server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This period is called propogation and these days can be over quite quickly, but is still an important point to be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However what do you do if you need to make sure you are looking at your new server and not your old server?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have two options really, you can wait for the propagation to complete or you can edit your HOSTS file to force your computer to look at your new server when you type your domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really quite easy. You only need to know one thing which is the IP address of your new server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you find your hosts file on your computer, open it up in a text editor like notepad (for windows) and add a line like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
123.123.123.123 www.mydomain.com

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at the bottom of the file. Then save that file, close all of your web browser windows and reopen a browser session and if you type your domain name you should get forced through to the new server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hosts_file#Location_and_default_content&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;See this wikipedia page for info on where to find your HOSTS file.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For windows users, you can generally find your HOSTS file here:
c:windowssystem32driversetc&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOSTS file, Vista and Blocking Unwanted Adverts</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/hosts-file-vista-and-blocking-unwanted-adverts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 15:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/hosts-file-vista-and-blocking-unwanted-adverts.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The hosts file is a highly useful little text file that most people are not really aware of. Basically what it does is set a specific url to an IP address that you specify. This is great for testing web server etc. Also, we can block unwanted content by changing the IP address for the URLs that the adverts are coming from. The convention is to change the IP address to 127.0.0.1 which basically means the local computer itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editing the HOSTS File &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your hosts file can usually be found in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c:/windows/system32/drivers/etc/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is a text file, but does not have .txt at the end - it has no dot at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To edit it in XP, simply right click the file and select to open in notepad. Make your edits then save the file. For your edits to work you will generally have to restart whichever programmes you wanted to change the behaviour of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editing the HOSTS File in Windows Vista &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HOSTS file is much more secured under Windows Vista. This is fair enough because malicious changes to your HOSTS file could set you up for all kinds of things such as phishing attempts etc. However it does make it a bit more tricky for you to edit it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heres how to do it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1)  Browse to Start -&amp;gt; All Programs -&amp;gt; Accessories
2)  Right click &amp;ldquo;Notepad&amp;rdquo; and select &amp;ldquo;Run as administrator&amp;rdquo;
3)  Click &amp;ldquo;Continue&amp;rdquo; on the UAC prompt
4)  Click File -&amp;gt; Open
5)  Browse to &amp;ldquo;C:\Windows\System32\Drivers\etc&amp;rdquo;
6)  Change the file filter drop down box from &amp;ldquo;Text Documents (&lt;em&gt;.txt)&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;All Files (&lt;/em&gt;.*)&amp;rdquo;
7)  Select &amp;ldquo;hosts&amp;rdquo; and click &amp;ldquo;Open&amp;rdquo;
8)  Make the needed changes and close Notepad.  Save when prompted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block MSN Messenger Adverts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a big fan of in your face adverts, especially within applications. MSN messenger adverts are easy to get rid of though. All we need to do is edit the hosts file, save it and then restart the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Open your HOSTS file for editing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Paste the following into the bottom of your HOSTS file:
&lt;pre&gt;# Windows Live Messenger ad servers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  rad.msn.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  global.msads.net&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  rss.video.msn.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  ads1.msn.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  rad.live.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  specials.uk.msn.com&lt;/pre&gt;
3.) Save Your HOSTS File&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Restart MSN Messenger&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>