<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: automatically | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/automatically/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-02T19:41:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Product Information Scraper]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/product-information-scraper.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T14:25:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/product-information-scraper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<h2>Bespoke Object-Oriented PHP Automated Scraping System</h2>


<p>The aim of this project is to put together an automated price retrial system, capable of running on its own. The system will collect general information for general products as well as more detailed information for named products.</p>

<h3>Discs Like New</h3>


<p>Discs Like New  offer a professional, effective and affordable <a href=”http://www.discslikenew.com/”>disc repair service </a>to business customers throughout the UK and Europe.</p>

<p><h3>
<img src="/assets/code_snippet.jpg">
The project is interesting as it wants to be run from both a web browser, so it can be set up and product files can be uploaded; and from the command line so it can quietly run in the background. This means that it will have to detect this state and modify what it outputs accordingly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Permanently and Automatically Mount HD in Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/permanently-and-automatically-mount-hd-in-ubuntu-linux.html"/>
    <updated>2011-05-22T21:19:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/permanently-and-automatically-mount-hd-in-ubuntu-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you have a secondary hard drive that you have to manually mount in Ubuntu/Linux everytime you boot up and you are not too comfortable with the syntax for fstab, this is a possible easy shortcut for you.</p>

<p>You can view the currently mounted partitions by looking at mtap</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>cat /etc/mtab</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you do this after you have mounted the drive, you can see the full mount command that has been used, eg</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>/dev/sdc1 /media/BigDrive ext4 rw,nosuid,nodev,uhelper=udisks 0 0</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You can copy that line and paste it into your fstab and from then on when you boot up the drive will be mounted automatically.</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>sudo gedit /etc/fstab</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>I have no idea what all that stuff means and to be honest I don&rsquo;t care I just want to use my hard drive.</p>

<p>ALWAYS back up your fstab before making changes!</p>

<p>Hope that helps ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
