<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content Management System on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/content-management-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content Management System on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 10:07:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/content-management-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal Developer UK</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/drupal/drupal-developer-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 10:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/drupal/drupal-developer-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
For content or community driven websites I definitely recommend taking a close look at the PHP based open source package &lt;b&gt;Drupal&lt;/b&gt;. Like other successful open source packages, one of it&amp;rsquo;s key strengths is in the tremendous breadth of additional modules that are available allowing you to create your custom mixture of features specific to your site requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of very cool modules are available allowing you to put together a comprehensively fully featured site without requiring any real custom development work. Also applying a custom design to Drupal is really quite easy. For you this all means that Drupal represents a comparitively low cost option for a powerful, custom content based web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need some freelance Drupal development do get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>