<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 17:52:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento 2: How to add new tabs to the product page</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento-2-how-to-add-new-tabs-to-the-product-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 17:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento-2-how-to-add-new-tabs-to-the-product-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tabs on the product page are handled by the &lt;code&gt;Magento_Catalog&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;product/view/details.phtml&lt;/code&gt; template file. In there the line &lt;code&gt;$block-&amp;gt;getGroupChildNames(&#39;detailed_info&#39;, &#39;getChildHtml&#39;)&lt;/code&gt; collects all blocks in the &lt;code&gt;detailed_info&lt;/code&gt; group for the tabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means the following layout XML will add a new tab:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;        &amp;lt;referenceBlock name=&amp;quot;product.info.details&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;block class=&amp;quot;Magento\Framework\View\Element\Template&amp;quot; template=&amp;quot;Magento_Theme::path/to/template.phtml&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;INSERT NAME&amp;quot; group=&amp;quot;detailed_info&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;arguments&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;argument name=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot; translate=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; xsi:type=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;&amp;gt;TAB TITLE HERE&amp;lt;/argument&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/arguments&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/block&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/block&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/referenceBlock&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;group=&amp;quot;detailed_info&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; part adds it to the tabbed area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;argument name=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; part of that sets a string value on the block which will be used for the tab&amp;rsquo;s title. The content of the block you&amp;rsquo;re adding will be used as the tab content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s no inbuilt way to determine the sort order of these tabs without overriding the &lt;code&gt;details.phtml&lt;/code&gt; template. This is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/magento/magento2/issues/4154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;known problem&lt;/a&gt;, but you can choose &lt;a href=&#34;http://magento.stackexchange.com/questions/110796/change-order-of-tabs-on-product-page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;one of the solutions om StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is User Experience &amp; Why Bother?</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/what-is-user-experience-why-bother.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 07:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/what-is-user-experience-why-bother.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are running an E-Commerce store then you&amp;rsquo;ve probably received various offers to improve the online shopping experience, optimize conversion rate and so on. All these offers are a part of a user experience. For example - if you receive an offer to improve your online store&amp;rsquo;s shopping experience then most likely the service provider will go thorough the sales funnel, get some valuable input by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/conversion-rate-optimization/using-advanced-analytics-to-improve-conversion-rates/&#34; title=&#34;Using Advanced Analytics to Improve Conversion Rates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;setting up and analysing your website metrics&lt;/a&gt;, conduct a user survey by online forms and ask directly to the customers via email or even give them a private call.
All of the above is necessary to really understand how your users (customers) interact with your site, how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;valuable&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;findable&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;usable&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;desirable&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;accessible&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;credible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they found your site or offer to be. As for those who need a definition - &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_experience&#34; title=&#34;User Experience - Wikipedia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s what wikipedia says about user experience&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;em&gt;User experience (UX) involves a person&amp;rsquo;s emotions about using a particular product, system or service. User experience highlights the experiential, affective, meaningful and valuable aspects of human-computer interaction and product ownership. Additionally, it includes a person’s perceptions of the practical aspects such as utility, ease of use and efficiency of the system. User experience is subjective in nature because it is about individual perception and thought with respect to the system. User experience is dynamic as it is constantly modified over time due to changing circumstances and new innovations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;So, what elements the user experience should contain?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/UserExperience.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Valuable&lt;/h3&gt;
The solution must deliver measurable value for site owners or interested group. It can be conversions, leads, subscriptions, etc.
&lt;h3&gt;Findable&lt;/h3&gt;
Make it easy to find what your target audience is looking for, not only by optimizing search engines but focusing on internal navigation
&lt;h3&gt;Usable&lt;/h3&gt;
Ease of use is extremely important; it must be intuitive and fluid. You need to create a funnel that leads your audience to your goal effectively
&lt;h3&gt;Desirable&lt;/h3&gt;
Your target audience must have a strong desire to use your solution whether it’s for content, experience or emotions
&lt;h3&gt;Accessible&lt;/h3&gt;
The solution must be easily accessible for your target audience – whether it’s technological requirements or people with disabilities
&lt;h3&gt;Credible&lt;/h3&gt;
Your solution must be credible by all means. It has to build trust in your particular target audience by including important credibility factors
&lt;h2&gt;What’s In It For You?&lt;/h2&gt;
The benefits are pretty obvious. In this stage we help you to identify your market and learn about your target audience behavior and needs as much as possible. These real world insights are extremely valuable and perform a key role in a project life-cycle. In short – careful planning allows you to focus on most beneficial features first and drive more revenue with minimum effort.
&lt;h2&gt;Why Plan?&lt;/h2&gt;
When embarking on a project to launch or relaunch an e-commerce web site it can seem like a daunting and overwhelming prospect. The danger is that without &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/web-project-management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow/&#34; title=&#34;Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;proper planning and project management&lt;/a&gt;, the final outcome can be much less effective and efficient than if proper planning and preliminary research is used to define clear goals and then ensure these are met
&lt;h2&gt;Why Work With Us?&lt;/h2&gt;
Edmonds Commerce is specifically focused on E-Commerce projects. We have experienced and professional team of certified Magento and Zend developers, User Experience, Design and Strategy experts. We tend to become partners and build a lasting business relationship which is proven by our long term clients of some of most promising UK’s e-commerce stores and businesses all over the Europe.
&lt;h2&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
We are happy to hear more about your upcoming or existing e-commerce project. Please get in touch with us and explain your vision, goals, requirements and deadlines. Discover how we can help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating &amp; Testing a Responsive Design Has Never Been Easier</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 07:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/Reflow.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got my hands on these two marvellous responsive design tools from Adobe - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adobe.com/EdgeReflow&#34; title=&#34;Adobe Edge Reflow Homepage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Edge Reflow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adobe.com/EdgeInspect‎&#34; title=&#34;Adboe Edge Inspect&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Edge Inspect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Reflow is still in Beta, it has brilliant concept. Never the less &lt;u&gt;it has a potential to redefine the way of how we create and test responsive designs&lt;/u&gt; once and for all. A much more effective way. It actually allows you to visualise everything blazing fast by adding different break points and adjusting the layout and design for each of them. Going further - you can test that right away on most of the devices with Edge Inspect. It&amp;rsquo;s that dead easy - just install the app and connect your phone or tablet with your computer to see how the design actually works on the target device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of good resources available that will get you started in no time. The effort of learning it is definitely worth every minute you spend. The most useful resource that I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://http://www.adobe.com/devnet/edge-reflow/articles/edge-reflow-getting-started.html&#34; title=&#34;Edge Reflow Guide for Beginners&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;original Edge Reflow guide from Adobe itself&lt;/a&gt; It is a beginner level guide. Once you understand the core principles everything else is dead easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/reflow_inspect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, that it is still in beta. Let&amp;rsquo;s help Adobe team to create more remarkable products and post our ideas of improvements it &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.adobe.com/community/edge_reflow_preview?view=idea&#34; title=&#34;Edge Reflow Forum&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Edge Reflow forum.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent zooming in a mobile browser</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/prevent-zooming-in-a-mobile-browser.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 14:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/prevent-zooming-in-a-mobile-browser.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It may some times be necessary to prevent a user from zooming in on a mobile browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be done with the following meta tag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34; data-lang=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0, maximum-scale=1.0, user-scalable=0&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;viewport&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;width=device-width&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup Balsamiq for Fast Mockup Process</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 11:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here at Edmonds Commerce when we are working on Magento design projects we use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balsamiq.com/&#34; title=&#34;Balsamiq - Mockup tool&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MyBalsamiq&lt;/a&gt; on-line mockup tool which We&amp;rsquo;ve found as one of the greatest in terms of support provided and especially for - live linking, which allows you to create live mockups in order to deliver the overall feel of navigation and User Experience to client more effectively. It has awesome sharing function as well - really easy to work and communicate ideas with clients, especially important in e-commerce projects where we like to test different approaches and see which could generate highest conversion rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, nobody&amp;rsquo;s perfect as well as Balsamiq. They don&amp;rsquo;t have grid system integrated which makes mockup process messy as well as lacking some other essential forms and elements. The good news are that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to Upload existing grid templates and add them to your mockup, whether they are created by Balsamiq, other users or you! I was lucky enough to find well designed Twitter Bootstrap Grid Template mockup on Balsamiq on-line resource &lt;a href=&#34;https://mockupstogo.mybalsamiq.com/projects&#34; title=&#34;Balsamiq Mockups&#34;&gt;database&lt;/a&gt; so I could really save time and concentrate on more important tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After mockup is downloaded in .bmml format - it can be easily uploaded on the system here:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/Upload_mockup-600x426.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might be useful to create your own collection of most used elements and share with others! So Go ahead and create your own collection of most used elements to speed up your mock-up process and share with others. I will definitely create my own. See for updates from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Implementation of Jewellery Site (White Label)</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/magento-implementation-of-jewellery-site-white-label.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 20:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/magento-implementation-of-jewellery-site-white-label.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of our white label service we provided the development and design implementation requirements for a large London agency to deliver a high quality Magento site on budget and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site required some customised functionality along with a full bespoke design implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/screenshot-thumb1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Web Design for Mobile and Tablet Optimised Web Sites</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 17:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/responsive-web-design-for-mobile-and-tablet-optimised-web-sites.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are at all involved or exposed to the world of web design and web development then you have no doubt heard of the phrase &amp;ldquo;responsive&amp;rdquo; web design. If you browse the popular theme sites for themes for platforms like WordPress and Magento then you can see responsive themes becoming more popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does it mean and how does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What does Responsive Web Design Mean?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive designs change the layout and visible content on a page depending on the width, height and other factors of the device or window rendering the page. You can generally test out responsive designs by simply unmaximising a browser window and then resizing it down to smaller sizes such as 320 pixels wide. On a normal design you would be quite lucky if the site still rendered in a readable way at that width. More than likely you will only be able to see a fraction of the page and would have to sideways scroll to see the rest of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a responsively designed site, the layout would change as the screen width gets smaller. It might hide certain elements such as side columns and may make things rearrange in a more vertical way to allow them to be displayed without the need for side scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, this is what responsive web design means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How Does Responsive Web Design Work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive web design works by using a CSS3 technique called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/&#34; title=&#34;W3C Media Queries Information&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Media Queries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS has had the concept of media specific style sheets for quite some time. Traditionally though this was limited to print and screen, allowing for example to remove background images from a page when printing and perhaps adjust font family and size for better printing results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media queries functionality extends this concept significantly, allowing custom style rules to be applied based upon a range of differnt media options. The most commonly used of these for responsive web design are width and height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full list of properties that can be utilised with media queries include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;width
height
device-width
device-height
orientation
aspect-ratio
device-aspect-ratio
color
color-index
monochrome
resolution
scan
grid&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Get Your Web Site Working Responsively&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to upgrade your web site to use responsive design techniques to better support the wide range of internet devices in use today then &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with Edmonds Commerce today to discuss how we can help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Some Useful and Interesting Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/ &#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://johnpolacek.github.com/scrolldeck.js/decks/responsive/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mediaqueri.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mediaqueri.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://mediaqueri.es/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://mac-blog.org.ua/css-3-media-queries-cheat-sheet/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Layers in the GIMP</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/group-layers-in-the-gimp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/group-layers-in-the-gimp.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that often frustrates those who have used Photoshop in the past often complain about the switch to Linux and the GIMP specifically is the lack of groupable layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a plugin that does provide this functionality, albeit in a rather unintuitive manner :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s called LayerGroups and is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://registry.gimp.org/node/16563&#34; title=&#34;http://registry.gimp.org/node/16563&#34;&gt;http://registry.gimp.org/node/16563&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really useful feature and really does need an overhaul on the usability stakes but might be useful if you are moving to Linux from Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress: Disqus plugin hiding content on mobile</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/wordpress/wordpress-disqus-plugin-hiding-content-on-mobile.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 10:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/wordpress/wordpress-disqus-plugin-hiding-content-on-mobile.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you use the disqus plugin on your wordpress site, you may be surprised to learn that your content is hidden on mobile devices (specifically ipad/iphone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem that occurs is that the content is covered by a nice white box that you can&amp;rsquo;t see through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully there&amp;rsquo;s a nice quick fix.  In your site&amp;rsquo;s css rules, simply add the following :-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;#disqus_thread&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;clear&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;cp&#34;&gt;!important&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And mobile users can see your content again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got the Insecure Content on a Secure HTTPs Page Problem - Easy Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/got-the-insecure-content-on-a-secure-https-page-problem-easy-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 12:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/got-the-insecure-content-on-a-secure-https-page-problem-easy-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often you will see SSL warnings or errors related to insecure content being displayed on a secure page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be as simple as one javascript file or image that is being included via http rather than https, though some times this can be a bit tricky to track down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest solution is to hit this site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whynopadlock.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.whynopadlock.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will give you a clear report of the problems and should help you quickly find and fix them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively if you use Chrome you may see the details in the Javascript console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you know what elements are being called by http as opposed to https, you simply need to make them use https or remove them altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of an Era: Internet Explorer Drops Below 50 Percent of Web Usage</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webmonkey.com/2011/11/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage/&#34;&gt;http://www.webmonkey.com/2011/11/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who had had to either do an extra 50% of work to get IE working, or had to pay someone else to do so. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you are thinking what we think. Yes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting an Ecommerce Business,  in a Nutshell</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/starting-an-ecommerce-business-in-a-nutshell.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 16:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/starting-an-ecommerce-business-in-a-nutshell.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
It may be obvious but after a discussion in the office we decided to put together a simple guideline for getting into e-commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a list of things that you need to do in order to start selling from your own web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Get a Domain Name&lt;/b&gt;
These are so cheap yet so fundamentally important it really should be one of the first things you do. Always ensure you can get the .com even if you intend to run from the .co.uk. If budget allows, buy all the top level domains you can afford simply to ensure they are yours - eg .com, .net, .co.uk, .org.uk, .info etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Find a Supplier&lt;/b&gt;
The first thing you need is a supplier that you can buy from cheap enough to markup and earn a reasonable profit. Often this is one of the hardest bits, especially when you are starting out, finding a supplier that will agree to supply you can be tough. Be prepared to pay for stock up front initially and also to take on stock holdings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;You May need Retail Shop&lt;/b&gt;
Even though you intend to make ecommerce the primary focus of your business, you may find some suppliers simply will not work with you if you do not have a retail shop. You need to double check this. Some times it is enough to have a few counters or a display rack in your warehouse, or some kind of &amp;ldquo;trade counter&amp;rdquo;. Other times you may really need a plate glass high street store front to get supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Decide on your Fulfillment&lt;/b&gt;
You need to decide how you are going to fulfill customer orders. Are you going to do everything yourself? Are you going to use a fulfilment company to take care of this for you. You may find that your supplier(s) offer a drop shipping service where they will fulfill orders directly for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Decide on Shipping Methods and Charges&lt;/b&gt;
Are you going to offer next day courier? Do you need to worry about insurance? Can you get away with Royal Mail? There are lots of things to consider when thinking about this aspect of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Merchant Account&lt;/b&gt;
If you want to take credit card payments, and any serious ecommerce business should - I definitely believe it is not enough to simply offer paypal - then you are going to need a merchant account. You will also need a business account - these do not have to be from the same bank, though they would have you believe they do. Shop around for the best rates - this can have a distinct impact on your bottom line, especially if margins are tight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Payment Service Provider&lt;/b&gt;
The payment service provider is the system that will actually allow customers to enter card details and will report transactions back to your merchant account. Again its worth shopping around for the best rates. Bear in mind you can only have one PSP per merchant account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Choose your Shopping Cart Platform&lt;/b&gt;
You need to choose which platform you want to base the site on. Choices generally include Magento which is without a doubt the most popular and powerful, Open Cart, osCommerce and derivatives are still popular though not really for new sites these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Get a Design&lt;/b&gt;
Your choices for design range from using an off the shelf theme which is the cheapest option through to getting a full custom design created. If you are looking for templates, simply search google for {platform} template or {platform} theme. For example &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.co.uk/search?gcx=c&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;client=ubuntu&amp;channel=cs&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=magento+templates&#34;&gt;Magento Templates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Implement your design on your Cart&lt;/b&gt;
If you have chosen a template then this is usually a case of installing that template and then making whatever customisations you want/need to make in order to brand the site with your logos, colour schemes etc. If you have chosen to go for a custom design then this is a much larger task but the end result is something that is exactly what you want. This is definitely something that Edmonds Commerce can help you with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Load your Product Data&lt;/b&gt;
You need to populate your store with product information. In its barest form this should include name, description, SKU, price and images. You may find getting the data is tricky. Alternatively you may be lucky enough to have suppliers that offer a full data feed and images for their products making this very easy. If you need to bridge the gap, getting a custom scraper built to get product data from your suppliers web sites can be a very cost effective solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Choose a Hosting Company&lt;/b&gt;
Whilst your store is in development you will not generally need hosting. All of our client work is carried out on our local environment and staging server. It is only when the site is ready to go live that hosting is required. When choosing a host there is lots to consider. The first and most obvious is the hardware spec of your server. Are you going to go for the cheapest shared hosting, a VPS with reasonable power or a dedicated with large RAM and CPU resources?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other big question that I think a lot of people do not consider in enough detail is the level of support you need from your hosting company. This has a dramatic impact on the price. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to get a very powerful dedicated for around the £100 per month mark. However don&amp;rsquo;t bother calling the support line at 2am on a Saturday Morning. If you need full phone support, especially 24/7 then expect to pay for this. I would also advise trying to ring the support lines at these kinds of times just to check that it really is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Launch Your Store&lt;/b&gt;
You can launch your store as soon as you have product data and a means of payment set up and the store is accessible by visiting your domain name. There are different schools of thought on when you should launch. One is that you should not launch until your site is 100% finished and ready to impress your visitors with its sheer amazingness. Another school of thought is that you should launch ASAP to allow search engine spiders to get in and also to allow visitors to start trickling in allowing you to ensure your systems are all working properly before you switch on the more powerful marketing that will drive large traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register Self Employed&lt;/b&gt;
If you are starting out in business you need to remember to register yourself as self employed with the revenue. Here is some more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hmrc.gov.uk/selfemployed/register-selfemp.htm&#34;&gt;info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Unleash the Marketing&lt;/b&gt;
Your store will not succeed unless you have an effective marketing strategy in place. This could involve simply SEO + PPC or might extend through to TV adverts, billboards etc. The main differentiator is scale and budget. SEO is a long term strategy, it is unlikley you will achieve great results from the get go. PPC offers an instant response though the costs can be very high so maintaining profitability can be a concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Continuous Improvement&lt;/b&gt;
Once your ecommerce business is up and running you should commit yourself to a continuous cycle of improvement. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way to ensure you stay ahead of the game and achieve the level of progress you desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to plan on the fact that you will need to periodically upgrade your shopping cart. Especially if you are using Magento - it is being updated all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Add Stylesheet to Head for Specific Category</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-add-stylesheet-to-head-for-specific-category.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 12:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-add-stylesheet-to-head-for-specific-category.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to include a custom stylesheet for a particular category you can do this very cleanly by specifying custom layout xml in the category admin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply find the category you want to apply this to and then hit the ```display settings
 tab&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in the custom layout update  box, paste something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[xml]
&lt;reference name=&#34;head&#34;&gt;
&lt;action method=&#34;addCss&#34;&gt;&lt;stylesheet&gt;css/extra_styles.css&lt;/stylesheet&gt;&lt;/action&gt;
&lt;/reference&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;clear your cache and this stylesheet should be included in the head section for this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could of course do this in the layout XML files, however if you need somethign that the admin of the site can easily apply to any other new categories that needs the same treatment then this is a great solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over Board - Magento Migration</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 16:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Over Board – Migration to Magento from OSCommerce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board wished to move away from OSCommerce due to limitations encountered while using OSCommerce. Using Magento allows the company the flexibility they desired. This project involved implementing a new site design as well as importing data from the old OSCommerce site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Over Board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board are an eCommerce company specialising in the sales of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.over-board.co.uk/&#34;&gt;water proof device cases and bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/overboards-300x224.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was terrific as it demonstrates the ability to move away from a relativity old system to a new system and at the same time enabling a lot more functionality and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dressnimpress - New Magento Based E-commerce Site Development</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/dressnimpress-new-magento-based-e-commerce-site-development.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 14:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/dressnimpress-new-magento-based-e-commerce-site-development.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are now working on developing a new Magento based e-commerce site for a UK based company called Dressnimpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client specialises in designer clothing for both male and female and will be targeting a world wide marketplace for selling designer clothes covering all the latests and famous brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site will be developed from scratch by implementing designs that have been provided to us by the client. Part of the development process will include building a number of custom extensions to fulfil specific features of the site, customizing specific areas or pages of the site as per design and it will also have to support multiple currencies for the world wide audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>