<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: chrome | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/chrome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-16T11:13:12+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trigger Basic Auth Popup in Chrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/trigger-basic-auth-popup-in-chrome.html"/>
    <updated>2013-12-02T19:32:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/trigger-basic-auth-popup-in-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Chrome, if you have already authenticated with a site using Basic Authentiation (a Web Server level authentication) then you will have probably realised that once you are authenticated, Chrome does not continuously prompt you for the details, and that is a good thing.
However, in a scenario where perhaps you want to authenticate as a different user or otherwise re enter the details then it can be tricky to figure out how to do this.</p>

<p>The answer is simple enough, you can retrigger this prompt by putting your username@ the url and the pop up will be shown again.</p>

<p>To be clear:</p>

<p><code>
http://www.somedomain.com
</code></p>

<p>becomes:</p>

<p><code>
http://username@www.somedomain.com
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Auto Populate Form Fields - Form Fuzzer]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-auto-populate-form-fields-form-fuzzer.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T10:42:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-auto-populate-form-fields-form-fuzzer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you ever used Webmaster Tools in Firefox but have now switched to using Chrom(e|ium) instead then you probably miss the form filler &ndash; especially if you ever need to test checkouts or other form intensive web site user stories.</p>

<p>A nice little extension that I just discovered takes care of this, <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/cbpplldpcdcfejdaldmnfhlodoadjhii" target="_blank">Chrome Form Fuzzer</a>.</p>

<p>You can configure it for simple form filling or with a little creative configuration it could easily be used for security testing and more in depth testing to ensure that input is being sanitised and filtered properly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Aliases for Bookmarks/Links Extension - Great Timesaver]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-aliases-for-bookmarkslinks-extension-great-timesaver.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T10:50:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-aliases-for-bookmarkslinks-extension-great-timesaver</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a few URLS you are constantly going to and you would prefer a quick keyboard based way of going to them without having to type full URLs then this little extension could be for you.</p>

<p>The concept is very simple. You can create an alias word (eg phpmyadmin) which then redirects to your full phpmyadmin URL.</p>

<p>When you first install it you might set up some aliases and try to use them but get redirected to the google search results pages for that word instead. The extension author has worked around this behaviour by requiring you to put an &ldquo;a &rdquo;, the letter a followed by a space, before your alias.</p>

<p>Setting up the aliases is simple and I can already see this becoming one of my must have extensions.</p>

<p>Check it out for yourselves:
<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hnmffkbofelpmfnimaicmkdhimnaegla" title="Chrome Link Alias" target="_blank"><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hnmffkbofelpmfnimaicmkdhimnaegla">https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hnmffkbofelpmfnimaicmkdhimnaegla</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tip: Copy CSS Selector in chrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/tip-copy-css-selector-in-chrome.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-29T16:14:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/tip-copy-css-selector-in-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, this is hacky but it really works, and saves a lot of time!</p>

<p>To copy the css selector of an element in chrome, you need your developer tools open popped-out of chrome, not docked but here is the trick :&ndash;</p>

<p>Inspect the element that you want, be sure it&rsquo;s selected in developer tools, then press F12.  This will open a second developer tools window inspecting the first developer tools.</p>

<p>Then, insert the following two lines of javascript magic, one at a time &ndash; the first pulls jQuery into the developer tools and the second runs a function to build the css path and output it into the console!</p>

<p>First jQuery :
<code>
var script = document.createElement('script');script.src = "https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.6.3/jquery.min.js";document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0].appendChild(script);
</code>
Then the path :
<code>
path=""; function addtopath(str) { if(typeof(str) != 'undefined') {path = str+' '+path} } jQuery('.crumbs span').each(function(){addtopath(jQuery(this).attr('title'))}); path;
</code></p>

<p>You can try stringing them together into one command, but sometimes jQuery doesn&rsquo;t seem to load fast enough.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome Handy Extensions]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-handy-extensions.html"/>
    <updated>2010-05-04T09:37:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-handy-extensions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you use Google Chrome then you might like this list of 10 decent Chrome extensions</p>

<p><a href="http://webdesignledger.com/tools/10-time-saving-google-chrome-extensions"><a href="http://webdesignledger.com/tools/10-time-saving-google-chrome-extensions">http://webdesignledger.com/tools/10-time-saving-google-chrome-extensions</a></a></p>

<p>It will be interesting to see if Chrome goes the way of Firefox with an over abundance of plugins gradually eroding the performance of the browser.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
