<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enterprise on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/enterprise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enterprise on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 09:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Programmer</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-programmer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 09:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-programmer.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days we call programmers developers. When working with web sites the usual term is web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are a team of highly skilled PHP web developers that specialise in Magento Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a Magento programmer, i.e. a Magento developer, then you have come to the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/a&gt; with Edmonds Commerce today to get the technical Magento expertise you need to make the most of your business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Enterprise 1.8 Features Solr</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-enterprise-1-8-features-solr.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-enterprise-1-8-features-solr.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very interesting to read about the latest Magento Enterprise version release. Among other things, they have implemented &lt;a href=&#34;http://lucene.apache.org/solr/&#34;&gt;Solr&lt;/a&gt; for searching. Solr is what can only be called a &amp;ldquo;proper search engine&amp;rdquo; and is the alternative to searching a database which is the usual way the Magento search works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using a proper search engine, the site will be able to display better, more relevant results a lot faster than is possible with the database driven method. The main downside is that its complex to set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see if a paid or community extension becomes available to provide Solr to community edition users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a Google Code project, but it seems to be dead in the water:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/magento-solr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/magento-solr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>