<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: android | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/android/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-07T11:18:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easily Test Mobile Version of your Site with Chrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/easily-test-mobile-version-of-your-site-with-chrome.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T15:33:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/easily-test-mobile-version-of-your-site-with-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have opted to have a customised mobile theme displayed for mobile users of your web site then it can be useful to be able to test this theme from the desktop. This is quite simple to do and there are plugins for most browsers. These days though Chrome users have this functionality built in, and quite nicely as well.</p>

<p>To access a mobile version of a site simply open Chrome and navigate to the site you would like to view in mobile version.</p>

<p>Then hit F12 to bring up the developer tools. Alternatively you can go to the right hand menu and select developer tools under the tools menu. This should bring up a screen looking similar to this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-162921-600x475.png"></p>

<p>In the bottom right hand corner of this screen you will see a little cog icon, please click that:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-162956.png"></p>

<p>This gives you the overrides menu where you can select the phone you want to emulate. You can also tick the device metrics box so that the displayable area corresponds to that of the phone giving you a good emultation of the phone experience.<img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-163013-600x354.png"></p>

<p>Tick the box next to User Agent and choose a phone.</p>

<p>Once you have selected the phone you want to emulate under the &ldquo;user agent&rdquo; section and also optionally ticked the box next to &ldquo;Device metrics&rdquo; then you can reload the page (hit [ctrl] + [f5]) and the page will be reloaded and should show you the mobile version of your site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Javascript User Scripting for Android - OnX]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/javascript-user-scripting-for-android-onx.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-18T13:34:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/javascript-user-scripting-for-android-onx</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just came across this interesting site:</p>

<p><a href="https://www.onx.ms/#recipesPage"><a href="https://www.onx.ms/#recipesPage">https://www.onx.ms/#recipesPage</a></a></p>

<p>It seems to be a very nice system for really customising your Android experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify Controller for Android and Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/spotify-controller-for-android-and-linux.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-15T18:54:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/spotify-controller-for-android-and-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.cewan.spotify"><a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.cewan.spotify">https://market.android.com/details?id=com.cewan.spotify</a></a></p>

<p>Nice android Spotify remote that works, with Linux</p>

<p>Download the server component then extract.</p>

<p>Then open folder in terminal and run install.</p>

<p>Finally run the SpotifyController script and you are away</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swype Android Keyboard]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/swype-android-keyboard.html"/>
    <updated>2011-09-18T09:15:47+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/swype-android-keyboard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Looking for a fast and easy text entry system for Android?</p>


<p>I have recently been introduced to Swype as an alternative keyboard for Android. The system involves drawing a line between the letters you want to type as opposed to tapping each letter individually.</p>


<p>This is surprisingly intuitive and the speed possible is massively increased in comparison to the standard keyboard.</p>


<p>Currently freely available as a beta though you wouldn't know, feels perfectly ready for usage to me.</p>


<p>Check it out for yourself at https://beta.swype.com/android/get/</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android Developer Leeds]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/android-developer-leeds.html"/>
    <updated>2011-04-15T12:36:24+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/android/android-developer-leeds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Android is a great mobile operating system, we love it. On a more professional note we believe that Android will (<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/mobile-news/stats-android-growth-continues-passes-ios-in-usage/422">if not already</a>) become the winner in the smart phone OS wars, in terms of number of users anyway (lets leave the &ldquo;which is the best&rdquo; debate for later).</p>

<p>For simple requirements the best option might actually be to create a mobile optimised version of your web page using one of the many libraries such as <a href="http://jquerymobile.com/">jQuery Mobile</a> which gives you the advantage of a single platform to maintain whilst giving the user a high quality mobile optimised experience that feels very much like using a native app.</p>

<p>However for more advanced requirements you might choose to develop a custom app. If you are looking for iPhone app development then we can certainly help, though our core focus is going to be on the Android side of things. We believe in being excellent at a few choice technologies rather than attempting to be a &ldquo;Jack of all trades, master of none&rdquo;.</p>

<p>If you didn&rsquo;t already know, this means we focus intently on ecommerce, PHP and <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/ecommerce/magento-ecommerce/">Magento</a> development. On the mobile side we focus on Android.</p>

<p>If you would like to discuss your Android development requirements and your idea for an Android app then get in touch today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
