<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: mockup | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/mockup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-10T11:40:03+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Great Way of Cross-platform Prototyping - Invisionapp]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:16:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at Edmonds Commerce we are always looking for new techniques and tools that allow to speed up and ease our internal work-flow which results in faster and more<a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/web-project-management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow/" title="Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management" target="_blank"> effective project planning</a>, management and development. We love to involve and closely collaborate with our clients as much as possible.</p>

<p>Just found this awesome c<a href=" http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="Invisionapp - cross platform prototyping tool" target="_blank">ross-platform mockup and interactive prototyping tool &ndash; Invision</a> &ndash; which has an amazing feedback feature which could replace long email conversations. It is filled with lots of  active guides and how-to&rsquo;s which makes it really understandable for clients. Actually, I find this part the most important about all the application. So far there have been a serious struggle with this particular phase &ndash; work showoff, iterations and final sign off. That is a long journey for traditional email conversations.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/InvisionApp-Design.png"> InvisionApp interface</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent just a few moments with it, but it looks like 135.004 people in 70 countries aren&rsquo;t trusting this awesome tool just for fun. (as it is stated on <a href="http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="invisionapp homepage" target="_blank">invisionapp homepage</a> when writing this post) Feels like I&rsquo;ve finally found a well designed tool which has the most of the essential features.</p>

<p>Looking forward to take our clients on the journey of designing and iterating on their projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Setup Balsamiq for Fast Mockup Process]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T11:12:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at Edmonds Commerce when we are working on Magento design projects we use <a href="http://www.balsamiq.com/" title="Balsamiq - Mockup tool" target="_blank">MyBalsamiq</a> on-line mockup tool which We&rsquo;ve found as one of the greatest in terms of support provided and especially for &ndash; live linking, which allows you to create live mockups in order to deliver the overall feel of navigation and User Experience to client more effectively. It has awesome sharing function as well &ndash; really easy to work and communicate ideas with clients, especially important in e-commerce projects where we like to test different approaches and see which could generate highest conversion rates.</p>

<p>However, nobody&rsquo;s perfect as well as Balsamiq. They don&rsquo;t have grid system integrated which makes mockup process messy as well as lacking some other essential forms and elements. The good news are that it&rsquo;s possible to Upload existing grid templates and add them to your mockup, whether they are created by Balsamiq, other users or you! I was lucky enough to find well designed Twitter Bootstrap Grid Template mockup on Balsamiq on-line resource <a href="https://mockupstogo.mybalsamiq.com/projects" title="Balsamiq Mockups">database</a> so I could really save time and concentrate on more important tasks.</p>

<p>After mockup is downloaded in .bmml format &ndash; it can be easily uploaded on the system here:
<img src="/assets/Upload_mockup-600x426.jpg"></p>

<p>Might be useful to create your own collection of most used elements and share with others! So Go ahead and create your own collection of most used elements to speed up your mock-up process and share with others. I will definitely create my own. See for updates from time to time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
