<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cheatsheet on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/cheatsheet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cheatsheet on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2010 10:46:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/cheatsheet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Events Cheat Sheet Grep - Works for Any Version</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-events-cheat-sheet-grep-works-for-any-version.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2010 10:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-events-cheat-sheet-grep-works-for-any-version.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you use the Magento event / observer system for extending Magento (if you don&amp;rsquo;t you should) then you will find this little script handy for parsing out all of the events in the latest (eg Magento 1.4) version of Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a Linux shell script so either use it on your server or if you run a decent desktop OS you should be able to run it on your desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two parameters you need to define.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
#!/bin/bash
# Find all Magento Events, include file names, line numbers and the preceding 6 lines of code

#Please define these two
ABSOLUTE_PATH_TO_MAGENTO_ROOT=/home/joseph/Projects/Magento/
ABSOLUTE_PATH_TO_OUTPUT_FILE_INC_FILE_NAME= /home/joseph/magentoEvents.txt

#here is the command
find $ABSOLUTE_PATH_TO_MAGENTO_ROOT  -name &amp;quot;*.php&amp;quot; | xargs -L10 grep -n -B 6 &amp;quot;dispatchEvent&amp;quot; . &amp;gt; $ABSOLUTE_PATH_TO_OUTPUT_FILE_INC_FILE_NAME

# save this file as magentoevents.sh
# then do command: chmod +x magentoevents.sh
# then to run, do command: ./magentoevents.sh


&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with Symfony</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/playing-with-symfony.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 17:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/playing-with-symfony.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to play with Symfony for ages. I have played with Zend Framework and have also created my own light weight framework (which I will probably continue to use for light weight / rapid development projects or where I am working with a designer and need to keep the complexity to an absolute minimum). So I Checked Symfony 1.2 out of SVN and started with the quickstart guide and using the Jobeet tutorials as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that is weird for me is creating my DB schema in YML files. Thankfully Netbeans seems to be helping me out by handling YML properly, syntax highlighting etc. Another great thing that I have found are these awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://andreiabohner.wordpress.com/category/cheat-sheet/&#34;&gt;cheatsheets&lt;/a&gt;, especially the DB schema cheatsheet which tells me pretty much everything I need to know in once nice colour coded page :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future I would like to use MySQL workbench and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trac.symfony-project.org/wiki/SymfonyYamlMyqlWorkbenchPlugin&#34;&gt;Symfony YAML MySQL Workbench&lt;/a&gt; exporter plugin to make this process more streamlined, but for now I am going to try to get my head around the native YAML syntax. I always believe in learning to do things in a text editor first and then looking to to automate once I have at least a basic understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>