<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: gnome | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/gnome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-04T14:45:41+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gnome 3 Bind Mouse Keys to Alt Tab and Overview]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/gnome-3-bind-mouse-keys-to-alt-tab-and-overview.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-03T19:02:26+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/gnome-3-bind-mouse-keys-to-alt-tab-and-overview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have switched to Gnome Shell or Gnome 3 then you are no doubt making a lot of use of the overview and alt tab functionality to switch between your windows.</p>

<p>To make this easier (if you have a mouse with extra buttons) you can map your extra buttons to do these actions with a few simple tools.</p>

<p>Firstly you need to install xbindkeys and xdotool</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>sudo apt-get install xbindkeys xdotool</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you need to know your mouse buttons, try running this command:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>xev | grep button</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This will give you a window you can click on with your mouse and it will tell you which button you clicked.</p>

<p>Then finally you need to edit your xbindkeys configuration. This is my xbindkeys config:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>gnome shell button 8 to alt tab</h1>

<p>&quot;xdotool keydown alt key Tab; sleep 2; xdotool keyup alt&quot;
release + b:8</p>

<h1>gnome shell button 9 to overview</h1>

<p>&quot;xdotool key Super_L&quot;
release + b:9</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get Compiz working with Linux Mint 13 (Maya) and MATE]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/linux%20mint/how-to-get-compiz-working-with-linux-mint-13-maya-and-mate.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T10:28:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/linux%20mint/how-to-get-compiz-working-with-linux-mint-13-maya-and-mate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the Gnome world moving on to Gnome Shell and Unity some of us are finding frustrating  the lack of ability to tweak and configure afforded to us by Gnome 2. MATE has gone a long way to ensuring that we can continue to use the familiar desktop environment without the worry of using an outdated and insecure version of your favourite distribution.</p>

<p>One such area where an immense ability to configure our DE is Compiz which is no longer compatible with Gnome Shell. Using Compiz with MATE requires a little tweaking for it to work, but ultimately is as functional as it&rsquo;s always been.</p>

<h2>Setting configurations</h2>


<p><code>bash
compiz --replace
</code>
Because Compiz is installed out of the box on Mint 13 (Maya), this does work. However you&rsquo;ll find yourself with ugly window decoration which doesn&rsquo;t fit in with your windows.</p>

<p><code>bash
mateconf-editor
</code>
Navigate to <strong>/desktop/mate/session/required_components/windowmanager</strong> and set the value to <strong>compiz</strong></p>

<p><code>bash
gconf-editor
</code>
Navigate to <strong>/apps/metacity/general/theme</strong> and set the value to your Metacity theme name. Mint&rsquo;s default is <strong>Mint-X</strong></p>

<h2>Setting up Compiz plugins</h2>


<p>You might find you need to tell Compiz to use the new Window Decorator. In CompizConfigSettingsManager you&rsquo;ll need to set the same into the Window Decoration plugin. Set the Command field to <strong>marco &mdash;replace</strong></p>

<p>You&rsquo;ll need to enable some other Window Manager must-haves in the following plugins: <strong>Move Window</strong>, <strong>Resize Window</strong>, <strong>Grid</strong> and <strong>Application Switcher</strong> for alt+tab</p>

<p>This should be enough to get you going &ndash; I have the Scale plugin working (for Exposé style window switching)</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s still a little rough around the edges &ndash; here&rsquo;s a few issues I still have, with solutions:</p>

<h2>Compiz occasionally crashes on MATE</h2>


<p>Switch to another tty (Ctrl+Alt+F1) and run
<code>bash
marco --replace -d 0:0
</code>
Once back in your X display, run alt+F2 and run compiz &mdash;replace again</p>

<h2>Workspace switching doesn't work in MATE</h2>


<p>Set the amount of workspaces you&rsquo;d like in CCSM > General Options > Desktop Size. Set your Horizontal Virtual Size and set Vertical Virtual Size to 1
Set your panel&rsquo;s workspace switcher to Number of Workspaces: 1</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging Programmatically Opened Terminals in Gnome]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/debugging-programmatically-opened-terminals-in-gnome.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-30T13:59:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/debugging-programmatically-opened-terminals-in-gnome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are building something that is opening a terminal, perhaps a fancy URL handler or something similar but there are errors causing the terminal to instantly close, then this is the solution for you.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s actually really simple!</p>

<p>Create a new profile</p>

<p>Select the &ldquo;Title and Command&rdquo; tab</p>

<p>at the bottom there is an option &ldquo;when command exits&rdquo;</p>

<p>You can switch this to &ldquo;Hold Terminal Open&rdquo; which will keep the terminal open so you can see the error message and then fix it</p>

<p>You need to add the following flag to your gnome-terminal launcher:</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>gnome_terminal &mdash;window-with-profile={profile_name}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Beautiful!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Terminals for SSH in Gnome Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/custom-terminals-for-ssh-in-gnome-ubuntu.html"/>
    <updated>2011-02-28T18:07:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/custom-terminals-for-ssh-in-gnome-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you manage a few servers, you might often find yourself with a few terminal windows open and it can get tricky to remember which terminal window is which.</p>

<p>To make this a lot easier you can create a custom terminal launcher for your panel and make it use a custom terminal colour scheme and profile and also make it automatically log into the server in question via SSH so it really is either that server or nothing (unless you exit but keep the terminal window open for some reason).</p>

<p>For your production server for example you might do the following:</p>

<p>Open up a terminal and create a new profile by selecting Edit->Profiles then hit the ```new
 button and create a profile called &ldquo;Production&rdquo;. Customise it to suit.</p>

<p>To create a new launcher, right click your panel and select &ldquo;Add to Panel&rdquo;</p>

<p>Then click &ldquo;Custom Application Launcher&rdquo;</p>

<p>For the name, call it something obvious like &ldquo;Production&rdquo;</p>

<p>The command should be like this:</p>

<p>[code]
gnome-terminal &mdash;window-with-profile=Production &mdash;command=&ldquo;ssh <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#x6f;&#58;&#117;&#x73;&#x65;&#x72;&#110;&#97;&#109;&#x65;&#x40;&#x73;&#x65;&#x72;&#x76;&#x65;&#x72;&#46;&#x63;&#111;&#109;">&#x75;&#x73;&#x65;&#114;&#x6e;&#x61;&#109;&#x65;&#x40;&#115;&#x65;&#x72;&#118;&#101;&#x72;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a>&rdquo;</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Now choose a nice icon by clicking the springy icon that is default and navigate around till you find one you like.</p>

<p>Save the launcher and try clicking it, it should automatically use the special colour scheme you set and should also either log you straight into SSH (if you are using SSH Keys) or will give you the password prompt.</p>

<p>Never be confused again!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[World Clock on Ubuntu - Its As Standard]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/world-clock-on-ubuntu-its-as-standard.html"/>
    <updated>2011-01-12T08:42:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/world-clock-on-ubuntu-its-as-standard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>We are starting to get more and more international clients primarily from America and Australasia. It&rsquo;s great to be getting a more global market, though keeping track of client&rsquo;s local time is sometimes confusing.</p>

<p>Then the thought occurs: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m using Linux, there&rsquo;s bound to be an excellent app to help me deal with this&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Turns out there is and its included with Ubuntu as standard.</p>

<p>The desktop clock, normally displayed in the top right actually has functionality to allow you to add as many extra locations as you want, so with a single click you can check the current time in whatever locations you want.</p>

<p>To set these up, simply click the clock which then drops down a calendar view. At the bottom of that view there is a Locations option. Click that to display a map and also an [Edit] button.</p>

<p>Hit the [Edit] button and you can add whatever locations you wish. Once they are set up you can check the local time for any of your locations by simply clicking the clock in the top right again.</p>

<p>Awesome. Got to love Ubuntu and Linux :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
