<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/categories/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 12:00:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Bitbucket on Windows using TortoiseGit</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/magento/git/using-bitbucket-on-windows-using-tortoisegit-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/magento/git/using-bitbucket-on-windows-using-tortoisegit-2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Install TortoiseGit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TortoiseGit is a Windows GIU for using Git on Windows, integrating nicely with Windows Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/tortoisegit/wiki/Download?tm=2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download TortoiseGit&lt;/a&gt; and install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Install and set up PuTTYgen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PuTTYgen is a program used to create SSH keys on Windows, the Public-Private-Key encryption used by SSH in place of passwords, you&amp;rsquo;ll need these to authenticate with Bitbucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://the.earth.li/~sgtatham/putty/latest/x86/puttygen.exe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download PuTTYgen&lt;/a&gt; and install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set up a public and private key. Open PuTTYgen from your Start menu/screen and follow the instructions on the screen. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve generate the key, save both the Prive and Public keys to your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Add your keys to Bitbucket&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Log in to Bitbucket navigate to Manage Account &gt; SSH Keys &gt; Add Key&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click your public key file and open in a text editor&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remove the lines beginning with -- and the Comment line&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remove any remaining line breaks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Prepend the key with &#34;ssh-rsa &#34; - including the space&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Paste this into the Key field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click a folder in Explorer &gt; Git Clone&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Copy the repository access from the Repository&#39;s main page, on the right next to the SSH button&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Paste this into the URL field of TortoiseGit&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tick Load Putty Key, and add your Private key from PuTTYgen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Switching Branches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enter your local repository&#39;s folder&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click an empty space &gt; TortoiseGit &gt; Switch/Checkout...&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Select your branch from the dropdown&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Committing changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click an empty space&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Click Git Commit -&gt; &#34;branchname&#34;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Add a commit message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re ready to push your changes to Bitbucket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click an empty space&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Click TortoiseGit &gt; Push...&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL DB Admin GUI for Windows / XAMPP</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/windows/xampp/mysql-db-admin-gui-for-windows-xampp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2008 12:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/windows/xampp/mysql-db-admin-gui-for-windows-xampp.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are using windows (with XAMPP) to develop your MySQL applications, you might currently be using phpMyAdmin for your DBA tasks. The phpMyAdmin package is an awesome tool and is a must have, however due to the fact that it runs under Apache and PHP - it can be tricky to use when dealing with big database dumps or other heavy processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, you may decide that the best thing to do is to hit the command line. That&amp;rsquo;s fair enough if you don&amp;rsquo;t mind using command line applications. If however you fancy keeping it GUI, then I can highly recommend using the free community edition of SQLyog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This open source community edition is a free version of their main Enterprise Edition software which is paid for. If you are doing a lot of DBA work then you may want to consider supporting this company by handing over some cash for the fully featured software. The enterprise edition can handle external as well as local MySQL database administration, using SSH, SSL or HTTP/HTTPS tunnelling. It features all kinds of GUI functionality for building your database schema and designing queries. For the serious DBA&amp;rsquo;s out there it may well be worth a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the occasional big DB import / export session on the local windows host though, the community edition does seem to suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download both the community and the enterprise edition here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webyog.com/en/downloads.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.webyog.com/en/downloads.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To compare functionalty check out this page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webyog.com/en/sqlyog_feature_matrix.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.webyog.com/en/sqlyog_feature_matrix.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Web Applications in Windows</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/web-development/programming/web-design/developing-web-applications-in-windows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 13:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/web-development/programming/web-design/developing-web-applications-in-windows.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
My favourite platform for web development has to be Ubuntu Linux. As a desktop system to work on (rather than play) I think it is unsurpassed. However there are some times that you really need to use windows. For example my laptop seems to refuse to install Ubuntu which means that I am forced to stick with windows XP for the time being. However windows can be a perfectly adequate web development environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the trickiest aspects of web development on windows used to be setting up the Apache, MySQL and PHP stack. However this is no longer the case thanks to the wonderful little package called XAMPP. This is short for XP, Apache, MySQL, PHP and Perl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xampp allows you to run a webserver on your local computer. This allows for superfast editing and checking of your web application. Anyone who has repeatededly edited and FTP&amp;rsquo;ed a file to a webserver will know that it can quickly become a pain and definitely slows down your performance as a programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By editing the file locally and simply refreshing your web browser you can quickly see how your web design is looking or ensure that your PHP is not throwing any errors etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, using XAMPP allows you to start and stop the entire web server stack easily from one simple control panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download XAMPP from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apachefriends.org/en/xampp-windows.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOSTS file, Vista and Blocking Unwanted Adverts</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/hosts-file-vista-and-blocking-unwanted-adverts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 15:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/windows/hosts-file-vista-and-blocking-unwanted-adverts.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The hosts file is a highly useful little text file that most people are not really aware of. Basically what it does is set a specific url to an IP address that you specify. This is great for testing web server etc. Also, we can block unwanted content by changing the IP address for the URLs that the adverts are coming from. The convention is to change the IP address to 127.0.0.1 which basically means the local computer itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editing the HOSTS File &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your hosts file can usually be found in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c:/windows/system32/drivers/etc/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is a text file, but does not have .txt at the end - it has no dot at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To edit it in XP, simply right click the file and select to open in notepad. Make your edits then save the file. For your edits to work you will generally have to restart whichever programmes you wanted to change the behaviour of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editing the HOSTS File in Windows Vista &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HOSTS file is much more secured under Windows Vista. This is fair enough because malicious changes to your HOSTS file could set you up for all kinds of things such as phishing attempts etc. However it does make it a bit more tricky for you to edit it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heres how to do it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1)  Browse to Start -&amp;gt; All Programs -&amp;gt; Accessories
2)  Right click &amp;ldquo;Notepad&amp;rdquo; and select &amp;ldquo;Run as administrator&amp;rdquo;
3)  Click &amp;ldquo;Continue&amp;rdquo; on the UAC prompt
4)  Click File -&amp;gt; Open
5)  Browse to &amp;ldquo;C:\Windows\System32\Drivers\etc&amp;rdquo;
6)  Change the file filter drop down box from &amp;ldquo;Text Documents (&lt;em&gt;.txt)&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;All Files (&lt;/em&gt;.*)&amp;rdquo;
7)  Select &amp;ldquo;hosts&amp;rdquo; and click &amp;ldquo;Open&amp;rdquo;
8)  Make the needed changes and close Notepad.  Save when prompted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block MSN Messenger Adverts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a big fan of in your face adverts, especially within applications. MSN messenger adverts are easy to get rid of though. All we need to do is edit the hosts file, save it and then restart the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Open your HOSTS file for editing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Paste the following into the bottom of your HOSTS file:
&lt;pre&gt;# Windows Live Messenger ad servers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  rad.msn.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  global.msads.net&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  rss.video.msn.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  ads1.msn.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  rad.live.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;127.0.0.1  specials.uk.msn.com&lt;/pre&gt;
3.) Save Your HOSTS File&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Restart MSN Messenger&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>