<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Update on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Update on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 10:42:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Yum Update Failing - RPMFusion &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/fedora-yum-update-failing-rpmfusion-plus-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 10:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/fedora-yum-update-failing-rpmfusion-plus-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found that Fedora was completely failing to update with the normal GUI based software update system. A prompt would be repeatedly displayed and then the process would die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see what was really going on I ran yum update from the command line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum -y update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This died with the following error message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Couldn&#39;t open file /etc/pki/rpm-gpg/RPM-GPG-KEY-rpmfusion-nonfree-fedora-19
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like something has been corrupted. A quick google around describes some possible causes and solutions however I thought I would try the obvious one first and just reenable RPMFusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that you can run this simple command (again in the command line):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;su -c &#39;yum localinstall --nogpgcheck http://download1.rpmfusion.org/free/fedora/rpmfusion-free-release-$(rpm -E %fedora).noarch.rpm http://download1.rpmfusion.org/nonfree/fedora/rpmfusion-nonfree-release-$(rpm -E %fedora).noarch.rpm&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did this and then ran the yum update command again and everything is fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Magento Database Migrations to Track Configuration Changes</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-database-migrations-to-track-configuration-changes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 09:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-database-migrations-to-track-configuration-changes.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often when working on a Magento site, there is a requirement to build custom functionality or implement new themes etc but to finish the job, the final step will be to perform some admin configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This manual step can introduce the possiblity of human error if a step is missed or not performed exactly correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also if the configuration is to be applied multiple times across staging, pre production and final production then these risks increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only sure way to make sure that the correct configuration is applied and also to provide a proper audit trail for configuration changes is to use Magento&amp;rsquo;s database migrations - install and upgrade scripts - to update the database programmatically with the required configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assist with this, there is a nice simple module you can find on Git Hub:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/danslo/MigrationHelper&#34;&gt;https://github.com/danslo/MigrationHelper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This module will automatically create the migration files for you which can be a real time saver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would always suggest you create your own custom namespaced configuration migration module that is purely to track these configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Magento: App, Responsive Theme or Mobile Version</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mobile-optimisation/mobile-magento-app-responsive-theme-or-mobile-version.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 18:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mobile-optimisation/mobile-magento-app-responsive-theme-or-mobile-version.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mobile internet usage is perhaps one of the defining revolutions of this decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People love how quick and easy it is to quickly look up something on their mobile that they carry around 24/7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signs of mobile usage are now all around us. People scroll through websites on tablets, smartphones, notebooks and other web-enabled mobile devices to pass their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-14731757&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;, almost 50% of people have used the internet whilst away from their computer in a survey last year. In fact that article was published in 2011 so the reality now is probably much higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a look at these statistics which clearly show how mobile use is climbing year on year and now well over 10% of total usage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;570&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;na634982574962912257&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt;document.getElementById(&amp;ldquo;na634982574962912257&amp;rdquo;).src=&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://netmarketshare.com/report.aspx?qprid=61&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qptimeframe=M&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpsp=164&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpnp=6&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpch=350&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpdt=1&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpct=4&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpcid=fw486185&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpf=16&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpwidth=600&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpdisplay=1111&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpmr=10&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;site=&amp;quot;+window.location.hostname&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://netmarketshare.com/report.aspx?qprid=61&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qptimeframe=M&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpsp=164&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpnp=6&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpch=350&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpdt=1&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpct=4&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpcid=fw486185&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpf=16&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpwidth=600&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpdisplay=1111&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;qpmr=10&amp;quot;+String.fromCharCode(38)+&amp;quot;site=&amp;quot;+window.location.hostname&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are wanting to increase access to your site this is definitely something to consider!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Developing World&lt;/h3&gt;
Mobile use is truly becoming a global phenomenon. Whilst China and India have the majority of mobile connections, the use of mobile phones by developing nations is also under a period of rapid growth.

Many people in the developing world are unable to buy or charge a computer but they can afford to use internet on their phone; they often lack a wired internet infrastructure, however the mobile technology is much easier to implement.

&lt;h3&gt;Mcommerce&lt;/h3&gt;
As people have more access to sites on their phones, it is not surprising that they want to buy the things that they see on their phones.

According to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sas.com/offices/europe/uk/downloads/press/sas-verdict-retail2012.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;report by SAS and Verdict Consulting&lt;/a&gt; survey m-Commerce &#34;is growing fast and will become an integral part of shopping for all ages –
retailers need mobile capability to engage with shoppers as well as sell to them.&#34;

&lt;h3&gt;App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building Apps is quite a bespoke task which means you can modify your app to your specific modifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However designing the app means that you need to create it individually for each type of device, so this can become expensive as you will need at the least both an iOS (iPhone etc) app and also an Android app. You might also want a Windows Phone app giving you a total of three separate apps that need to be coded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popularity of mobile Apps has not gone unnoticed by Magento themselves as they have launched their own Magento mobile integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to find out more about Magento mobile app capability &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/product/mobile&#34;&gt;here is the link to their website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mobile Version of your Website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than opting for an app, we always recommend that instead you focus on having a mobile friendly web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to optimise your site for mobile devices: these are responsive themes and mobile versions. They have positive points and drawbacks and it really depends on what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer both types of mobile optimisation so whatever option you decide, we are happy to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in case you are not sure about what the differences between responsive themes and mobile versions is, I shall give some more detail on this below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Responsive Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive themes are basically your current website but with the capability to scale itself to the size of a mobile device. The idea is rather than having one web page you can shape,size and place the elements of your site to fit any size browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://googlemobileads.blogspot.co.uk/2012/07/mobile-websites-vs-responsive-design.html&#34; title=&#34;Google&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;google&lt;/a&gt; responsive themes are great for SEOs and for ease of updating the site. This may be because they minimise bounce rate which means it minimises problems of when a visitor presses the back button when the site is unresponsive. This in turn will improve your site ranking. Another SEO benefit is that it directs the user to one URL.  It is also easier to update than a mobile version of your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mobile Version&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mobile version is literally a completely different website. This means that you can edit your site to be completely how you want it rather than tweak an existing site. The disadvantages of this is that it can time consuming and expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mobile version is served up as a completely alternative version of your website if a mobile user agent is detected. For Magento there are some modules that do a nice job of offering a fairly bog standard mobile version which is optimised for slow connections etc. These days with large screen powerful smartphones running on 3G networks, the issues that prompted the mobile version are less of an issue so we tend to lean more towards the responsive strategy these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
To summarise it is a great idea to optimise your site with mobile capability so that your customers can properly view your site. Responsive themes are best if you want to have a mobile version of your site that is easier, quicker and cheaper to update, while mobile versions are better if your aims are to have a bespoke mobile version of your site that you would not need to update regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Security Update Testimonials</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-security-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-security-update.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you run a Magento store or are otherwise familiar with the world of Magento then you have no doubt seen the urgent security patch that live stores needed to apply quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We opted to offer the security patching service for free to our existing clients and then also to the rest of the world. The process of applying the patch is quick and painless thanks to a nice Bash script we put together so there was really no problem in offering this service. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-security-vulnerability-free-assistance/&#34;&gt;You can read all about that offer here&lt;/a&gt;. For anyone still not patched, the offer still stands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since that time we have had a few nice testimonials which we thought we would share:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chris from Mobile CAD Surveying&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Thank-you to Edmonds Commerce for highlighting a recent Magento security breach that we were unaware of. Edmonds let us know about this problem and offered to fix it for us at no cost.  We gave them our log in details and within an hour a patch had been installed and everything was working fine.
Thanks once again to Edmonds for their professional service and for attending to this matter very swiftly.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilecadsurveying.co.uk/&#34; title=&#34;Mobile CAD Surveying&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mobile CAD Surveying Ltd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Buckley Jewellery originally approached Edmonds Commerce to take our existing site and develop it onto a Magento platform.
Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp;amp; expand our ecommerce business.
The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design.
I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buckley-jewellery.com/&#34; title=&#34;Buckley Jewellery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buckley Jewellery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Clare from Libertinesque&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I can thoroughly recommend Joseph and his team for such a fantastic service and the security patch which was generously offered as a free service and efficiently applied with a very quick response time. Giving great personal attention every time, I have no hesitation in recommending the team for Magento upgrades and service.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.libertinesque.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Libertinesque&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress Install/Update Plugins etc Locally via Admin</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/wordpress/wordpress-installupdate-plugins-etc-locally-via-admin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/wordpress/wordpress-installupdate-plugins-etc-locally-via-admin.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you like the admin functionality to manage plugins, themes and other updates that wordpress features and would like to have this working when you are developing locally then you might find that you need to set up an FTP server locally just for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a better solution, especially if you use a *nix based desktop such as Linux is to try this extension:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/ssh-sftp-updater-support/&#34;&gt;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/ssh-sftp-updater-support/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will extend the FTP functionality to also use SFTP or SSH for the updates. If you are already running an SSH server on your desktop then there is very little left to do. If you are not then a quick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
sudo apt-get install openssh-server

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you are ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this point you can then use the admin functionality to manage plugins etc which is a nice slick way of doing things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Merged CSS Clear Not Working &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-merged-css-clear-not-working-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 18:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-merged-css-clear-not-working-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are having an issue with Magento and the optional Merge CSS Files (beta) turned on and it not updating with recent CSS changes, you may appreciate this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other cached elements that are stored in var/cache, Magento stores the cached and minified CSS files in media/css&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you simply delete the contents of this folder, your CSS changes should kick in as Magento is forced to rebuild these files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an option in cache management to flush CSS storage but for some reason this wasn&amp;rsquo;t working for me. Could be a permissions issue or something else I am not sure, we simply needed to get this change implemented (emergency live site fix) so flushing this folder manually did the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope it helps someone else looking for Magento merged CSS clear not working, Magento CSS cache, Magento CSS Files beta&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very High Speed Batch Update Multiple Rows of a Table in Single Query</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/very-high-speed-batch-update-multiple-rows-of-a-table-in-single-query.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/very-high-speed-batch-update-multiple-rows-of-a-table-in-single-query.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you need to update a large number of rows on a single table then your first reaction may be to write a loop that updates one row at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course if the table is large then this can result in a very large number of SQL queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a bit of inspiration from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kavoir.com/2009/05/mysql-update-multiple-rows-with-one-single-query.html&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; I have put together this simple PHP function that will allow you to update as many rows as you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trade off is basically memory usage as you build up a big array of row update information preparing for the batch. For this reason you may want to tune the number of rows you update per query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;function bulkUpdateSingleColumn($table, $id_column, $update_column, array &amp;amp;$idstovals){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        $sql = &amp;quot;update $table set $update_column = CASE $id_column &amp;quot;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        foreach($idstovals as $id=&amp;gt;$val){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;            $sql .= &amp;quot; WHEN &amp;#39;$id&amp;#39; THEN &amp;#39;$val&amp;#39; \n&amp;quot;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        $sql .= &amp;quot; END &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        WHERE $id_column in (&amp;quot; . implode(&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;, array_keys($idstovals)) . &amp;quot;)&amp;quot;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;//debugging info&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        echo &amp;#39;&amp;lt;small&amp;gt;&amp;#39;.$sql.&amp;#39;&amp;lt;/small&amp;gt;&amp;#39;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        $idstovals=array();        &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        db_query($sql);       &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        done();        &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JQuery Keeping Click Handler when Updating Content - Live Binding</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/jquery-keeping-click-handler-when-updating-content-live-binding.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 15:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/jquery/jquery-keeping-click-handler-when-updating-content-live-binding.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are using jQuery and attaching click handlers etc to elements as part of your document ready block, you may find you are losing those handlers if you update the page with Javascript after load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example if you have some kind of slide show which involves redrawing the contents of a div, you might find that the click handlers you had attached to the links of class &amp;lsquo;slideshow-link&amp;rsquo; stop working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you can reattach handlers manually after dropping in your new HTML but that&amp;rsquo;s pretty messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A much nicer solution is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of using&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;.slideshow-link&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;click&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kd&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(){});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;.slideshow-link&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;live&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;click&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kd&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(){});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Live method will keep the attachment to elements matching the selector now and in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://api.jquery.com/live/&#34;&gt;http://api.jquery.com/live/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gotta love jQuery ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce Payment Module Configuration Not Saving &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-payment-module-configuration-not-saving-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 17:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-payment-module-configuration-not-saving-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are having a weird problem with your payment modules not saving the configuration when you edit them via the admin, try this to see if it fixes it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in admin/modules.php&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;find:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;  while (list($key, $value) = each($HTTP_POST_VARS[&amp;#39;configuration&amp;#39;])) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and replace it with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;  //while (list($key, $value) = each($HTTP_POST_VARS[&amp;#39;configuration&amp;#39;])) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;foreach ($HTTP_POST_VARS[&amp;#39;configuration&amp;#39;] as $key =&amp;gt; $value){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>