<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 12:15:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up an Ipv6 Tunnel in Fedora</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/setting-up-an-ipv6-tunnel-in-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 12:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/setting-up-an-ipv6-tunnel-in-fedora/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;creating-an-ipv6-tunnel-in-fedora&#34;&gt;Creating an IPv6 tunnel in Fedora&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I had to access a server that only had an IPv6 address. As I am one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/intl/en/ipv6/statistics.html#tab=per-country-ipv6-adoption&amp;amp;tab=per-country-ipv6-adoption&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;over 80% of the UK without IPv6 access&lt;/a&gt; I needed to set up a tunnel on my machine to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking through the different ways of doing this I concluded that the easiest way to do this was to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tunnelbroker.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tunnel Broker&lt;/a&gt; which offers a free tunneling service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After registering for a free account you need to login and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a tunnel. Click the Create Regular Tunnel link in the User Functions box on the left hand side and fill out the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this is done you&amp;rsquo;ll be taken to the Tunnel Details page, the next time you log in you can access this directly from the Configured Tunnels box visible after you have logged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the Example Configurations tab and then select the most appropriate option from the drop down menu - I found that Linux-net-tools worked but Linux-route2 did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy and paste the command into a root terminal and then you should be able to access the IPv6 web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>