<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelancer on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/freelancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freelancer on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 15:36:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/freelancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance osCommerce UK</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/freelance-oscommerce-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 15:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/freelance-oscommerce-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
It seems that there are many UK webmasters who struggle to find a reliable UK based web developer who specialises in PHP. I have heard stories of people who claim to be osCommerce experts but in reality they simply know how to install a few contributions and that&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a freelance osCommerce developer, especially if you would prefer to deal with someone else in the United Kingdom then you would do well to get in touch with me. I now have a long list of happy clients who have had their osCommerce sites improved, speeded up and automatically populated with huge catalogues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to clarify. Edmonds Commerce is a &lt;b&gt;Freelance web developer&lt;/b&gt; who specialise in &lt;b&gt;osCommerce&lt;/b&gt; and is &lt;b&gt;UK Based&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Edmonds Commerce also specialise in all &lt;em&gt;osCommerce Derived Systems&lt;/em&gt; including &lt;b&gt;CRE Loaded&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Zen Cart&lt;/b&gt; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>