<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: freeze | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/freeze/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-17T12:40:40+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prevent Ctrl+S Freezing Your Terminal]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/prevent-ctrl-plus-s-freezing-your-terminal.html"/>
    <updated>2014-06-11T10:30:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/prevent-ctrl-plus-s-freezing-your-terminal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As someone who types a lot of text everyday and am generally quite keen not to lose my work, I tend to hit the key combination [Ctrl]+[S] quite a lot.
In fact its almost become muscle memory that every sentence or two I will hit that combination.</p>

<p>When working on a terminal, this can have the unfortunate outcome that the terminal freezes up. For more time than I would like to admit, I thought that this was a Linux bug
And found myself frequently restarting terminal sessions that had locked up.</p>

<p>Then I discovered that you can unlock this when it freezes by hitting [Ctrl]+[Q]. However this is a bit of a pain.</p>

<p>I have now discovered a way of turning off this behaviour completely which is a real relief. Simply add the following to your .bashrc file:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>Prevent Ctrl+S Freezing Terminal</h1>

<p>stty -ixon
```</p>

<p>Credit goes to this Stackoverflow post:
<a href="http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/12107/how-to-unfreeze-after-accidentally-pressing-ctrl-s-in-a-terminal">http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/12107/how-to-unfreeze-after-accidentally-pressing-ctrl-s-in-a-terminal</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim Locking Up, Always When you are Ready to Save? Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vim-locking-up-always-when-you-are-ready-to-save-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-10-04T10:33:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vim-locking-up-always-when-you-are-ready-to-save-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are constantly frustated by Vim freezing up on you are editing a file on a server then this is quite possibly your problem, and your solution.</p>

<p>The issue is that most text editors and IDEs have [ctrl]+[s] mapped to save. If you do a lot of file editing then you probably bash the [ctrl]+[s] combo all the time, without even thinking about it&hellip;</p>

<p>Now back to Vim. As it is running in the terminal then it can be frozen by using the [ctrl]+[s] combination. You probably weren&rsquo;t aware of that feature.</p>

<p>To bring things back to life, just hit the [ctrl]+[q] combo. There are ways to permanently disable this which you can try.</p>

<p>For full information on this, check out this great <a href="http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/12107/how-to-unfreeze-after-accidentally-pressing-ctrl-s-in-a-terminal" target="_blank">stack exchange page</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
