<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 12:00:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Bitbucket on Windows using TortoiseGit</title>
      <link>http://example.com/windows/magento/git/using-bitbucket-on-windows-using-tortoisegit-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/windows/magento/git/using-bitbucket-on-windows-using-tortoisegit-2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Install TortoiseGit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TortoiseGit is a Windows GIU for using Git on Windows, integrating nicely with Windows Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/tortoisegit/wiki/Download?tm=2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download TortoiseGit&lt;/a&gt; and install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Install and set up PuTTYgen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PuTTYgen is a program used to create SSH keys on Windows, the Public-Private-Key encryption used by SSH in place of passwords, you&amp;rsquo;ll need these to authenticate with Bitbucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://the.earth.li/~sgtatham/putty/latest/x86/puttygen.exe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download PuTTYgen&lt;/a&gt; and install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once installed, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set up a public and private key. Open PuTTYgen from your Start menu/screen and follow the instructions on the screen. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve generate the key, save both the Prive and Public keys to your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Add your keys to Bitbucket&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Log in to Bitbucket navigate to Manage Account &gt; SSH Keys &gt; Add Key&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click your public key file and open in a text editor&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remove the lines beginning with -- and the Comment line&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remove any remaining line breaks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Prepend the key with &#34;ssh-rsa &#34; - including the space&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Paste this into the Key field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click a folder in Explorer &gt; Git Clone&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Copy the repository access from the Repository&#39;s main page, on the right next to the SSH button&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Paste this into the URL field of TortoiseGit&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tick Load Putty Key, and add your Private key from PuTTYgen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Switching Branches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enter your local repository&#39;s folder&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click an empty space &gt; TortoiseGit &gt; Switch/Checkout...&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Select your branch from the dropdown&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Committing changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click an empty space&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Click Git Commit -&gt; &#34;branchname&#34;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Add a commit message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re ready to push your changes to Bitbucket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Right-click an empty space&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Click TortoiseGit &gt; Push...&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xampp 1.8 is out!</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/xampp-1-8-is-out.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/xampp-1-8-is-out.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new version of Xampp has been release which includes PHP 5.4! Remember that instantly jumping to the latest version of PHP is not necessarily a good idea as numerous deprecated features may have been removed and others may now be deprecated and cause issues in your applications. Check the PHP 5.4 release announcement for the major changes: &lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/releases/5_4_0.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://php.net/releases/5_4_0.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Xampp 1.8 release also includes numerous other updates including phpMyAdmin, MySQL and many more of the applications bundled with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab the new version here &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/xampp/files/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/xampp/files/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freely Available Windows Virtual Machines for Testing IE</title>
      <link>http://example.com/linux/freely-available-windows-virtual-machines-for-testing-ie.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 18:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/linux/freely-available-windows-virtual-machines-for-testing-ie.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you need to test your code against the (ahem) interesting interpretations of the various iterations of Internet Explorer then this is a great resource for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out Microsoft have thrown web devs a bone by offering free virtual machine images with the various IE/OS flavours for you to test on. You can download them &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/download/en/details.aspx?id=11575&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use VirtualBox and also a *nix based operating system such as Linux or OSX then you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xdissent/ievms&#34;&gt;this, frankly awesome, bash script&lt;/a&gt; to automatically download one or all of these machines and fully set them up in VirtualBox for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VirtualBox, if you are not aware, is a freely available Virtualisation platform allowing you to run other operating systems on your desktop. On todays powerful machines its perfectly easy to run Linux as your core operating system and then for either running windows only apps or for testing dodgy browsers, you can fire up one of these VMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind that they are not for keeps, you will need to reset them every 30 days due to the fact that they can not be activated. For our purposes though this is not really a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
Please note all of this has been copied and pasted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webupd8.org/2011/09/test-websites-in-internet-explorer-9-8.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Posted here for reference only, all original attribution and credit goes to webupd8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before proceeding, make sure you have the latest VirtualBox installed - you can find Ubuntu installation instructions HERE. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need &amp;ldquo;curl&amp;rdquo; (for both Linux and OSX) and &amp;ldquo;unrar&amp;rdquo; (Linux only). In Ubuntu, install them using the command below:
```&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install curl unrar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;

2. To download and run the CODE, use the following command in a terminal:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl -s &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&lt;/a&gt; | bash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;If you want to check out the bash source before running it, you can find it @ GitHub.

The above command will download Windows WHDs for IE7, IE8 and IE9. If you only need one Internet Explorer version, you can run:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl -s &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&lt;/a&gt; | IEVMS_VERSIONS=&amp;ldquo;9&amp;rdquo; bash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;```
Where &amp;ldquo;9&amp;rdquo; is the IE version you want (you can also add two versions here, like &amp;ldquo;7 9&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the download should start and it will take a while so be patient.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP 5.3 Windows Bug &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/php-5-3-windows-bug-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 15:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/php-5-3-windows-bug-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Just got a heads up about a bug with PHP 5.3 and windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t actually use windows but on the off chance that I might in the future for some reason I thought I would make a note of the solution here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem can be spotted by getting this error message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PHP Warning: mysqli::mysqli(): ```2002
 A connection attempt failed because the connected party did not (trying to connect via tcp://localhost:3306) in xxx.php on line 2
PHP Warning: mysqli::mysqli(): (HY000/2002): A connection attempt failed because the connected party did not properly respond after a period of time, or established connection failed because connected host has failed to respond.
in xxx.php on line 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit your hosts file and comment out the Ipv6 line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[code]#::1 localhost
```&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento XAMPP Portable Demo - Easily Try Out Magento on Windows</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-xampp-portable-demo-easily-try-out-magento-on-windows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 15:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-xampp-portable-demo-easily-try-out-magento-on-windows.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have put together an XAMPP based portable Magento demo site. You can easily download it to your windows PC, drop the xampp folder into the root of your C: drive, launch the XAMPP control panel to start Apache and MySQL and then you are away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get the files on GitHub here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/edmondscommerce/XAMPP-Magento-Demo-Site&#34;&gt;http://github.com/edmondscommerce/XAMPP-Magento-Demo-Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please read the README which is displayed at the bottom of the GitHub page for up to date instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>