<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: performance | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/performance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-24T10:23:39+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Apache JMeter For Load Testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/load%20testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-27T13:01:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/load%20testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Load testing is something that you really need a decent solution for. A simple tool such as Apache Bench (ab) is overly simplistic for todays web applications.</p>

<p>After some research I decided to use Apache Jmeter as the tool of choice. It is written in Java so easy enough to run on any platform.
It features a GUI which is ideal for creating your tests, then a command line version which is what you should use to run your tests.</p>

<p>For my purposes I wanted to feed in a large list of URLs, for that I followed these instructions:
<a href="http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv">http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv</a></p>

<p>This allows you to create a csv file with your choice of URLs. It was actually quite hard to find a decent and succint guide to getting this set up but thankfully that page fitted my requirements.</p>

<p>Once I started to run the test I quickly realised that my system was grinding to a halt with out of memory errors. A bit more searching yielded this page which advises on how to properly run Jmeter including the fact that you really should run it on the command line for proper testing.
<a href="http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips">http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Log File Analysis Script]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/bash/apache-log-file-analysis-script.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-14T14:17:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/bash/apache-log-file-analysis-script</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is a little bash script we knocked together to track down some malicious activity on a clients server.</p>

<p>Using a bit of awk etc to parse the log files we could quickly track down an IP address that was overloading the server and then take steps to block that person.</p>

<p>Here is the script:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<h1>!/bin/bash</h1>

<h6>SETUP</h6>

<p>LOG_FOLDER=/var/www/vhosts/domain.co.uk/statistics/logs
ACCESS_LOG=$LOG_FOLDER/access_log</p>

<p>HOW_MANY_ROWS=20000</p>

<h6>### FUNCTIONS</h6>

<p>function title() {</p>

<pre><code>echo "
</code></pre>

<hr />

<h2>$@</h2>

<p>&ldquo;
}</p>

<p>function urls_by_ip() {</p>

<pre><code>local IP=$1
tail -5000 $ACCESS_LOG | awk -v ip=$IP ' $1 ~ ip {freq[$7]++} END {for (x in freq) {print freq[x], x}}' | sort -rn | head -20
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>function ip_addresses_by_user_agent(){</p>

<pre><code>local USERAGENT_STRING="$1"
local TOP_20_IPS="`tail  -$HOW_MANY_ROWS $ACCESS_LOG | grep "${USERAGENT_STRING}"  | awk '{freq[$1]++} END {for (x in freq) {print freq[x], x}}' | sort -rn | head -20`"
echo "$TOP_20_IPS"
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<h6># RUN REPORTS</h6>

<p>title &ldquo;top 20 URLs&rdquo;
TOP_20_URLS=&ldquo;<code>tail -$HOW_MANY_ROWS $ACCESS_LOG | awk '{freq[$7]++} END {for (x in freq) {print freq[x], x}}' | sort -rn | head -20</code>&rdquo;
echo &ldquo;$TOP_20_URLS&rdquo;</p>

<p>title &ldquo;top 20 URLS excluding POST data&rdquo;
TOP_20_URLS_WITHOUT_POST=&ldquo;<code>tail  -$HOW_MANY_ROWS $ACCESS_LOG | awk -F"[ ?]" '{freq[$7]++} END {for (x in freq) {print freq[x], x}}' | sort -rn | head -20</code>&rdquo;
echo &ldquo;$TOP_20_URLS_WITHOUT_POST&rdquo;</p>

<p>title &ldquo;top 20 IPs&rdquo;
TOP_20_IPS=&ldquo;<code>tail  -$HOW_MANY_ROWS $ACCESS_LOG | awk '{freq[$1]++} END {for (x in freq) {print freq[x], x}}' | sort -rn | head -20</code>&rdquo;
echo &ldquo;$TOP_20_IPS&rdquo;</p>

<p>title &ldquo;top 20 user agents&rdquo;
TOP_20_USER_AGENTS=&ldquo;<code>tail  -$HOW_MANY_ROWS $ACCESS_LOG | cut -d\  -f12- | sort | uniq -c | sort -rn | head -20</code>&rdquo;
echo &ldquo;$TOP_20_USER_AGENTS&rdquo;</p>

<p>title &ldquo;IP Addresses for Top 3 User Agents&rdquo;</p>

<p>for ((I=1; I&lt;=3; I++))
do</p>

<pre><code>UA="`echo "$TOP_20_USER_AGENTS" | head -n $I | tail -n 1 | awk '{$1=""; print $0}'`"
echo "$UA"
echo "~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~"
ip_addresses_by_user_agent "$UA"
echo "
"
</code></pre>

<p>done</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Block Caching Cache Key Helper Method - Generate Safe Unique Cache Keys]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-block-caching-cache-key-helper-method-generate-safe-unique-cache-keys.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T12:21:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-block-caching-cache-key-helper-method-generate-safe-unique-cache-keys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you do any work at all on Magento performance optimisation with a view to making pages load faster then you must have come across block caching. To understand block caching you need to first of all understand that a Magento page is actually made up of a lot of nested chunks called blocks.</p>

<p>Blocks can have their HTML generated dynamically every time though it is also possible to make Magento cache the block HTML output so that it loads a LOT faster, especially with heavy and slow blocks such as best sellers etc.</p>

<p>When setting up block caching, you need to specify a cache key. If your cache key is not unique enough then there is a risk that you will display the wrong cache for a particular scenario.</p>

<p>For this reason I created a block caching helper with this method that can generate a very unique cache key based on the current block usage.
/app/code/local/EdmondsCommerce/Helper/Data.php
```php</p>

<p>/**</p>

<pre><code> * Generate a nice unique block cache key
 *
 * @param Mage_Core_Block_Abstract $block
 * @return string
 */
public function ecCacheKey(Mage_Core_Block_Abstract $block){
    $class = get_class($block);
    $template = $block-&gt;getTemplateFile();
    $md5 = md5(var_export($block-&gt;getData(), true));
    $params = trim(implode(",", $block-&gt;getRequest()-&gt;getParams()), ',');
    $category=($block-&gt;getCurrentCategory())?$block-&gt;getCurrentCategory()-&gt;getName():'no-category';
    $store_id = Mage::app()-&gt;getStore()-&gt;getId();
    return 'edmondscommerce-'. $params . '-'. $category . '-' . $store_id . '-' . $class.'-'.$template.'-'.$md5;
}
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>You would use this in the following way:</p>

<p>In a block class, set up the following:
```php</p>

<pre><code>public function _construct(){
    parent::_construct();
    $this-&gt;addData(array(
        'cache_lifetime' =&gt; 999999999,
        'cache_tags' =&gt; array(Mage_Catalog_Model_Product::CACHE_TAG, Mage_Catalog_Model_Category::CACHE_TAG),
        'cache_key' =&gt; Mage::helper('blockcaching')-&gt;ecCacheKey($this)
    ));

}
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extending a Modules CSS within a Theme in PrestaShop]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/extending-a-modules-css-within-a-theme-in-prestashop.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T17:26:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/extending-a-modules-css-within-a-theme-in-prestashop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop has a really nice structure for handling all the CSS that will appear in a site. It starts by splitting the CSS so that the CSS is split up per modules. There is a global CSS sheet but this should only be used for things that genuinely appear on all pages.</p>

<p>Extending the CSS of a module in PrestaShop is easy. All you need to do is create a CSS file that matches the naming convention of the module you are looking to extend.</p>

<p>For example if you wanted to change the CSS of the “Wishlist block” module (a.k.a. blockwishlist) in your theme, you would create the file themes/mytheme/css/modules/blockwishlist/blockwishlist.css. This file will then be included on every page that the CSS from the blockwishlist module appears on.</p>

<p>This system is good because it minimises the amount of CSS the browser has to load and also splits the concern of CSS into separate files making it much easier to manage. It also makes adding to a modules CSS with in a theme much easier.</p>

<p>One problem with this method of handling CSS is that by default a PrestaShop site may want the browser to download ten or more individual CSS files which is quite a overhead. Fortunately since PrestaShop 1.4 it has supported CCS merging (referred to as CCC in the admin) which causes the CSS for a page to be merged into a single file on the server to prevent the client having to download tens of CSS files.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T17:36:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of our clients use <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.</p>

<p>The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.</p>

<p>The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.</p>

<p>The last release for PHP 5.2 was <a href="http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1" target="_blank">version 5.2.16 released back in 2010</a>. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.</p>

<p>You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php" target="_blank">this page</a>.</p>

<p>If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then <b><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today</a></b>.</p>

<p>Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> or <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/opencart">OpenCart</a>. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
