<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Database on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Database on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 16:27:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Base table or view already exists: 1050 Table ‘*’ already exists&#34; After Deleting Tables</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/base-table-or-view-already-exists-1050-table-already-exists-after-deleting-tables.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 16:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/base-table-or-view-already-exists-1050-table-already-exists-after-deleting-tables.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If for example you&amp;rsquo;re removing an extension and want to clear out its information from the database, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to establish the rows and tables it&amp;rsquo;s inserted, as well as some standard Magento table entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;ve removed everything, cleared your cache and now you go to the homepage to check everything is all good, and boom, PDOException:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Base table or view already exists: 1050 Table ‘*’ already exists
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case it was &lt;code&gt;salesrule&lt;/code&gt;, which made me question why it was trying to create the table afresh. The reason I got this is that I&amp;rsquo;d erroneously removed salesrule_setup from core_resource, and therefore Magento was reinstalling the module. Reinstating the row, and clearing my cache solved the issue&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Multiple MySQL Queries in a Single Function</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/run-multiple-mysql-queries-in-a-single-function.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 12:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/run-multiple-mysql-queries-in-a-single-function.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to be able to run multiple queries in a single function call, for example doing the classic drop table blah; create table blah; then you might like this function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use case is for things like database migration systems which you might copy and paste chunks of SQL including multiple queries from things like phpMyAdmin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;/**&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * Run multiple queries passed in as a single string&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * This is optimised for copying and pasting from phpMyAdmin&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * Handy for things like database migration systems&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; * @param string $sql  multiple queries terminated with ; and a new line&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;function multiQuery($sql)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    $sqls = preg_split(&amp;#39;%;$%m&amp;#39;, trim($sql));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    foreach ($sqls as $q) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        if (empty($q)) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;            continue;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;        mysql_query($q); //suggest you replace this with your custom query function or if not throw in some extra error checking at least&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Profiler Improved - Aoe_Profiler by Fabrizio Branca</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Magento profiler is useful when you are trying to discover what potential bottlenecks are in place in a specific Magento implementation that are slowing down the performance of the site. Often when doing this kind of analysis you might find that a particular block or extension is responsible for more than 70% of the total page load time. At this point you would choose to either optimise, cache or disable the block altogether to remove this performance bottleneck and improve page speed significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever tried to use Magento&amp;rsquo;s built in profiler you will no doubt agree with Fabrizio&amp;rsquo;s comments that, when you have it working, the output is hard to read and not really very useful in terms of seeing what is actually going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To aid with this process and give us a nice colourful and friendly user interface to the Magento profiler, Fabrizio has built a Magento module that extends the default profiler and makes it a much more useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the extension from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fbrnc/Aoe_Profiler&#34; title=&#34;Magento Aoe Profiler on Git Hub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;git hub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full blog story &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabrizio-branca.de/magento-profiler.html&#34; title=&#34;Fabrizio Branch blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like some help optimising the performance of your Magento store, feel free to get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today and we can assist in getting the very best performance from your Magento web site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mysql_dump not restored correctly 1064: USING BTREE &#43; fix</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql_dump-not-restored-correctly-1064-using-btree-fix.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql_dump-not-restored-correctly-1064-using-btree-fix.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
When migrating one server to another you often hit bumps in the road.  Todays was transferring a database from one server to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this standard procedure I found that the restored database was missing a few tables.  Irritating as Magento doesn&amp;rsquo;t like missing tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digging down into the backup and extracting the first missing table I was able to replicate the error which came out as
&lt;code&gt;1064 - You have an error in your SQL syntax; check the manual that corresponds to your MySQL server version for the right syntax to use near &amp;lsquo;USING BTREE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually found out that some versions of mysql 5.1 export a dump file that contains mysql5.1 specific features and loading the file into mysql 5.0 will not work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is a little frustrating but if you run the command with the &amp;ndash;compatible=mysql40 switch, the dump file extracts fine :-
&lt;code&gt;mysqldump &amp;ndash;compatible=mysql40&lt;/code&gt;
Don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why there&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;ndash;compatible=mysql50 flag.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Database Repair Tool</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-database-repair-tool.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 08:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-database-repair-tool.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Varien have just released a new tool to help repair Magento databases. The system works by taking a reference database (a clean installation of the same Magento version your store is running) and comparing this to your live store DB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It then goes through and repairs your store DB, fixing things like missing foreign keys etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t personally seen a requirement for this as yet, but if they have gone to the effort of releasing a tool I imagine it is because there is a requirement for this kind of tool. Definitely something to bear in mind if you ever do need to repair an Existing Magento database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full wiki post here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/wiki/doc/db-repair-tool&#34;&gt;http://www.magentocommerce.com/wiki/doc/db-repair-tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>