<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: tools | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/tools/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-07T18:59:40+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Great Way of Cross-platform Prototyping - Invisionapp]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:16:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/a-great-way-of-cross-platform-prototyping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at Edmonds Commerce we are always looking for new techniques and tools that allow to speed up and ease our internal work-flow which results in faster and more<a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/web-project-management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow/" title="Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management" target="_blank"> effective project planning</a>, management and development. We love to involve and closely collaborate with our clients as much as possible.</p>

<p>Just found this awesome c<a href=" http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="Invisionapp - cross platform prototyping tool" target="_blank">ross-platform mockup and interactive prototyping tool &ndash; Invision</a> &ndash; which has an amazing feedback feature which could replace long email conversations. It is filled with lots of  active guides and how-to&rsquo;s which makes it really understandable for clients. Actually, I find this part the most important about all the application. So far there have been a serious struggle with this particular phase &ndash; work showoff, iterations and final sign off. That is a long journey for traditional email conversations.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/InvisionApp-Design.png"> InvisionApp interface</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent just a few moments with it, but it looks like 135.004 people in 70 countries aren&rsquo;t trusting this awesome tool just for fun. (as it is stated on <a href="http://www.invisionapp.com/" title="invisionapp homepage" target="_blank">invisionapp homepage</a> when writing this post) Feels like I&rsquo;ve finally found a well designed tool which has the most of the essential features.</p>

<p>Looking forward to take our clients on the journey of designing and iterating on their projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating & Testing a Responsive Design Has Never Been Easier]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:02:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/creating-testing-a-responsive-design-has-never-been-faster</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/Reflow.png"></p>

<p>Got my hands on these two marvellous responsive design tools from Adobe &ndash; <a href="http://www.adobe.com/EdgeReflow" title="Adobe Edge Reflow Homepage" target="_blank">Edge Reflow</a> and <a href="http://www.adobe.com/EdgeInspect‎" title="Adboe Edge Inspect" target="_blank">Edge Inspect</a>.</p>

<p>Although Reflow is still in Beta, it has brilliant concept. Never the less <u>it has a potential to redefine the way of how we create and test responsive designs</u> once and for all. A much more effective way. It actually allows you to visualise everything blazing fast by adding different break points and adjusting the layout and design for each of them. Going further &ndash; you can test that right away on most of the devices with Edge Inspect. It&rsquo;s that dead easy &ndash; just install the app and connect your phone or tablet with your computer to see how the design actually works on the target device.</p>

<p>There are plenty of good resources available that will get you started in no time. The effort of learning it is definitely worth every minute you spend. The most useful resource that I&rsquo;ve found so far is the <a href="http://http://www.adobe.com/devnet/edge-reflow/articles/edge-reflow-getting-started.html" title="Edge Reflow Guide for Beginners" target="_blank">original Edge Reflow guide from Adobe itself</a> It is a beginner level guide. Once you understand the core principles everything else is dead easy.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/reflow_inspect.png"></p>

<p>Remember, that it is still in beta. Let&rsquo;s help Adobe team to create more remarkable products and post our ideas of improvements it <a href="http://forums.adobe.com/community/edge_reflow_preview?view=idea" title="Edge Reflow Forum" target="_blank">Edge Reflow forum.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Static Analysis Tool for PHP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/static-analysis-tool-for-php.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T07:14:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/static-analysis-tool-for-php</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Static analysis is the process of parsing and searching through code without actually running it. It is the equivalent of someone opening your code base in their IDE and reading through it in detail.</p>

<p>RIPS is a tool I have just come across for doing PHP static analysis. You just need a working Apache stack etc for it to work which any PHP dev is going to have.</p>

<p><a href="http://rips-scanner.sourceforge.net/"><a href="http://rips-scanner.sourceforge.net/">http://rips-scanner.sourceforge.net/</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
