<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: optimization | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/optimization/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-03T12:08:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Advanced Analytics to Improve Conversion Rates]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Conversion%20Rate%20Optimization/using-advanced-analytics-to-improve-conversion-rates.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T15:00:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Conversion%20Rate%20Optimization/using-advanced-analytics-to-improve-conversion-rates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/conversion_rates_cover.png"></p>

<p>Every e-commerce web site owner would like to improve sales and one clear strategy to do this is to focus on increasing the conversion rate by effective use of website analytics leading to tested content changes that improve conversion.</p>

<h3>Why you Need to Start Doing this Today</h3>


<p>Let’s put it simple &ndash; without a proper use of analytics you are driving blind. You know that there is something happening but you really don’t know why, nor you can identify the bottleneck. We all know the saying &ndash; “A chain is only as strong as its weakest link” At that weakest spot you are losing most of your customers. If you can reduce the leak &ndash; more customers will make a purchase and your bottom line will be increased.</p>

<p>Check against these questions to make sure you do enough to catch and improve the bottlenecks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Have you already set up analytics for your e-commerce web site? </li>
<li>If you have - are you set up to get all of the essential metrics? </li>
<li>Do you act on the data provided? </li>
<li>Are your conversion rates increasing?</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/assets/conversion_strategy.png"></p>

<h3>The Strategy in a Nutshell</h3>


<p>Analytics enable you to track every important aspect of your conversion funnel and any additional funnels that generates or somehow supports the main conversion. By proper use of analytics you can track even the smallest action in great detail, it helps to understand the actual user behaviour and make improvements. Most commonly the process is to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Set up the analytics and determine the most important actions and funnels to track</li>
<li>Let the tracking run for enough time to get a decent amount of data (from one week to a month and more)</li>
<li>Learn from collected data and look for the bottleneck which if were fixed would bring the largest benefit (conversion rate improvement) </li>
<li>Create a strategy on how to fix the bottleneck and set up a split testing to see the actual difference</li>
<li>Go for next bottleneck and repeat</li>
</ul>


<p>Website optimization is never done, it is always possible to make improvements by repeating tests and looking for best solution possible. Solutions change as time goes, industry evlolves and people’s needs change.</p>

<h3>What is Conversion</h3>


<p>In internet marketing, conversion rate is ratio of visitors who convert casual content views or website visits into desired actions. See the definition on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversion_rate" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>

<h3>Conversion Bottlenecks</h3>


<p>Conversion rate bottlenecks are the so called “bottlenecks” therefore they hurt your bottom line the most. You want you site to be intuitive and easy to use so your ecommerce site converts the most of the traffic into sales.</p>

<p>By setting up the analytics properly and learning from data you can see where are the most weakest spots and create a strategy on how to improve them.</p>

<p>Then start to test again and compare the results.</p>

<h3>Content Optimization by Experiment</h3>


<p>Once you have identified the bottlenecks you can start to experiment with different solutions to the problem. Every solution must be tested to make sure that it really reaches the goal effectively. That is why it is called experiment. You can not know for sure whether your new strategy will actually reach the goal more effectively and how much effectively.
Difference Between Improving Conversion and Increasing Traffic
The goals are the same &ndash; to increase the bottom line of your ecommerce business. However, the set of actions are completely different and they must come together to increase your income.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/conversion_rates.png"></p>

<p>By improving conversion rate your website will benefit more from the traffic it gets because more of the traffic will be converted. For example if you are getting:</p>

<ul>
<li>Traffic - 50000 visits a month</li>
<li>Conversions - 750 a month</li>
<li>Conversion rate - 1.5%</li>
</ul>


<p>Then obviously, in this oversimplified version of reality, you could either do the conversion rate optimization or increase the traffic, just flip the coin?</p>

<p>Not quite.</p>

<p>An increased traffic may not lead you to more sales as it would not persuade the customer to actually buy. Besides, you need the right target audience coming to your site which will more likely convert. However, if you do get to attract the right traffic it might double the conversion.</p>

<p>Then what is the difference?</p>

<p><strong>More traffic</strong> &ndash; your ecommerce site is more visible
<strong>More conversions</strong> &ndash; your ecommerce site is more usable</p>

<p>As you might notice then the second one is the one that makes the customer happy and builds long term relationships which results in return customer and again &ndash; results in repeated sale and increased bottom line.</p>

<p><strong>In short</strong> &ndash; conversion rate optimization is really vital to make your customer happy and to make more returning customers.</p>

<h3>Conversion and Usability</h3>


<p>Conversion rate and usability are going in hand-to-hand. The more usable your ecommerce site is, the more conversions you get.</p>

<h3>What is Analytics</h3>


<p>Business must be data-driven and that is exactly what analytics provide. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analytics" target="_blank">The simplest definition of analytics is “the science of analysis”</a>. It is the discovery and communication of meaningful patterns in the data.</p>

<h3>Google Analytics</h3>


<p><a href="http://www.google.co.uk/analytics/" target="_blank">Google Analytics</a> is a service offered by Google that generates detailed statistics about a website&rsquo;s traffic and traffic sources and measures conversions and sales. The product is aimed at marketers as opposed to webmasters and technologists from which the industry of web analytics originally grew. It is the most widely used website statistics service.</p>

<h3>Other Analytics Providers</h3>


<p><strong><a href="http://www.kissmetrics.com/why" target="_blank">Kiss metrics</a></strong>&ndash; lets you track the person not only overall data
<strong><a href="http://www.crazyegg.com/" target="_blank">Crazy Egg</a></strong> &ndash; provides you with heatmaps for eye tracking to understand onsite user behaviour.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How 10,000 Geeks break the UK's biggest distributors, RS and Farnell (Raspberry Pi)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T06:50:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, 6am this morning (Wed 29 2012), a bunch of geeks eagerly awaiting the Raspberry Pi have killed the websites of both RS Components and Farnell</p>

<p>Why, you ask? Because the servers were not prepared for the influx of visitors that such an announcement brings.  Raspberry Pi themselves (a UK Foundation, like a Charity) were well prepared and are presently serving up a static page.</p>

<p>So, if you&rsquo;re running an eCommerce site, like Magento or osCommerce, and are warned by one of your suppliers, or your manufacturing department that you&rsquo;re launching a new product, be prepared.  Raspberry Pi certainly were and provided their suppliers with the information that they would be getting a huge amount of traffic, unfortunately those suppliers didn&rsquo;t listen hard enough.</p>

<p>This is to all intents a DDoS attack, but not an intentional attack.  Well done for keeping everyone updated via twitter though @raspberrypi, we know it isn&rsquo;t your fault.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Link Building Strategies – The Complete List | Point Blank SEO]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/link%20building/link-building-strategies-%25e2%2580%2593-the-complete-list-point-blank-seo.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T08:16:25+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/link%20building/link-building-strategies-%e2%80%93-the-complete-list-point-blank-seo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Very comprehensive list of link building strategies, some great inspiration for anyone looking to boost their SEO.</p>

<p>Mostly common sense though a few interesting ideas you may not gave thought of.</p>

<p><a href="http://pointblankseo.com/link-building-strategies"><a href="http://pointblankseo.com/link-building-strategies">http://pointblankseo.com/link-building-strategies</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Hosting Optimisation Tips]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-hosting-optimisation-tips.html"/>
    <updated>2011-09-19T17:23:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-hosting-optimisation-tips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are looking to gain the most out of your Magento hosting and to optimise your Magento hosting stack, here are a few top tips that you can try.</p>

<p><b>1. Ensure Caching is Enabled</b>
It may sound obvious, but if you do not have caching enabled then the performance of your Magento store is going to suffer massively.</p>

<p>Generally whilst developing, caching will need to be at least partially disabled to ensure that changes are reflected. Unfortunately some times when a site goes live, enabling caching is a forgotten step.</p>

<p><b>2. Upgrade your Magento</b>
More recent versions of Magento offer much better performance than earlier versions. If you are running a Magento version older than 1.4 then you should definitely look to upgrade as soon as possible as there are vast improvements to be made in terms of performance.</p>

<p><b>3. Disable or Improve Bad Extensions</b>
Some custom modules or forum inspired template hacks can be functionally fine but absolutely terrible in terms of performance. Fancy a best sellers list? Lets calculate the top ten products on every single page load and display the results in the right hand column!</p>

<p><b>4. Use Block Caching</b>
In order to deal with the above scenario, it is fairly easy to use block caching &ndash; something built into Magento as standard &ndash; to cache the html output of a block and serve from the cache rather than doing lots of heavy processing on an unnecessarily regular basis.</p>

<p><b>5. Move Hosts</b>
Some times you just have to accept  that your hardware or hosting is no up to scratch. A well optimised LAMP stack can out perform an unoptimised standard stack by a surprising degree. Combine that with some choice extensions such as opcode caching etc and the performance difference can be really quite significant &ndash; and without any hardware upgrades. If you are running a VPS or dedicated server then it is possible to optimise the stack yourselves, or hire an agency like us to help you with this. Alternatively you can try to move hosts to a more specialist Magento hosting company that will provide this service as standard.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Optimised Hosting]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-optimised-hosting.html"/>
    <updated>2011-09-15T07:17:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-optimised-hosting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Edmonds Commerce have been with Magento since the beginning. If you would like us to optimise your VPS or dedicated server for Magento then please <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/">get in touch today</a>.</p>

<p>Back then the speed of Magento was one of its main drawbacks. Since that time, the code has improved a lot and things have generally got a lot better but one thing that has become clear over the years is that Magento really does require a well optimised hosting platform to perform the best. Conversely, hosting Magento on a badly configured or none optimised hosting stack will have a really detrimental effect on the performance of the store.</p>

<p>If you are using shared hosting then you are a bit stuck. Magento optimised shared hosting is available and there are some good companies out there that we would be happy to recommend for you. If your current store is not performing well though and you are on shared hosting then the likelihood is that the only solution is to either upgrade to some kind of dedicated or virtual private server, commonly shortened to VPS.</p>

<p>A VPS or VDS as they are some times called is what is known as a virtual machine. It is a full instance of an operating system (Linux) running on hardware that is actually running multiple virtual machines from one real server. In some respects this is like shared hosting, however the difference is that on a VPS you have a fully dedicated, private and customisable operating system that can be configured and optimised as required.</p>

<p>Of course if you have a real dedicated server then you have the same benefits of a VPS and also enjoy dedicated hardware.</p>

<p>Either way, as soon as you have a dedicated operating system you are free to configure your database, web server and PHP however you wish. Generally though this is too technical for most people. This is where we come in.</p>

<p>We are happy to provide for you a full VPS or dedicated server Magento optimisation service. Our Magento hosting optimisation service will ensure you are getting the best out of your current hosting package. It means that you are not required to move hosts if you are generally happy them, but you can be assured that you are running on a highly optimised Magento stack.</p>

<p>If that sounds interesting and you would like to discuss this in more detail, simply <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/">get in touch today</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
