<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: ignore | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/ignore/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-10T14:18:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Layout ignore="1"]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-layout-ignore1.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T17:17:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-layout-ignore1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are looking at your Layout XML when trying to debug missing blocks for example, you may see the attribute ignore=&ldquo;1&rdquo; being assigned to chunks of XML.</p>

<p>These are set when some module or other is using the remove syntax to remove a block.</p>

<p>For example I have just had some issues with Fontis Recaptcha and TBT Sweetooth extensions not playing nice together.</p>

<p>The reason is that the Fontis extension is removing the entire customer_form_register handle and replacing it with a custom one however the Sweettooth module is still referring to the core Magento handle which then means its layout updates are not having any effect.</p>

<p>The way to see this is find the layout sections with ignore=&ldquo;1&rdquo;</p>

<p>```xml</p>

<p><block type="core/text_list" name="left" as="left" ignore="1"/></p>

<p>```</p>

<p>and search your files for a corresponding</p>

<p>```xml</p>

<p><remove name="left"/></p>

<p>```</p>

<p>The name attribute is the one you need to look for the correlation on.</p>

<p>For the sweettooth issue, the solutions was to simply add in the sweet tooth XML to the Fontis XML like this:</p>

<p>```xml</p>

<pre><code>&lt;customer_account_create&gt;
    &lt;remove name="customer_form_register"/&gt;

    &lt;reference name="content"&gt;
        &lt;block type="customer/form_register" name="recaptcha_form_register" template="fontis/recaptcha/register.phtml"&gt;
            &lt;block type="core/template" name="recaptcha.box" as="recaptcha_box" template="fontis/recaptcha/recaptcha.phtml"/&gt;
            &lt;block type="rewardsref/field_register" name="rewards_referral" template="rewardsref/customer/register/fieldset.phtml" /&gt;
        &lt;/block&gt;
    &lt;/reference&gt;
&lt;/customer_account_create&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>Inspiration from this <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1087733/magento-my-account-layout-xml-problem">Stack Overflow</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git Ignore All Files Except PHP etc + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/git-ignore-all-files-except-php-etc-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2009-07-02T09:41:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/git-ignore-all-files-except-php-etc-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Using Git for version control is great, but if like my you work on a lot of different projects then everything you can do to save time setting Git up is well worth it.</p>

<p>One of the features of Git is the ability to only track certain files and ignore other files. For me that means I only want to track files I am likely to be editing and ignore images, flash files and whatever other junk is floating around in a project.</p>

<p>The solution (and all credit and thanks to the kind people on #Git on Freenode IRC) is this .gitignore file. This file will ignore everything except files with the extensions that you set. Dead easy.</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>ignore everything apart from php, css, xml, htaccess, sql, js</h1>

<p>*
!<em>/
!</em>.php
!<em>.css
!</em>.xml
!<em>.htaccess
!</em>.sql
!*.js</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
