<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: cart | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/cart/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-08T12:55:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TomatoCart UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/tomatocart-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-10-22T10:58:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/tomatocart-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Edmonds Commerce are big believers in open source software and especially open source ecommerce packages which are our speciality.</p>

<p>There is an excellent selection of open source ecommerce platforms available today including Magento and Open Cart, old favourites like osCommerce (Zen Cart, CRE Loaded) and Presta Shop.</p>

<p>One that you might not have heard of though that is definitely worth a look is <a href="http://www.tomatocart.com" target="_blank">TomatoCart</a>. The key wow factor in this cart is the RIA style admin that basically looks and feels like a windows desktop. This makes it very intuitive and powerful to use and definitely feels like the way the web based apps of the future will work. Check out the <a href="http://www.tomatocart.com/products/store-demo.html" target="_blank">demo</a></p>

<p>TomatoCart is a direct descendant of oscommerce and is based on the oscommerce 3 codebase (which never made it beyond alpha status). It comes feature packed as standard with a slick and intuitive front end with features like image zoom, home page slide show and product comparison. You can read the full list of features <a href="http://www.tomatocart.com/products/features.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you are looking for a UK based TomatoCart specialist then <b><a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce</a></b> and let us help you to achieve your goals.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Cart Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/open%20cart/open-cart-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-09-07T13:31:05+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/open%20cart/open-cart-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>At Edmonds Commerce we are always keeping a close eye on the latest and greatest ecommerce platforms available. For the majority of our clients we recommend Magento as we feel that it is an excellent platform for SME level businesses to work with.</p>

<p>If however the priority is on simplicity rather than features then more and more we are recommending Open Cart as the platform of choice. The differences between the two platforms are quite significant, though ultimatey both will give end users a nice interface and both have excellent SEO features.</p>

<p>If you are looking for a UK based e-commerce specialist PHP development company that can help you set up your Open Cart based business then please do get in touch today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
