<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vps on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/vps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vps on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 10:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/vps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Running out of disk space but df shows you have lots of space left</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 10:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a strange occurency this morning with an server reporting it had no disk space when disk usage according to df was at 50%. After some head scratching I decided to read the man page for the df command and came across the -i flag. According the man page this lists inode information instead of block usage. After running it I got the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Filesystem      Inodes   IUsed  IFree IUse% Mounted on
/dev/xvda1     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2621440&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2621440&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  100% /
udev            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;124879&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;398&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;124481&lt;/span&gt;    1% /dev
tmpfs           &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;288&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126604&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126888&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/lock
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126891&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/shm
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126891&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/user
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it turned out that the system had reached its max inodes so the next line of investigation was to find any excess of files in an directory. Which was sone by using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i in /var/*&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; find &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; wc -l&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will list the total number of files in a given directory. You can change the path to work your way down the directory tree finding directories with lots of files. In the end we found excess of old logs which I was able to remove.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Hosting Optimisation Tips</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-hosting-optimisation-tips.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 17:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-hosting-optimisation-tips.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to gain the most out of your Magento hosting and to optimise your Magento hosting stack, here are a few top tips that you can try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Ensure Caching is Enabled&lt;/b&gt;
It may sound obvious, but if you do not have caching enabled then the performance of your Magento store is going to suffer massively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally whilst developing, caching will need to be at least partially disabled to ensure that changes are reflected. Unfortunately some times when a site goes live, enabling caching is a forgotten step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Upgrade your Magento&lt;/b&gt;
More recent versions of Magento offer much better performance than earlier versions. If you are running a Magento version older than 1.4 then you should definitely look to upgrade as soon as possible as there are vast improvements to be made in terms of performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Disable or Improve Bad Extensions&lt;/b&gt;
Some custom modules or forum inspired template hacks can be functionally fine but absolutely terrible in terms of performance. Fancy a best sellers list? Lets calculate the top ten products on every single page load and display the results in the right hand column!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Use Block Caching&lt;/b&gt;
In order to deal with the above scenario, it is fairly easy to use block caching - something built into Magento as standard - to cache the html output of a block and serve from the cache rather than doing lots of heavy processing on an unnecessarily regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. Move Hosts&lt;/b&gt;
Some times you just have to accept  that your hardware or hosting is no up to scratch. A well optimised LAMP stack can out perform an unoptimised standard stack by a surprising degree. Combine that with some choice extensions such as opcode caching etc and the performance difference can be really quite significant - and without any hardware upgrades. If you are running a VPS or dedicated server then it is possible to optimise the stack yourselves, or hire an agency like us to help you with this. Alternatively you can try to move hosts to a more specialist Magento hosting company that will provide this service as standard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Optimised Hosting</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-optimised-hosting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 07:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-optimised-hosting.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce have been with Magento since the beginning. If you would like us to optimise your VPS or dedicated server for Magento then please &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then the speed of Magento was one of its main drawbacks. Since that time, the code has improved a lot and things have generally got a lot better but one thing that has become clear over the years is that Magento really does require a well optimised hosting platform to perform the best. Conversely, hosting Magento on a badly configured or none optimised hosting stack will have a really detrimental effect on the performance of the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using shared hosting then you are a bit stuck. Magento optimised shared hosting is available and there are some good companies out there that we would be happy to recommend for you. If your current store is not performing well though and you are on shared hosting then the likelihood is that the only solution is to either upgrade to some kind of dedicated or virtual private server, commonly shortened to VPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A VPS or VDS as they are some times called is what is known as a virtual machine. It is a full instance of an operating system (Linux) running on hardware that is actually running multiple virtual machines from one real server. In some respects this is like shared hosting, however the difference is that on a VPS you have a fully dedicated, private and customisable operating system that can be configured and optimised as required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course if you have a real dedicated server then you have the same benefits of a VPS and also enjoy dedicated hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, as soon as you have a dedicated operating system you are free to configure your database, web server and PHP however you wish. Generally though this is too technical for most people. This is where we come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are happy to provide for you a full VPS or dedicated server Magento optimisation service. Our Magento hosting optimisation service will ensure you are getting the best out of your current hosting package. It means that you are not required to move hosts if you are generally happy them, but you can be assured that you are running on a highly optimised Magento stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that sounds interesting and you would like to discuss this in more detail, simply &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>