<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: magento training | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/magento-training/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-23T17:43:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ongoing Magento Support and Consultation]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T15:52:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.buckleylondon.com">Buckley</a> is a UK based company that prides itself on designing and manufacturing high quality fashion &amp; costume jewellery at competitive prices since its inception in 1989. The company has rapidly expanded into a worldwide brand with jewellery collections available to a vast market of over 200 stores including more than 60 Duty Free shops and 120 airlines . We are glad to hear that Buckley has contributed over US$3 million to the funding of the Royal British Legion through the sale of its elegant Buckley Poppy.</p>

<h3>The development idea:</h3>


<p>Buckley Jewellery was initially launched using Wordpress and used an ecommerce package called ShopperPress. As the company grew and they started to expand their business to Duty Free shops and airlines, it became apparent that WordPress could not provide enough support for their complex modifications and customisations. This is when the idea of re-building the site in Magento was suggested.</p>

<p>We started working with Buckley in 2011 and have been providing them with continuous support since then. Some of the main requirements were broadly to do the following:</p>

<h3>1. Magento implementation and migration from previous platform</h3>


<p>We installed and configured Magento onto Buckley’s chosen hosting platform and installed the essential extensions such as shipping and payment gateways including PayPal and SagePay. We also migrated all of their products, customers and orders database from the previous platform into Magento. A clean and clear design was created and customised to their specification and we have been tweaking it per their needs and requirements ever since.</p>

<h3>2. Magento training</h3>


<p>After successfully migrating the site to Magento, we did an <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-course-details/">on-site one day introduction course</a> with Buckley, where we gave them the background understanding and some useful skills required to get the most out of their new Magento store.
Here is a quote from Mark at Buckley Jewellry: “<em>The day was extremely useful with just the right amount of content to set us on our way</em>.”</p>

<h3>3. Magento upgrade and Magento security patch applied</h3>


<p>It is important to make sure that your Magento site is up to date. We have done two upgrades for Buckley so far and they all went really well.The upgrades were done in three separate phrases &ndash; exploratory upgrade, bugs fixing and deployment to live. We hit a few bugs but managed to fix them within hours.
Around mid July 2012, a serious security hole was found in Zend Framework which allow hackers to gain access to mysql server credentials. A patch was quickly applied to Buckley live store using a nice Bash script we put together. We offered this free security patching service to all Magento sites with a voluntary charity donation and had a lot of sites take us up on this offer.</p>

<h3>4. Ongoing support</h3>


<p>Buckley have joined our retainer scheme where we provide them with daily maintenance supports, bugs fixing and consultation services. Various <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery/">firesale promotions</a>, extensions and marketing exercises were installed and configured into their website.
Recently we had migrated Buckley and its sister site <a href="http://www.attwoodandsawyer.com">Attwood &amp; Sawyer</a> to a dedicated server, which is faster, more secured and gives them better control over the sites.
Buckley also engages in designing beautiful vintage inspired pieces in the silver <a href="http://www.bouton.co.uk/">Bouton</a> rages and we are currently managing the merger process of Bouton into Buckley main sites.</p>

<h3>Testimonial</h3>


<p>Here is a quote from Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery:</p>

<p><em>“Buckley Jewellery originally approached <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk">Edmonds Commerce</a> to take our existing site and develop it onto a <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/platforms/magento/">Magento platform</a>. Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp; expand our ecommerce business. The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design. I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice”. </em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb1.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Leeds]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-leeds.html"/>
    <updated>2010-01-19T19:25:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-leeds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>Edmonds Commerce have been specialising in <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/">Magento</a> for a while now. We have been involved in numerous Magento sites doing things ranging from setting up entire stores (including multi store) through to developing custom Magento modules for specific client requirements.</p>

<p>If you are looking for a <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/php/magento-uk/">Magento Developer</a> based in the UK, particularly the <strong>Leeds</strong> / <strong>Bradford</strong> area of <strong>West Yorkshire</strong> then definitely get in touch with us.</p>

<p>2010 has seen the full launch of our <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/magento/magento-training-uk/"><strong>Magento Training Courses</strong></a> which are running in Leeds. The first was in early January and we now have two more dates lined up so if you are looking for Magento training then give us a buzz about that and we can give you all the details.</p>

<p>We think Magento is great and we are really happy to be helping more and more UK ecommerce businesses to migrate or establish themselves on this excellent open source ecommerce platform.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
