<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zf on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/zf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zf on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 13:07:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/zf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Security Vulnerability &#43; Free Assistance</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-security-vulnerability-free-assistance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 13:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-security-vulnerability-free-assistance.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The magento platform is based on a PHP framework called Zend Framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently a bug was found in Zend Framework which potentially allows attackers to read any file on your server. This could mean they could gain access to your mysql server credentials for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read the full details &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/blog/comments/update-zend-framework-vulnerability-security-update/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual bug details for Zend Framework are in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://framework.zend.com/security/advisory/ZF2012-01&#34;&gt;security advisory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Free Security Patching Service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell this represents a serious security hole that you need to plug as soon as possible. Fixing this issue is very simple indeed if you know what you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason Edmonds Commerce are happy to offer &lt;b&gt;FREE&lt;/b&gt; assistance in applying this patch to any Magento store owner whether you are a current client or not. We will not charge you in any way for this service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To request &lt;b&gt;FREE&lt;/b&gt; assistance &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/contact-us/?about=Free+Magento+Security+Fix&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;contact us today&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Donation to Charity&lt;/h3&gt;
If you choose to, you could make a donation to cover this service here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justgiving.com/EdmondsCommerce&#34;&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/EdmondsCommerce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Please Note&lt;/h3&gt;
We will need you to give us shell (otherwise known as SSH) access to your server if available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are on a shared hosting service that is not able to supply shell access, we would suggest you ask your hosting company to help you with this issue. Feel free to refer them to this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento or Zend Framework Session issues with PHPUnit and session_start()</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/magento-or-zend-framework-session-issues-with-phpunit-and-session_start.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 16:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/magento-or-zend-framework-session-issues-with-phpunit-and-session_start.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are having issues running unit tests that work with sessions and call session_start(), you might see error messages like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;output started at &amp;ldquo;PHPUnit/Util/Printer.php:173&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do, the solution is fairly simple. Just add the flag &amp;ndash;stderr to PHPUnit eg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
 phpunit --stderr mytest.php

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using Netbeans, you simply need to add this to your PHPUnit script setting in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools-&amp;gt;Options-&amp;gt;PHP-&amp;gt;Unit Test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eg /opt/lampp/bin/phpunit &amp;ndash;stderr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/Screenshot-600x323.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zend Framework UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/zend-framework/zend-framework-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/zend-framework/zend-framework-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Currently working on a big Zend Framework project so I though I would have a breather and do a little blog post targeted at anyone looking for a UK based Zend Framework developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve built a few Zend Framework based systems and have found it a fun system to work with, especially on the more recent versions of the library. There have been a few hurdles along the way and I have definitely improved my object oriented PHP development skills a lot since I first had a go at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://framework.zend.com&#34;&gt;Zend Framework&lt;/a&gt; quick start way back when.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to learn &lt;strong&gt;Zend Framework&lt;/strong&gt; primarily because Magento is based on it, and Magento is the ecommerce platform that I have chosen to specialise in. Since then though I have found that Zend Framework has a definite place for me, especially when coding more heavy duty data processing applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For simple web sites I would tend more towards using Symfony or my own lightweight MVC framework for very simple sites. For me Zend Framework really shines when you need to do something a little different that doesn&amp;rsquo;t easily fit into the mold specified by the Symfony code creation tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to conclude, if you are looking for a PHP web developer who specialises in Zend Framework and particularly if you would prefer a UK based Zend Framework specialist then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-zend-framework.html&#34;&gt;get in touch with us today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>