<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: open | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/open/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-10T17:28:33+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging Programmatically Opened Terminals in Gnome]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/debugging-programmatically-opened-terminals-in-gnome.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-30T13:59:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/debugging-programmatically-opened-terminals-in-gnome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are building something that is opening a terminal, perhaps a fancy URL handler or something similar but there are errors causing the terminal to instantly close, then this is the solution for you.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s actually really simple!</p>

<p>Create a new profile</p>

<p>Select the &ldquo;Title and Command&rdquo; tab</p>

<p>at the bottom there is an option &ldquo;when command exits&rdquo;</p>

<p>You can switch this to &ldquo;Hold Terminal Open&rdquo; which will keep the terminal open so you can see the error message and then fix it</p>

<p>You need to add the following flag to your gnome-terminal launcher:</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>gnome_terminal &mdash;window-with-profile={profile_name}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Beautiful!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenERP UK - Open Source Enterprise Class ERP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/openerp/openerp-uk-open-source-enterprise-class-erp.html"/>
    <updated>2011-01-07T11:49:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/openerp/openerp-uk-open-source-enterprise-class-erp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>OpenERP is a fully featured enterprise class open source ERP system that thanks to it&rsquo;s modular structure can support all kinds of business models and requirements ranging from Retail to E-Commerce to Manufacturing to Services and beyond.</p>

<p>OpenERP is written in a language called Python, widely regarded as an excellent language thanks to it&rsquo;s power, cross platform compatibility and ease of development.</p>

<p>Thanks to being open source, you can experiment or even implement OpenERP for you business without any up front costs, licence costs, vendor lock in or any of the other big drawbacks of standard paid for ERP packages.</p>

<p>This means you can dip your toe in the water initially and roll out further integration and functionality as you are ready for it and your business requires it.</p>

<p>There is a wide global network of specialist agencies supporting the OpenERP package and at it&rsquo;s centre is a large development house based in Belgium that is entirely devoted to the platform. This kind of business backed open source package is great news for you because it ensures that there will be professional support and training available and you can expect the platform to continue developing in the future, making it an excellent platform to invest into.</p>

<p>This is similar to the way that Magento, our most highly recommended open source ecommerce package, is backed by Varien &ndash; a large and well funded company that is pushing the platform and really making it an enterprise class platform.</p>

<p>Of course the logical best of breed combination is to use the awesome front end functionality of Magento for your e-commerce stores and hook this into OpenERP&rsquo;s excellent business management functionality.</p>

<p>If you would like to discuss OpenERP or Magento or of course both for your business, get in touch today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Cart Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/open%20cart/open-cart-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-09-07T13:31:05+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/open%20cart/open-cart-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>At Edmonds Commerce we are always keeping a close eye on the latest and greatest ecommerce platforms available. For the majority of our clients we recommend Magento as we feel that it is an excellent platform for SME level businesses to work with.</p>

<p>If however the priority is on simplicity rather than features then more and more we are recommending Open Cart as the platform of choice. The differences between the two platforms are quite significant, though ultimatey both will give end users a nice interface and both have excellent SEO features.</p>

<p>If you are looking for a UK based e-commerce specialist PHP development company that can help you set up your Open Cart based business then please do get in touch today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
