<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: google apps | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/google-apps/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-04T16:57:08+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrate to Google Apps - Google Apps Reseller]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T14:21:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are big fans of Google Apps and have built a large portion of our business processes around the system. For this reason we have absolutely no problem recommending the service to our clients and have assisted numerous clients with a migration to the system.</p>

<p>The first benefit you will get is your emails migrated over and a much better email service. You have the option of using normal IMAP access so you can continue to use your preferred desktop application however we suspect that you will start to use the web interface as it is really quite powerful with some unique features that you can not access on a normal desktop client.</p>

<p>Along with this you have great support of mobile devices, especially if you opt for Android with powerful and free native apps meaning that you can have all the access to your emails that could possibly wish for.</p>

<p>Along with the really excellent email functionality you also have powerful online documents giving you the basic office application functionality along with really powerful collaboration features allowing multiple people to be working on the same document simultaneously from geographically separate locations. This can be great when putting together proposals, specifications etc.</p>

<p>Now called Google Drive, the documents system has grown from managing purely office documents into a fully featured online file store that can be used to store and share all kinds of files across your organisation and with third parties.</p>

<p>Finally the calendar functionality is great. If you have never used Google Calendar then I suspect the first things you will notice is the abilty to easily drag and drop appointments around when reorganising your schedule. The ability to quickly create appointments using natural language such as &ldquo;call steve at 11am&rdquo; is really nice. A full barrage of reminders can be set up if you wish including on screen, SMS and emails meaning you should never miss an appointment again.</p>

<p>All in all we think Google Apps is great and would love to help you move your organisation across to the system. If you would like to discuss this in more detail please do <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us"><b>get in touch today</b></a>.</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce are a Google Apps Reseller.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Drops Google Apps Free Tier]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/google-drops-google-apps-free-tier.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T14:19:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/google-drops-google-apps-free-tier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a move that will hurt a lot of small businesses and especially startups, Google have withdrawn their free Google Apps for Domains which has been slowly reducing in number of users from 50, to 10 to now 0 (almost).</p>

<p>They are keeping the existing accounts open so if you have Google Apps already, don&rsquo;t panic yet, your data is still there.</p>

<p>For one-man-band startups apparently there is the option of creating a single-user apps account still apparently, according to Greg D'Alesandre of Google.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome AutoCorrect for Gmail (and Google Apps)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T13:54:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you use Gmail (also bundled with Google Apps) for your business then you probably write a lot of emails directly into the gmail interface. If you are like me you probably make teh the mistakes all teh time. (See what I did there!)</p>

<p>As the MD of Edmonds Commerce I probably write more emails than most people with everything from <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento">Magento</a> quotes, client communications, enquiries and maybe even the occasional personal email. At a guess I would say I write a good few thousand words per day. I should calculate that one day.</p>

<p>Well help is at hand with this wonderful chrome extension that will auto correct common typos as you type them in gmail. For me this is a real productivity booster as I type fast but badly and this really tidies up a lot of my common mistakes meaning less <em>backspace</em> and more <em>getting stuff done</em>.</p>

<p>You can grab the extension <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ezautocorrect-for-gmail/fholdolknchpdbajhpdenookmikblmda/related" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>I hope you find it useful. On another note, if you aren&rsquo;t currently using Google Apps (its free you know) and would like to look at transitioning your business to the system then get in touch with us and we would be happy to help you with it. I can not recommend the service enough to be honest, even if you go for the paid version the cost is negligible really. Smaller companies should be find with the free version though which you really can&rsquo;t argue with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Apps and Two Factor Authentication]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/google-apps-and-two-factor-authentication.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-07T10:22:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/google-apps-and-two-factor-authentication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are using Google apps and have two factor authentication turned on then you are probably using the convenient &ldquo;Remember this PC for 30 days&rdquo; feature.</p>

<p>If you like your browser to forget every thing except a very select set of data (bookmarks, etc.) but keep the convenience of the 30 day authentication then you only need to keep the cookie called &ldquo;SMSV&rdquo; for the domain &ldquo;www.google.com&rdquo; with path &ldquo;/a&rdquo;.</p>

<p>There is a variety of ways you can keep this cookie. You could, for example, export it then import it when ever (and where ever) you need it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating to Google Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2010-06-10T07:48:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>We recently decided to give Google Apps a try, mainly due to the requirement for some decent webmail and it being a brilliant webmail system at the unbeatable price of free.</p>

<p>Here is my quick guide to migrating easily:</p>

<p>Migrating emails &ndash; sign up to the free trial of the premier edition and use the IMAP migration system. It is by far the slickest option and will faithfully and accurately import all of your emails across. Best, you can set it going and then shut down your local machine, its all handled server side, so no requirement to shunt emails up from your desktop or anything like that.</p>

<p>Nested Folders &ndash; if you do the above and have a lot of nested folders, you will notice a pretty ugly massive list of tags with forward slashes in. To get back your nested sub folder like functionality you need to go to settings, then labs and then enabled the nested tags extension. This will give you a sub folder like interface for your tags and tidy the whole thing up.</p>

<p>Turn off those adds at the top &ndash; If you notice adds being displayed at the top and would like to get rid, its easy &ndash; Gmail calls them web clips and you can turn them off in the settings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
