<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: varnish | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/varnish/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-12T14:05:23+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Varnish and Nginx redirecting to port 8080]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/nginx/varnish/varnish-and-nginx-redirecting-to-port-8080.html"/>
    <updated>2015-01-23T15:22:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/nginx/varnish/varnish-and-nginx-redirecting-to-port-8080</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So theres a strange problem where any redirects are going port 8080 when running your web application or site under varnish and nginx. Now arroung the web the solution apears to have varnish listen locally on port 80 while leaving nginx to listen on port 80 for any network addresses. The issue is that nginx when doing a redirect will add the port automatically to any redirect specified in nginx or is triggered from php, this is so that you dont have to ajust your rewrites if you are running on a non standard web port. But in the case of running varnish on top we dont want this behaviour to happen.</p>

<p>To stop this in the location, server or http context of your nginx config. Simply add:</p>

<p><code>bash
port_in_redirect off;
</code></p>

<p>As by default according to the <a href="http://nginx.org/en/docs/http/ngx_http_core_module.html#port_in_redirect">nginx documentation</a> this behaviour is on by default.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Performance Problems]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-performance-problems.html"/>
    <updated>2012-04-16T08:56:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-performance-problems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are having performance issues with your Magento store and you are running on a dedicated or VPS server that you think should be up to the task of running your store properly but you continue to have performance problems then this post is for you.</p>

<p>Having decent server specification is only the first step on the road to having a high performance Magento store. Without proper configuration your server is not going to make the best use of its resources and that could make the difference of literally seconds or even tens of seconds of page load time.</p>

<p>The first and most important thing to check is that you are running a PHP opcode cacher such as APC. Opcode caching takes your PHP source code and compiles it to opcodes and then stores this in a cache. This opcode is actually what is run when people visit your store and the process of creating it, especially if you have a very large application with lots of file (like Magento), can be a real performance bottleneck. This problem is easily resolved by having APC installed and configured. If you are not sure, ring your hosting company and find out and if you don&rsquo;t have it running, ask them to set it up for you.</p>

<p>The next thing to check is MySQL configuration. The standard MySQL configuration defaults were set when server hardware and memory was a tiny fraction of what it is today and that means that the configuration is generally way too sparse with allocation of memory for caching and other optimisations. Tweaking MySQL can be a little tricky, its definitely not something you should do if you are not sure, but it is well worth getting someone to optimise your MySQL configuration.</p>

<p>After that, the next major performance gain with Magento is to make proper use of block caching. Magento has a brilliant built in feature where every block (page section) can be cached so that next time someone visits the page, the logic used to generate that section of page (for example a best sellers list) does not have to be run, we simply redisplay the cached copy of that block&rsquo;s HTML.</p>

<p>Beyond these three steps there are still many more things that can be done to improve the performance of your Magento store. If you would like professional help getting the best out of your server and Magento with a view to getting the lowest possible page load speeds then get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
