<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: cpanel | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/cpanel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-04T14:45:41+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento cPanel Backup Issue - Not Backing up the Core Folder + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-cpanel-backup-issue-not-backing-up-the-core-folder-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-11-15T13:06:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-cpanel-backup-issue-not-backing-up-the-core-folder-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are hosting a Magento site on cPanel powered hosting and are relying on the cPanel backup system to manage backing up your files then you need to be aware of this issue.</p>

<p>After a recent upgrade, cPanel has started to ignore any code inside a core/ directory when doing backups.</p>

<p>Of course this means that your app/code/core folder will not be backed up &ndash; of course this is the most crucial folder in your Magento installation.</p>

<p>Hopefully you are not editing core files anyway, so ultimately you shoudl be able to redownload your Magento version and extract the app/code/core folder from there, but even so, this is an extra step that you might need to take which will slow down your recovery in case of a disaster.</p>

<p>See this Magento forum thread for more details:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/boards/viewthread/210785/">http://www.magentocommerce.com/boards/viewthread/210785/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
