<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/job/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 16:15:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/job/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Job Bradford</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/job/php-job-bradford.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 16:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/job/php-job-bradford.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a PHP developer looking for a job in the Bradford area then please do get in touch with Edmonds Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a team of PHP developers who focus on e-commerce based on open source packages such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk&#34;&gt;Magento&lt;/a&gt;, osCommerce, Prestashop, OpenCart and others. We also do a fair bit of Wordpress, Drupal, Zend Framework etc as well. We even do bespoke PHP development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a skilled PHP developer and would like to join a team of enthusiastic developers in a friendly flexible environment with a focus on productivity, personal skills development and fun then get in touch with us today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs in Leeds, PHP and Admin/Sales</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/job/jobs-in-leeds-php-and-adminsales.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 10:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/job/jobs-in-leeds-php-and-adminsales.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Edmonds Commerce are hiring at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;PHP Job Leeds&lt;/h2&gt;
We are always looking to grow our team of Leeds based professional PHP Developers. If you are at or around the Zend Certified Developer level and think you would pass the exam given a little time and preparation then please get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Administration Job Leeds&lt;/h2&gt;
At the moment we are also looking for someone to join the team to help with administration and general customer services requirements. There is the possibility for this role to grow to meet your personal skills and ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For either role, please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/recruitment-contact-form/&#34;&gt;Job Application form&lt;/a&gt; to apply for a Job in Leeds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Job Leeds, Still Hiring Developers</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-job-leeds-hiring-developers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 18:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-job-leeds-hiring-developers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Just an update for any PHP developers in and around the Leeds, Bradford and West Yorkshire region:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are still looking for skilled and enthusiastic PHP developers to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our focus is entirely on e-commerce which is an exciting and challenging field for the right kind of person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect our developers to be at or around the Zend Certified Developer level but other than that there are no specific criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested please do get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will initially ask you to do a quick PHP quiz, if you want to do that straight away just go here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmonds-commerce.co.uk/PHPTest/form.php&#34;&gt;http://www.edmonds-commerce.co.uk/PHPTest/form.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us&#34;&gt;get in touch directly&lt;/a&gt; as well though, the spam bots quite enjoy filling it out as well and I haven&amp;rsquo;t got around to protecting it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Jobs Leeds</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-jobs-leeds.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 14:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-jobs-leeds.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Looking for PHP Jobs in the Leeds area?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have come to the right place. Edmonds Commerce are actively recruiting PHP developers in the Leeds area. We have more work on than we can handle and that&amp;rsquo;s only likely to grow even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to work as a PHP Developer with Edmonds Commerce in Leeds then &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/?about=php-jobs-leeds&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as we have a great job to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/about/job-recruitment-php-developer-leeds/&#34;&gt;PHP Jobs&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/about/job-recruitment-php-developer-leeds/&#34;&gt;Leeds&lt;/a&gt; by visiting this page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://is.gd/phpjobleeds&#34;&gt;http://is.gd/phpjobleeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are from anywhere in or around Leeds, Bradford, Hunslet, Beeston Hill, Knowsthorpe, Kirkstall, Belle Isle, Farnley, Beeston, Killingbeck, Meanwood, Bramley, Adel, Stanningley, Moortown, Gildersome  and looking for PHP work then get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Developer Job - Come Work With Us</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-developer-job-come-work-with-us.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 13:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-developer-job-come-work-with-us.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We are currently looking for a new PHP developer to join our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal candidate will be a highly competent PHP developer comfortable working with both procedural and object oriented PHP code. We focus nearly entirely on ecommerce, mainly osCommerce (and derivatives such as Zen Cart, CRE Loaded etc) and of course Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more though, Magento is what we are working on, so if you are more comfortable with object oriented coding than procedural that&amp;rsquo;s not too much of a problem. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know OO coding though, you might struggle with Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with a high level of PHP competency, we would also expect a good grounding in HTML, CSS and Javascript. Any other skills that you have will also be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in the Leeds area (or able to commute to Leeds easily enough) and would like to discuss the role, please send us an email via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-jobs.html&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>