<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: upgrade | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/upgrade/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-14T13:45:08+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrading from Fedora 19 to 20 using FedUp]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Fedora/upgrading-from-fedora-19-to-20-using-fedup.html"/>
    <updated>2014-01-03T19:32:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Fedora/upgrading-from-fedora-19-to-20-using-fedup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to upgrade to the latest version because why not, its the first Friday of the year.</p>

<p>The first thing to do is head over to <a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FedUp">this page</a> which explains how to use the tool.</p>

<p>I spotted the note about the 19-20 upgrade not working unless you install the bleeding edge version of the tool so thats to do first:</p>

<p><code>
sudo yum -y --enablerepo=updates-testing install fedup
</code></p>

<p>You also need to make sure that your system is fully up to date so lets do that. Once this is done you probably want to reboot to be on the safe side.</p>

<p><code>
sudo yum -y update
</code></p>

<p>Once that is all done then you need to run the fedup command itself:</p>

<p><code>
sudo yum -y update fedup fedora-release
sudo fedup --network 20
</code></p>

<p><em>I did this though and had an issue with RMPFusion. To fix that you need to run this command, then run the fedup command again:</em>
<code>
sudo rpm --import /etc/pki/rpm-gpg/RPM-GPG-KEY-rpmfusion-nonfree-fedora-20
sudo fedup --network 20
</code></p>

<p>Once fedup completes successfully you can reboot and will have an upgrade option as your first GRUB option when booting up. Select that to start the main upgrade.
It takes a while, make a brew or something.</p>

<p>Once you log in, you will no doubt notice some of your Gnome Shell Extensions are not working. Thankfully the process of upgrading these is pretty painless, just head over to
<a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/local/">https://extensions.gnome.org/local/</a> and you will see all your extensions. Any that are not compatible with your new version of Gnome Shell will have OUTDATED written where the on/off slider usually resides. Those with upgraded versions will have an upgrade button. Click that for each one, accepting the prompt.
When that&rsquo;s done, refresh the page and you should see all your upgraded extensions are now working.</p>

<p>For me the only one I&rsquo;m really going to miss is the <a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/352/middle-click-to-close-in-overview/">Quick Close in Overview</a> which is really handy, hopefully will be updated soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento 1.8 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-8-released.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-30T10:01:28+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-8-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I got a notification through that Magento 1.8 had finally been released.</p>

<p>This has been in beta since alpha since April, and contains server fixes that a lot of people have been waiting for.</p>

<p>The most important one for UK vendors is that the rounding issue in tax calculations has been fixed.</p>

<p>There are also improvements to caching and database performance. The full release notes can be seen <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/knowledge-base/entry/ce-18-later-release-notes">here</a></p>

<p>These are issues that have affected merchants since that change in the VAT rate, so we would recommend upgrading for everyone at this time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ongoing Magento Support and Consultation]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T15:52:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.buckleylondon.com">Buckley</a> is a UK based company that prides itself on designing and manufacturing high quality fashion &amp; costume jewellery at competitive prices since its inception in 1989. The company has rapidly expanded into a worldwide brand with jewellery collections available to a vast market of over 200 stores including more than 60 Duty Free shops and 120 airlines . We are glad to hear that Buckley has contributed over US$3 million to the funding of the Royal British Legion through the sale of its elegant Buckley Poppy.</p>

<h3>The development idea:</h3>


<p>Buckley Jewellery was initially launched using Wordpress and used an ecommerce package called ShopperPress. As the company grew and they started to expand their business to Duty Free shops and airlines, it became apparent that WordPress could not provide enough support for their complex modifications and customisations. This is when the idea of re-building the site in Magento was suggested.</p>

<p>We started working with Buckley in 2011 and have been providing them with continuous support since then. Some of the main requirements were broadly to do the following:</p>

<h3>1. Magento implementation and migration from previous platform</h3>


<p>We installed and configured Magento onto Buckley’s chosen hosting platform and installed the essential extensions such as shipping and payment gateways including PayPal and SagePay. We also migrated all of their products, customers and orders database from the previous platform into Magento. A clean and clear design was created and customised to their specification and we have been tweaking it per their needs and requirements ever since.</p>

<h3>2. Magento training</h3>


<p>After successfully migrating the site to Magento, we did an <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-course-details/">on-site one day introduction course</a> with Buckley, where we gave them the background understanding and some useful skills required to get the most out of their new Magento store.
Here is a quote from Mark at Buckley Jewellry: “<em>The day was extremely useful with just the right amount of content to set us on our way</em>.”</p>

<h3>3. Magento upgrade and Magento security patch applied</h3>


<p>It is important to make sure that your Magento site is up to date. We have done two upgrades for Buckley so far and they all went really well.The upgrades were done in three separate phrases &ndash; exploratory upgrade, bugs fixing and deployment to live. We hit a few bugs but managed to fix them within hours.
Around mid July 2012, a serious security hole was found in Zend Framework which allow hackers to gain access to mysql server credentials. A patch was quickly applied to Buckley live store using a nice Bash script we put together. We offered this free security patching service to all Magento sites with a voluntary charity donation and had a lot of sites take us up on this offer.</p>

<h3>4. Ongoing support</h3>


<p>Buckley have joined our retainer scheme where we provide them with daily maintenance supports, bugs fixing and consultation services. Various <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery/">firesale promotions</a>, extensions and marketing exercises were installed and configured into their website.
Recently we had migrated Buckley and its sister site <a href="http://www.attwoodandsawyer.com">Attwood &amp; Sawyer</a> to a dedicated server, which is faster, more secured and gives them better control over the sites.
Buckley also engages in designing beautiful vintage inspired pieces in the silver <a href="http://www.bouton.co.uk/">Bouton</a> rages and we are currently managing the merger process of Bouton into Buckley main sites.</p>

<h3>Testimonial</h3>


<p>Here is a quote from Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery:</p>

<p><em>“Buckley Jewellery originally approached <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk">Edmonds Commerce</a> to take our existing site and develop it onto a <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/platforms/magento/">Magento platform</a>. Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp; expand our ecommerce business. The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design. I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice”. </em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb1.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T17:36:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of our clients use <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.</p>

<p>The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.</p>

<p>The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.</p>

<p>The last release for PHP 5.2 was <a href="http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1" target="_blank">version 5.2.16 released back in 2010</a>. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.</p>

<p>You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php" target="_blank">this page</a>.</p>

<p>If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then <b><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today</a></b>.</p>

<p>Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> or <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/opencart">OpenCart</a>. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MySQL 5.1 to 5.5 Migration]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-5-1-to-5-5-migration.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T11:09:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-5-1-to-5-5-migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>According to pretty much every source there&rsquo;s only one sensible way to migrate from 5.0, 5.1 or 5.2 to 5.5 of mysql (or mariadb/percona for that matter), and it&rsquo;s not pretty (for a server with only two active magento installations for instance, this will take about 3 hours).</p>

<p>The answer is that you have to do an sql dump and restore.  This does take an age but does at least provide the reassurance that you are going to have nice clean databases after the upgrade.</p>

<p>So the commands are :&ndash;
```bash</p>

<p>mysqldump &mdash;all-databases &mdash;routines &mdash;events > fulldump.sql
mysqldump mysql &mdash;tables user > users.sql</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Then upgrade mysql binaries to 5.5 and empty the database directory &ndash; such as /var/lib/mysql and start mysql with it&rsquo;s script (e.g. /etc/init.d/mysql start).   Note, if you&rsquo;re using a distribution that doesn&rsquo;t come with start scripts, you may want to run mysql_install as root before starting mysql however you start it.</p>

<p>Then the following will restore the databases and users :
```bash</p>

<p>mysql -u root # add -p if you set up a default password when upgrading/installing 5.5
\r mysql
source users.sql
source fulldump.sql
FLUSH PRIVILEGES;
\q</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
