<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ebay on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/ebay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ebay on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 20:34:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/ebay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebay Security Breach</title>
      <link>http://example.com/security/ebay-security-breach.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 20:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/security/ebay-security-breach.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is being reported that there has been a database breach at eBay leading to the leaking of encrypted passwords&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there has not been any reported access to user accounts it is worth updating your password for eBay and any other site that share the same password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is considered bad practice to have the same password for multiple site, so to help me keep track of all of them I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;lastpass&lt;/a&gt; to make the job simpler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full statement for ebay is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebayinc.com/in_the_news/story/ebay-inc-ask-ebay-users-change-passwords&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play.com to Go Marketplace Only - Abandoning Retail Completely</title>
      <link>http://example.com/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most online merchants who are into multichannel selling (that&amp;rsquo;s all of you, right?) must have heard of Play.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never quite up there with Amazon and Ebay it was often the one that merchants asked us to integrate with once the two big ones were taken care of. Play was originally a pure online retailer but decided a few years ago to jump on the marketplace bandwagon like market leaders Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it seems Play have been bought out by a Japanese company and thanks to a lucrative VAT loophole being closed (and rightly so) they have now decided to abandon retail sales completely and concentrate purely on their marketplace business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about it here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042&#34;&gt;http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it might be worth checking out their current clearance for particularly good offers as well from a punters point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento and eBay integration now Free</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-and-ebay-integration-now-free.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 12:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-and-ebay-integration-now-free.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the acquisition of Magento by eBay, one of the major extension developers, Ess, now has an agreement with eBay/Magento to provide their integration extension free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://m2epro.ess-ua.com/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s their site&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/magento-connect/ebay-magento-integration-order-importing-and-stock-level-synchronization.html&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s the extension on Magento Connect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also worth knowing that the extension is avaiable on Magento Go, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for hosted-only, management-free eCommerce with integration with eBay, that might be an option.  Remember that Magento Go is not extendable by third parties though as it is a locked-down solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, some of the features of the extension are :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stock Level Synchronisation between eBay and Magento Stores&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create eBay listing templates which can create eBay listings direct from your Magento products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple eBay accounts per store&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically leave feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eBay transaction and order import&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>