<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: hook | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/hook/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-03T12:47:48+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Git to Track DB Schema Changes with Git Hook]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/using-git-to-track-db-schema-changes-with-git-hook.html"/>
    <updated>2010-01-28T10:48:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/using-git-to-track-db-schema-changes-with-git-hook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you use Git for version control and you would like to also keep a track of your database schema (and possibly content though I&rsquo;m not doing that due to potential file sizes / speed issues) then all you need to do is this simple step:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Go to your project folder and into the hidden .git folder, then a sub folder in there called hooks
<code>
cd .git/hooks
</code></p></li>
<li><p>Create a file called pre-commit and open it in vim (or whatever text editor you like)
<code>
vim pre-commit
</code></p></li>
<li><p>Add a mysql dump command to that file and save it
```</p></li>
</ol>


<h1>!/bin/sh</h1>

<p>mysqldump -u DBUSER -pDBPASSWORD  DATABASE &mdash;no-data=true > SQLVersionControl/vc.sql
git add SQLVersionControl/vc.sql
exit 0</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>(note this assumes you have a folder called SQLVersionControl in the root of your project. If you don&rsquo;t just create it.)</p>

<p>No without any further effort, you will update the schema file on every commit.</p>

<p>eg
```</p>

<p>git commit -am &lsquo;this commit will include a mysql schema dump that has been run just before the commit &ndash; sweet :)&rsquo;</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
