<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Cart on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/categories/open-cart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Cart on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 13:31:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/categories/open-cart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Cart Developer UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/open-cart/open-cart-developer-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 13:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/open-cart/open-cart-developer-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
At Edmonds Commerce we are always keeping a close eye on the latest and greatest ecommerce platforms available. For the majority of our clients we recommend Magento as we feel that it is an excellent platform for SME level businesses to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If however the priority is on simplicity rather than features then more and more we are recommending Open Cart as the platform of choice. The differences between the two platforms are quite significant, though ultimatey both will give end users a nice interface and both have excellent SEO features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a UK based e-commerce specialist PHP development company that can help you set up your Open Cart based business then please do get in touch today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>