<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Local on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/local/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Local on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 20:21:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/local/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Wordpress Website for SDM Architecture</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/architecture-wordpress-website-for-sdm-architecture.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 20:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/architecture-wordpress-website-for-sdm-architecture.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have recently launched a clean, clear and simple web site for local architects &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sdmarchitecture.co.uk/&#34;&gt;SDM architecture&lt;/a&gt; who are based in Baildon near Shipley, Bradford and Leeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brief was a clean web site that Stephen the owner can easily manage with his own content showcasing his work and attracting new clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all the project was a big success with a very rapid turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen said
&amp;ldquo;you have been very helpful and I have appreciated everything you have done for me&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here is a screenshot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/Screenshot-600x320.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netbeans &#43; Xdebug Not Highlighting Lines or Opening Files when Step Through Debugging &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/netbeans-xdebug-not-highlighting-lines-or-opening-files-when-step-through-debugging-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 10:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/netbeans-xdebug-not-highlighting-lines-or-opening-files-when-step-through-debugging-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you use Netbeans along with Xdebug to facilitate step through debugging when coding PHP then you may come across this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible to get it into a semi working scenario where you can have working breakpoints and see variable values but you have no idea which bit of code you are actually stepped up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can happen if your server path and project path are not correctly configured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To resolve this simply go to your project properties, run configuration and then hit the advanced button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The server path should be the absolute path to the project root on the server (eg /home/server/sites/blah/) and the project path should be the path on your local machine to the project files (eg /home/joseph/projects/blah/).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop any debugging sessions and then start another one up and if you have the paths set right, you should get the behaviour you expect where Netbeans highlights the current line of code and allows you to step through the code to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s going on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>