<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 17:17:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Streets Of York and Participation in First Ever PHP Yorkshire conference</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/exploring-streets-of-york-and-participation-in-first-ever-php-yorkshire-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 17:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/exploring-streets-of-york-and-participation-in-first-ever-php-yorkshire-conference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When something unbelievable happens, people tend to say “you were in the right place at the right time” that’s why you’re lucky. That is how I feel what happened to me here at Edmonds Commerce Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within first few weeks since I started working on Magento projects here at Edmonds. Nolwenn came to me with a question. “Hey Tadas, development team is going to this conference ‘PHP Yorkshire’, they don’t know what to expect, but it will be fun, will you join them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then in my head I am like “Wow, my first weeks and I got this promising opportunity to spend the weekend knowing my colleagues better and listen to these passionate people who loves PHP”. Who could decline such offer? So off we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunny Friday evening, we are all set and heading to the city of York, which distanced just a bit more than hour from our office in Shipley. Few rounds of everyone&amp;rsquo;s preferred music requests and here we are, passing the door to explore York after we have left our belongings in the place we stayed overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-night-in-york-or-how-to-know-the-city-centre-within-3-pubs&#34;&gt;The night in York or how to know the city centre within 3 pubs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not into architecture, but York looked very appealing to me and it was my first time visiting it, definitely not last. I didn’t see any building there which would look out of sync. And the buzz of people on the Friday night was more on the calm side, just the way I like. But let’s move onto the fun stuff. So our first stop was just meters away from the place we stayed where we order some beer and appreciated the moment and the beginning of night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then another bar/pub and another. Everyone know how it goes, don’t we? The heading of this part might be too cheesy, you definitely can’t cover all the beauty of York within the distance of 3 pubs, but yeah&amp;hellip; York is great and the beer is great too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-day&#34;&gt;The Big Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are, little bit tired from the night before, but we stood tall in the morning, ready to enjoy our day. I was amazed to be honest, that we were just right on time to begin our conference in the University of York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what was this all conference about? 1 day, 2 tracks, 13 experts. So after all, everyone was satisfied with how it ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest I enjoyed all of the talks I have participated in but the most memorable to me was about HTML5 API’s, naming things and object calisthenics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my colleagues loved the speeches on GIT internals, handling errors gracefully, and they got answered what MySQL 8 is all about and why it is 8 and not any other number and Joseph have even won a MySQL dolphin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the weekend was enjoyable, I am glad I had a chance to be there, know my colleagues better and just be inspired by the talks and the community of PHP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Tadas&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP UK Conference In London</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/programming/usability/php-uk-conference-in-london.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/programming/usability/php-uk-conference-in-london.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you might be aware, the UK PHP Conference was held in London last weekend. Having been the lucky winner of a ticket from PHP NW I went along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Venue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference was held in The Brewery in London city centre, a well suited conference centre with a variety of different conference rooms. An old Whitbread brewery, it was modern and practical while still maintaining enough of its history to keep its character. Overall the venue was great and it was good to have the variety of different rooms for all of the different events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talks on offer were on a wide variety of subjects, varying from the very specific libraries to things of use to any PHP developer. Each of the talks was led by a volunteer giving up their time to speak about a subject for which they held a passion, it came across very well and as ever is good to hear from active members of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks I found to be of particular interest were
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future of the PHP Development Environment&lt;/strong&gt; A practical introduction to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vagrantup.com/&#34; title=&#34;Vagrant&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;, demonstrating its purpose in creating a reliable, predictable server environment. Covered was the installation, configuration and use of the software&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenStreetMap for the Web&lt;/strong&gt; An enthusiastic demonstration of the power of having openly accessible data of the world&amp;rsquo;s maps and the APIs which enable a plethora of different applications&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Hands-On Introduction to Writing Unit Tests Using PHPUnit&lt;/strong&gt; A very practical (with live coding and demonstration of the Unit Tests, a risky move that paid off) intro to unit tests in PHP. Aimed at the very beginner, it started slowly with very simple tests but showed the power of them in much bigger projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;In summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed the day, and would recommend anyone wanting to attend in future. The talks will be posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://phpconference.co.uk/schedule&#34; title=&#34;PHP UK Website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PHP UK website&lt;/a&gt; in the coming weeks so you should be able to get a sample of the events there&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PHPNW12 Round UP</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpnw12-round-up.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpnw12-round-up.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All of the PHP developers from Edmonds Commerce made our annual pilgramage over the Pennines to Manchester this weekend to visit arguably one of the best PHP conferences around - PHP North West, PHPNW for short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a three track conference with a diverse range of expert PHP developers giving presentations on some really interesting topics. The team split up and chose their own route through the choice of talks meaning that between us all we got a real flavour of the entire conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They Keynote by Ade Oshineye was all to do with API development and DevX - developer experience as opposed to the more usual and in vogue UX - user experience. The point being that users are often getting a lot of thought put into their experiences but developers are often given sparsely documented and unwieldy APIs to work with. The metaphor of a door with an ambiguous push/pull requirement was really apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particular highlights for me included the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodephp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ReactPHP&lt;/a&gt; talk by Igor Wiedler which was both entertaining and really informative. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeromq.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ØMQ (zero MQ)&lt;/a&gt; layer looks really interesting among other things. The guys that went to the Data structures talk by Patrick Allaert were really impressed with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take homes from the conference in terms of projects and technologies to keep an eye on include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getcomposer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Composer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silex.sensiolabs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Silex Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nodephp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;React PHP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeromq.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ØMQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/code/6752709412171743&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services Command Line Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PHPNW09 Round Up</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpnw09-round-up.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 20:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpnw09-round-up.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
This weekend saw the second annual PHP North West conference in Manchester. It was great :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After seeing two talks that touched upon the Symfony framework plus the plethora of other developers with an almost religious passion for the framework that I spoke to, I will definitely be getting into it soon. Especially now I have seen that I can try the Symfony framework and still have access to some of the cool Zend Framework modules such as Zend_Mail as demonstrated by Stefan Koopmanschap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison to PHP London, they managed to restrict the Microsoft evangelists to a roughly 15 minute slot rather than a full slot on track 1, which was a welcome relief. I used the time to try to register my free PHP Architect Magazine voucher and extend my subscription. (Didn&amp;rsquo;t actually work though, but I seem to remember there were issues last year as well, customer service request pending).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the talk about Xdebug as well. Xdebug is so awesome, it was great to see an in depth explanation of all of its features, there were a few that I have yet to play with. Also great to see that my favourite FOSS IDE, Netbeans, is regarded by Derick Rethans, the inventor of Xdebug, to be the second best IDE for use with Xdebug. He prefers Komodo which I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually tried and is paid for software so that makes Netbeans the best open source IDE (I already knew it was).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was good to get an overview of the SPL library by Michelangelo van Dam. Its one of the features of PHP that I know I should probably use more and it was great to have some demonstrations of the capabilities of the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all it was a great conference and the food was really nice too :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to next year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>phpuk2009 Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpuk2009-tomorrow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 09:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpuk2009-tomorrow.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m going down to London tonight because tomorrow is the PHP UK Conference of 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to it :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phpconference.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.phpconference.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>