<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: help | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/help/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-11T14:12:46+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Security Vulnerability + Free Assistance]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-security-vulnerability-free-assistance.html"/>
    <updated>2012-07-10T13:07:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-security-vulnerability-free-assistance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The magento platform is based on a PHP framework called Zend Framework.</p>

<p>Recently a bug was found in Zend Framework which potentially allows attackers to read any file on your server. This could mean they could gain access to your mysql server credentials for example.</p>

<p>You can read the full details <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/blog/comments/update-zend-framework-vulnerability-security-update/">here</a>.</p>

<p>The actual bug details for Zend Framework are in this <a href="http://framework.zend.com/security/advisory/ZF2012-01">security advisory</a>.</p>

<h3>Free Security Patching Service</h3>


<p>In a nutshell this represents a serious security hole that you need to plug as soon as possible. Fixing this issue is very simple indeed if you know what you are doing.</p>

<p>For this reason Edmonds Commerce are happy to offer <b>FREE</b> assistance in applying this patch to any Magento store owner whether you are a current client or not. We will not charge you in any way for this service.</p>

<p>To request <b>FREE</b> assistance <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/?about=Free+Magento+Security+Fix"><b>contact us today</b></a></p>

<h3>Donation to Charity</h3>


<p>If you choose to, you could make a donation to cover this service here:
<a href="http://www.justgiving.com/EdmondsCommerce"><a href="http://www.justgiving.com/EdmondsCommerce">http://www.justgiving.com/EdmondsCommerce</a></a></p>

<h3>Please Note</h3>


<p>We will need you to give us shell (otherwise known as SSH) access to your server if available.</p>

<p>If you are on a shared hosting service that is not able to supply shell access, we would suggest you ask your hosting company to help you with this issue. Feel free to refer them to this page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
