<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: python | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/python/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-11T14:12:46+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Desktop Slideshow Recursive Folder]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/python/ubuntu-desktop-slideshow-recursive-folder.html"/>
    <updated>2011-01-08T11:50:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/python/ubuntu-desktop-slideshow-recursive-folder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you use Ubuntu, you probably use F-Spot for managing your photos. It&rsquo;s a nice app and it organises all your photos into a directory tree based on date.</p>

<p>If you want to set up a desktop slideshow that shows images from this folder tree then you need to create a custom XML file that you can then set as the desktop background. Of course you need a system to create the slideshow.</p>

<p>This script does just that:</p>

<script type="text/javascript" src="http://snipt.net/embed/7cb620ed391c0a6e72548a0cc804fe3a"></script>


<p>Inspired by a few scripts I found on the web, though <a href="http://royvandewater.com/blog/2009/12/ubuntu-wallpaper-slideshow/">this is the one I based it on</a>, simply modified to make it recursively pull images rather than just images in the current directory and also shuffle the resulting list.</p>

<p>Place the script in the root of your ~/Photos directory, mark it as executable and then run it. It generates an XML file for you. You can now go to your desktop, right click and go to background then hit the [Add] button.</p>

<p>Now navigate to your ~/Photos directory and select the generated XML file. Job done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python Developer UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/python/python-developer-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-12-13T16:57:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/python/python-developer-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Looking for UK based Python development services, you have come to the right place. Edmonds Commerce can help you with your Python requirements.</p>

<p>Python is an excellent choice of language for anything from simple scripts up to large scale applications. Python applications can be fast and yet easy to work on.</p>

<p>There are a number of excellent Python based applications out there such as OpenERP and the Django web framework.</p>

<p>Get in touch with Edmonds Commerce about Python today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
