<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Browser on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/browser/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Browser on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 16:42:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/browser/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Useful features of the Opera Browser for Web Developers</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/opera/useful-features-of-the-opera-browser-for-web-developers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 16:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/opera/useful-features-of-the-opera-browser-for-web-developers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Remotely debugging mobile websites using your Android phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/remotedebug-600x352.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Dragonfly, Opera&amp;rsquo;s answer to Firebug and Chrome&amp;rsquo;s Developer Tools has a killer feature: it&amp;rsquo;s able to let you use your local desktop to debug a page on another instance of Opera - including Opera Mobile
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What this means is that all the benefits you get from inspecting elements on your desktop can be done on your Android phone. You can have the full array of debugging: inspecting specific elements, checking the CSS being applied to elements, changing the CSS in real time, and editing the HTML. You can even tap specific elements on your phone and they&amp;rsquo;ll be selected in your desktop&amp;rsquo;s Dragonfly instance.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1. Connect your phone to the same wifi network as your desktop/laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/RemoteConnect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3. On your phone open Opera Mobile and go to opera:debug in your URL bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4. Enter your desktop&amp;rsquo;s IP address or hostname and tap Connect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/tabselect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. Separating and grouping local, staging and live tabs for the site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/tabstackingannotated2-600x191.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You know the situation - you have three different versions of the site in your tabs - some for local, some on staging and maybe some for the live site too. Keeping track of which is which can be difficult with them having the same favicon, title etc
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tab Stacking is a way of grouping your tabs in various ways, including grouping all your local, staging and live tabs into their own respective groups - avoiding the confusion of which tab belongs to which instance
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Validating Local Web Pages In 2 Clicks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/validate2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The W3C validator is the standard place to validate your web pages, but of course you can&amp;rsquo;t pass in your local URL to the validator. The only option you have is to right-click &amp;gt; view source, select all and copy, open a new tab for the validator, select Direct Input and press Validate - phew!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are of course extensions for this in Chrome and Firefox, but I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of any which allow you to use the official W3C validator
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Opera&amp;rsquo;s right-click context menu allows you to simply right-click any page and click Validate. Opera will then automatically post the rendered HTML to the Validator and give you instant results
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. Site-Specific Preferences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/Site-specific-preferences-600x466.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;ll want to have different settings for websites you&amp;rsquo;re currently working on - maybe you want to enable a more liberal cookie policy, or you want to show Flash content automatically only on sites you&amp;rsquo;re developing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For other browsers this means multiple instances of the browser, or installing addons. In Opera you can set up a whole array of configurations on a per-site basis by simnply right-clicking the page and selecting Edit Site Preferences
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. Cross Browser Testing made easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/OpenWith-600x79.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cross-browser testing is important. When developing a specific page it&amp;rsquo;s often useful to open the page in an array of browsers to check that it&amp;rsquo;s consistent across the board.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Opera automatically looks for other browsers installed on your system and gives you quick access to opening the current URL in them. Simply right-click your page, select Open With and then pick your browser. Opera will then launch an instance of the selected browser already landed on the right page.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Content HTTPS Red Line SSL Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/debugging/mixed-content-https-red-line-ssl-google-chrome.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 17:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/debugging/mixed-content-https-red-line-ssl-google-chrome.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If Chrome is displaying mix content errors this means that Chrome thinks that some of the resources on the page where loaded over HTTP rather than HTTPS. But one behaviour of Chrome that might catch you out is that if Chrome at any point on a domain encountered a page with mixed content, it will then treat the whole site as having mixed content even if a given single page does not have mixed content. Chrome is unlikely to tell you this is the reason a single page has mixed content, the best way to tell is to keep closing chrome, starting a new session and browse until you get mixed content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of an Era: Internet Explorer Drops Below 50 Percent of Web Usage</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webmonkey.com/2011/11/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage/&#34;&gt;http://www.webmonkey.com/2011/11/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who had had to either do an extra 50% of work to get IE working, or had to pay someone else to do so. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you are thinking what we think. Yes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View HTML Files from the Command Line - Linux</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/view-html-files-from-the-command-line-linux.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 11:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/view-html-files-from-the-command-line-linux.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you ever want to have a quick look at a html file from the command line (eg when SSHing into a server) then you will love this little app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Called w3m, its a basic text based browser that will render your html into readable formatted text right on the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great for me as I often create log files in a HTML format, before this the only way to read them was to either have them web accessible or download them and view them locally in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with this little app I can view them right in situ - dead handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install on Cent OS just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
yum install w3m

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome on Linux (Well Kind Of)</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/google-chrome-on-linux-well-kind-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 15:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/google-chrome-on-linux-well-kind-of.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeweavers.com/services/ports/chromium/&#34;&gt;Check this out - chromium (the open source backbone of Google Chrome) running on Linux, courtesy of the nice people at Code Weavers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul class=&#34;pc_pingback&#34;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://www.kev009.com/wp/2009/02/arora-a-refreshing-new-qtwebkit-browser/&#34;&gt;Arora, a refreshing new Qt/WebKit &lt;b&gt;browser&lt;/b&gt; | Kev009.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://www.winaddons.com/avant-browser-117-build-22/&#34;&gt;Avant &lt;b&gt;Browser&lt;/b&gt; 11.7 Build 22 winAddons.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://ajaydsouza.com/archives/2009/02/27/open-browser-window-crp-plugins-minor-updates/&#34;&gt;Open &lt;b&gt;Browser&lt;/b&gt; Window &amp;amp; CRP Plugins Minor Updates | Ajay - On the &lt;b&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul class=&#34;pc_pingback&#34;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://benolsatuem.com/2009/03/01/google-chrome-201670-beta-google-chrome-1015448/&#34;&gt;Google &lt;b&gt;Chrome&lt;/b&gt; 2.0.167.0 Beta/ Google &lt;b&gt;Chrome&lt;/b&gt; 1.0.154.48 | BeNolSatuEm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul class=&#34;pc_pingback&#34;&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Internet Explorer under Ubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-development/linux/ubuntu/web-design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 16:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-development/linux/ubuntu/web-design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Ubuntu Linux is undoubtedly the most successful desktop version of linux available today. It has managed to tempt across many dedicated windows users with its easy installation procedure, comprehensive bundle of applications including open office and firefox, its greater security and reduced vulnerability to internet viruses and malware. And of course the fact that it is free to download and install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a web designer, it is nice to have a sleek desktop environment to code in whilst being able to run a full LAMP stack web server as the localhost - meaning that designing and developing web sites is a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are times when you simply need to check that a design is going to work with Internet Explorer. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Internet Explorer web browser is bundled with windows and is therefore the most popular web browser at the moment. However as a web designer it causes problems as it often behaves erratically or unexpectedly. For this reason a web designer always needs to make sure that they check their designs in Internet Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason that Ubuntu users may need to use Internet Explorer is to log into certain sites which are not compatible with anything other than Internet Explorer. This is a real pet hate as it is real sign of laziness on the part of the web designers not to ensure that their web sites are accessible by all web browsers. Unfortunately the sites that tend to be like this are the ones that you really need, such as online banking sites. Its probably something to do with sloppy handling of ssl secure and insecure content, but I am not sure on that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway - to save you having to maintain a windows installation and reboot everytime you need to check something in Internet Explorer - there is the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IEs 4 Linux package&lt;/a&gt;. This great package allows you to easily install Internet Explorer under Ubuntu (or any other version of Linux).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have WINE installed and working, and also have the cabextractor working. Both of these packages are available in the syntaptic package manager in Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>