<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Server on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/categories/server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Server on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 10:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/categories/server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Running out of disk space but df shows you have lots of space left</title>
      <link>http://example.com/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 10:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a strange occurency this morning with an server reporting it had no disk space when disk usage according to df was at 50%. After some head scratching I decided to read the man page for the df command and came across the -i flag. According the man page this lists inode information instead of block usage. After running it I got the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Filesystem      Inodes   IUsed  IFree IUse% Mounted on
/dev/xvda1     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2621440&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2621440&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  100% /
udev            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;124879&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;398&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;124481&lt;/span&gt;    1% /dev
tmpfs           &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;288&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126604&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126888&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/lock
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126891&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/shm
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126891&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/user
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it turned out that the system had reached its max inodes so the next line of investigation was to find any excess of files in an directory. Which was sone by using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i in /var/*&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; find &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; wc -l&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will list the total number of files in a given directory. You can change the path to work your way down the directory tree finding directories with lots of files. In the end we found excess of old logs which I was able to remove.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Access, what is it all about in Simple Words?</title>
      <link>http://example.com/server/ssh-access-what-is-it-all-about-in-simple-words.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 16:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/server/ssh-access-what-is-it-all-about-in-simple-words.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What is an SSH access?&lt;/h3&gt;
SSH stands for Secure Socket Shell. SSH is a protocol, like HTTP, it gives us a way to gain a secure access to remote computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle is to connect two networked computers via a secure encrypted channel within an insecure network environment such as the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With SSH access we can easily move files around and run programs on your server. We can also transmit files to and from our own network onto your server, for example to take a copy of your site for local development or to push updated files onto your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSH needs a server application installing on your server (most web servers will have this by default) and an SSH client on your local machine to allow you to connect to your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Where do you get your SSH access from?&lt;/h3&gt;
If you need SSH access details you should ask your hosting company, they should be able to install it for you if it is not already in place. If you are on shared hosting then the chances are that you will not be able to get SSH access details, if you need SSH access then you should consider upgrading your hosting to something that will support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSH access details will consist of at least:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;domain or IP address:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
domain.com

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
123.123.123.123

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;username:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
mywebserverlogin

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;password:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
ihy324579ySDWf

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it may also include a port if SSH is not running on the standard port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
2020

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Why do we need the SSH access details?&lt;/h3&gt;
We will always ask our customers to provide us with SSH access details. This is for two main reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;1. Power and Speed&lt;/h4&gt;
SSH access allows us to run commands directly on the server, compress files, run scripts etc. For example we will generally run some static analysis scripts for our &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/platforms/magento&#34;&gt;Magento&lt;/a&gt; customers using a bash script that we can run with SSH access. This gives us some instant feedback on the state of your Magento installation and allows us to spot any potential problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we need to get a copy of your site files, using SSH we can prepare a compressed archive of your site files allowing us to download them much faster. Likewise we can easily get a reliable database dump, especially if you have a large database that might cause problems for browser based tools such as phpMyAdmin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;2. Security&lt;/h4&gt;
SSH is a much more secure protocol than something like FTP. In SSH everything is encrypted. It has been built from the ground up to be a very secure way of networking and inter communicating between servers on an insecure network such as the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C-Panel Access using WHS/Root Password</title>
      <link>http://example.com/server/c-panel-access-using-whsroot-password.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 15:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/server/c-panel-access-using-whsroot-password.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wondering how you could gain access into any Control panel(c-panel) account when you confidently know only the username of the c-panel account. I tried doing this by actually using the Web host manager (WHS) password, and it worked brilliantly for any c-panel user account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the only gotcha I found out  was that I could not use Phpmyadmin. Nevertheless, you could still find a way around this by adding a PHP database management file on the web root directory which installs an alternative database management User interface which provides functions similar to Phpmyadmin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>