<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: version | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/version/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-25T15:37:55+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Magento Version on the Command Line]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/get-magento-version-on-the-command-line.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T16:37:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/get-magento-version-on-the-command-line</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you just want to get the Magento version on the command line quickly try this one liner:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>php -r &quot;require &lsquo;app/Mage.php&rsquo;; echo Mage::getVersion(); &quot;</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Does exactly what you need</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Multi Store, Websites and Storeviews Explained]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-multi-store-websites-and-storeviews-explained.html"/>
    <updated>2012-10-16T13:56:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-multi-store-websites-and-storeviews-explained</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most exciting features of Magento for many merchants is the ability to run multiple front end websites with a single administration area. For those of you who have managed multiple separate installations of a cart system to power many websites, perhaps selling the same products, then this on its own can make a huge difference in terms of ease of management.</p>

<p>Magento has had multi store functionality designed in from the ground up. This results in a multistore implementation that feels solid and intuitive and also very powerful. This is in contrast to other carts' multi store systems which can often feel like a bit of a bolt on after thought that isn&rsquo;t as clearly embedded into the system.</p>

<h2>Magento Scopes</h2>


<p>Magento has a hierarchical system of stores with 4 levels.</p>

<h3>Global Scope</h3>


<p>The top of the hierarchy is the global scope. This scope defines the default values for the various attributes that products and categories contain. You can not see the global scope as a store front but in the admin side the global scope is the one you work in by default and is likely to be where you spend most of your admin time.</p>

<h3>Website Scope</h3>


<p>Magento has the concept of websites. You can think of a website as a domain name (though this is perhaps an over simplification). A website can contain one or more stores.</p>

<h3>Store Scope</h3>


<p>A store is the item that contains products and categories. A category structure is built from a &ldquo;root&rdquo; category. The root category is not displayed on the front end, its children categories become the top level categories for the store when viewed in the front end. A store can have it&rsquo;s own root category and structure or can share the same one used by other stores.</p>

<h3>Store View</h3>


<p>Every store contains at least one store view. You can generally think of store views as translations of a store (though this is not the only use case). The category structure will be the same for the various store views and this scope is generally used to store alternative values for textual content such as product names, descriptions etc.</p>

<h2>Editing Values on a Per Scope Basis</h2>


<p>When you are editing products, categories or configuration in your Magento admin you will have a drop down in the top left of the screen that determines which scope you are currently working in. As a best practice always try to be as close to the global scope as possible when making your edits, only descending into the lower scopes as required.</p>

<h2>Possibilites</h2>


<p>The possibilities of these various scopes are almost limitless, you can manage a large and diverse range of store fronts that may or may not be clearly related to each other from the customers point of view from a single Magento administration. Like many things in Magento, this powerful system can become complex and we really strongly advise that you plan out your store structure before you start actually adding things so that you ensure you are building a nice logical system that is going to scale up as you grow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStorm 5 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T09:07:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Edmonds Commerce we were staunch Netbeans users for years but we always struggled with large scale projects (<a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento/" title="Magento Platform Overview">Magento</a> I&rsquo;m looking at you) meaning that Netbeans would sometimes really crawl as it tried to reindex thousands of PHP files.</p>

<p>After a recent upgrade of our Linux desktop environment to the Mate edition of Linux Mint 13, Netbeans seemed to perform even worse and had a few bugs as well. At the same time we had been evaluating other IDE options including Eclipse and Zend Studio (which we all have free licences for thanks to being Zend Certified Developers).</p>

<p>In the end though, the one we tried that really impressed was PHPStorm. It isn&rsquo;t free open source but it isn&rsquo;t too expensive, especially considering it is perhaps the single most important and highly used tool of a professional PHP developer.</p>

<p>Now a new version has come out. Downloading and upgrading took all of 5 minutes and we are now going to enjoy better performance and some nice new features. I have yet to really test out the new version so I can&rsquo;t really report on them but they look good. You can read about all the new features in version 5 <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/whatsnew/" title="PHPStorm 5 Features" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento 2 - Key Points for Developers!]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-key-points-for-developers.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T14:41:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-key-points-for-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first development release of Magento 2 has a few areas worthy of note for developers of the coming changes to Magento.</p>

<p>Magento 2 now requires PHP 5.3
Zend is still version 1.11.1.
Magento 2 now implements templates on a per modules basis. So now all the different bits of the theme are separated into the modules it belongs to. This means that any existing version 1 theme cannot be dropped into version 2.
Themes in Magento 2 have the concept of variations of the same theme. So a theme can have different CSS and images but use the same templates, this can be configured per store per user agent in the admin. This is useful if you have different seasonable themes that are the same as each other but with a few different images and colours. To achieve the same in Magento 1 you would have to use packages and Magento&rsquo;s ability to cascade up, this is not longer necessary.</p>

<p>This development release of Magento has a major focus on updating the theme and template system to be more ridged unlike Magento version 1 where the template files could be basically any where within a theme.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento 2 Source Code Available on GitHub]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T07:37:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento version two is coming. For those of us who are eagerly awaiting the next major version of the most popular and powerful open source e-commerce platform, you can now see, track and download the code on GitHub.</p>

<p>Not had chance to have an in depth look as yet but we expect great things!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/magento/magento2"><a href="https://github.com/magento/magento2">https://github.com/magento/magento2</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
