<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: course | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/course/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-12T10:12:30+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Computer Science and Programming Online Courses]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/free-computer-science-and-programming-online-courses.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-07T12:49:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/free-computer-science-and-programming-online-courses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are looking to increase your knowledge in a variety of fields and are open to online training then you could be interested in this site:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.coursera.org/" target="_blank">www.coursera.org</a></p>

<p>There are loads of courses on there but of particular interest to us are the computer science ones. Not had a close look at them but they do look interesting and the fact they are free is of course a bonus!</p>

<p><a href="https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming" target="_blank"><a href="https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming">https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming</a></a> is the list of free computer programming courses</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Magento Training]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/online-magento-training.html"/>
    <updated>2010-05-12T09:33:17+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/online-magento-training</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><b>UPDATE</b>:

This course is now live and we are actively taking bookings. There is some funding available for people in the Yorkshire area, though the amount of funding may change as part of Government cuts. 

It is delivered online in 2 mornings, a total of 8 hours training. The course content is the same as our face to face training course, its simply the online delivery that is different.

If you would like to book on please <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/?about=online-magento-training">get in touch</a>
</blockquote>


<p><b>original post</b>:</p>

<p>If you are looking for some Magento training but are a little too far away from Leeds to do our classroom based <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-uk/">Magento training course</a> then you may well be interested in this.</p>

<p>We are currently beta testing a new online training delivery system based upon Elluminate which is a professional online training delivery system &ndash; emulating as close as possible the classroom experience online.</p>

<p>There are no fixed details about this online magento training as yet, we will update this post as soon as we have more information. If you are interested though please do <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/">get in touch</a> about our online magento training today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Training Course Feedback]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-feedback.html"/>
    <updated>2010-03-17T15:11:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-feedback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We just ran our Magento training course last week and despite some technical issues at the start of the day I think it was a great success. By the end of the day the delegates all knew their Attribute Sets from their Attribute Groups, could set up layered navigation, create configurable products the fastest way possible without using spreadsheets and generally had a good grounding to go and make the most out of their Magento web shops.</p>

<p>If you are interested in doing some Magento training, we have more course coming up all the time, just give us a call on <strong>0844 357 0201</strong> or drop as a line via our <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/">contact form</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symfony Training UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-training-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-02-15T11:06:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-training-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>After a few enquiries, we are looking into the possibility of setting up a Symfony training course based in Leeds in the UK.</p>

<p>At present this is not a firm plan but we are definitely looking into it and would really like some feedback on what kind of Symfony Training course you would like to see.</p>

<p>The course would likely be an introduction to the Symfony PHP framework, possibly going through the Jobeet sample site documentation which represents an excellent training framework.</p>

<p>At this stage it is not totally clear what we would need to include in the course, especially if we can expect candidates to already be familiar and confident with object oriented PHP. One option is that we do another course which is purely focussed on the object oriented aspects of PHP, like a crash course of OO PHP for coders who have no or little experience of this style of coding.</p>

<p>If you are interested and would like to share with us your ideas and expectations for a UK Symfony course please do get in touch. We will take your ideas on board and keep your info on file so we can let you know as and when the course goes live.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now Teaching Zend PHP Courses]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/now-teaching-zend-php-courses.html"/>
    <updated>2009-12-11T15:46:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/now-teaching-zend-php-courses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>I&rsquo;ve just finished my first delivery of a Zend PHP course module. It was the databases section of the higher structures course. Everyone seemed to enjoy it and I think it went really well. Its great to be able to help newcomers to PHP to get a better understanding of the language and see the power and flexibility that it offers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
