<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>5.2 on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/5/index.2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 5.2 on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 17:36:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/5.2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP</title>
      <link>http://example.com/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 17:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of our clients use &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/platforms/oscommerce&#34;&gt;osCommerce&lt;/a&gt; for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last release for PHP 5.2 was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;version 5.2.16 released back in 2010&lt;/a&gt;. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on &lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/contact-us&#34;&gt;get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/platforms/oscommerce&#34;&gt;osCommerce&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/platforms/opencart&#34;&gt;OpenCart&lt;/a&gt;. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flash Messenger Bug in Zend Framework &#43; Patch</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/flash-messenger-bug-in-zend-framework-patch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 16:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/flash-messenger-bug-in-zend-framework-patch.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Arrgh am I going mad.. could something so simple really not work..?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going mad, and Flash Messenger in Zend Framework really does have a bug. If its not working for you, the following patch may well fix things. You can check if this bug applies by setting your error reporting to E_ALL in your bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get the following error message then this patch should fix things for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Notice: Indirect modification of overloaded property Zend_Session_Namespace.....

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix this problem and get FlashMessenger working correctly, you need to edit library/Zend/Controller/Action/Helper/FlashMessenger.php&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;find this line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;self::$_session-&amp;gt;{$this-&amp;gt;_namespace}[] = $message;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and replace with this block&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt; //self::$_session-&amp;gt;{$this-&amp;gt;_namespace}[] = $message;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;$sessionMessages = self::$_session-&amp;gt;{$this-&amp;gt;_namespace};&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;$sessionMessages[] = $message;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;self::$_session-&amp;gt;{$this-&amp;gt;_namespace} = $sessionMessages;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently this issue only affects php 5.2 and so they have decided not to fix it and instead suggest upgrading the PHP version. If you need to get it working though the above will fix it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://framework.zend.com/issues/browse/ZF-1385;jsessionid=EF0F1B3DF6D09DC98918BBCCD06F0262?page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels:all-tabpanel&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a nice tutorial about flash messenger, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://shabadeehoob.com/2008/08/24/setting-up-flash-messages-in-zend-framework/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>