<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: recovery | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/recovery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-03T12:47:48+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency Server Recovery Support - PHP, MySQL, Fatal Error, Site Down, Table Crashed + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/management/emergency-recovery-php-mysql-fatal-error-site-down-table-crashed-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-11-26T11:55:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/management/emergency-recovery-php-mysql-fatal-error-site-down-table-crashed-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If your site has suddenly gone down and you are tearing your hair out because the people you usually call for server support aren&rsquo;t answering the phone then fear not &ndash; we can help you out.</p>

<p>Along with our core business of building, customising and extending e-commerce web sites, we are also pretty handy at fixing problems when the pressure is on and you need results quickly.</p>

<p>If you are running a PHP/MySQL based web site on a Linux server and its stopped working with Fatal Error or even an empty white screen then get in touch with us.</p>

<p>We appreciate that your e-commerce web site is your business and when the site is down your doors are closed and you are losing money. We can help you to get your doors back open again as quickly as possible.</p>

<p>Get in touch with us on <b>0844 357 020</b>1 and drop us a <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk">contact form</a></p>

<p>We will support you in your server emergency.</p>

<h3>Errors that you might encounter include:</h3>


<p>Fatal Error</p>

<p>Warning</p>

<p>MySQL Error</p>

<p>Headers Already Sent</p>

<p>There has been an error processing your request</p>

<p>Error log record number</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
