<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: conversion rates | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/conversion-rates/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-28T13:35:12+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is User Experience & Why Bother?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/what-is-user-experience-why-bother.html"/>
    <updated>2013-09-02T07:50:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web%20design/what-is-user-experience-why-bother</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are running an E-Commerce store then you&rsquo;ve probably received various offers to improve the online shopping experience, optimize conversion rate and so on. All these offers are a part of a user experience. For example &ndash; if you receive an offer to improve your online store&rsquo;s shopping experience then most likely the service provider will go thorough the sales funnel, get some valuable input by <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/conversion-rate-optimization/using-advanced-analytics-to-improve-conversion-rates/" title="Using Advanced Analytics to Improve Conversion Rates" target="_blank">setting up and analysing your website metrics</a>, conduct a user survey by online forms and ask directly to the customers via email or even give them a private call.
All of the above is necessary to really understand how your users (customers) interact with your site, how:</p>

<ul>
    <li>valuable</li>

    <li>findable</li>

    <li>usable</li>

    <li>desirable</li>

    <li>accessible</li>

    <li>credible</li>
</ul>


<p>they found your site or offer to be. As for those who need a definition &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_experience" title="User Experience - Wikipedia" target="_blank">here&rsquo;s what wikipedia says about user experience</a> &ndash; <em>User experience (UX) involves a person&rsquo;s emotions about using a particular product, system or service. User experience highlights the experiential, affective, meaningful and valuable aspects of human-computer interaction and product ownership. Additionally, it includes a person’s perceptions of the practical aspects such as utility, ease of use and efficiency of the system. User experience is subjective in nature because it is about individual perception and thought with respect to the system. User experience is dynamic as it is constantly modified over time due to changing circumstances and new innovations.</em></p>

<h2>So, what elements the user experience should contain?</h2>


<p><img src="/assets/UserExperience.png"></p>

<h3>Valuable</h3>


<p>The solution must deliver measurable value for site owners or interested group. It can be conversions, leads, subscriptions, etc.</p>

<h3>Findable</h3>


<p>Make it easy to find what your target audience is looking for, not only by optimizing search engines but focusing on internal navigation</p>

<h3>Usable</h3>


<p>Ease of use is extremely important; it must be intuitive and fluid. You need to create a funnel that leads your audience to your goal effectively</p>

<h3>Desirable</h3>


<p>Your target audience must have a strong desire to use your solution whether it’s for content, experience or emotions</p>

<h3>Accessible</h3>


<p>The solution must be easily accessible for your target audience – whether it’s technological requirements or people with disabilities</p>

<h3>Credible</h3>


<p>Your solution must be credible by all means. It has to build trust in your particular target audience by including important credibility factors</p>

<h2>What’s In It For You?</h2>


<p>The benefits are pretty obvious. In this stage we help you to identify your market and learn about your target audience behavior and needs as much as possible. These real world insights are extremely valuable and perform a key role in a project life-cycle. In short – careful planning allows you to focus on most beneficial features first and drive more revenue with minimum effort.</p>

<h2>Why Plan?</h2>


<p>When embarking on a project to launch or relaunch an e-commerce web site it can seem like a daunting and overwhelming prospect. The danger is that without <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/web-project-management/guidelines-of-effective-web-project-workflow/" title="Guidelines of Effective Web Project Management" target="_blank">proper planning and project management</a>, the final outcome can be much less effective and efficient than if proper planning and preliminary research is used to define clear goals and then ensure these are met</p>

<h2>Why Work With Us?</h2>


<p>Edmonds Commerce is specifically focused on E-Commerce projects. We have experienced and professional team of certified Magento and Zend developers, User Experience, Design and Strategy experts. We tend to become partners and build a lasting business relationship which is proven by our long term clients of some of most promising UK’s e-commerce stores and businesses all over the Europe.</p>

<h2>What’s Next?</h2>


<p>We are happy to hear more about your upcoming or existing e-commerce project. Please get in touch with us and explain your vision, goals, requirements and deadlines. Discover how we can help you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Advanced Analytics to Improve Conversion Rates]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Conversion%20Rate%20Optimization/using-advanced-analytics-to-improve-conversion-rates.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T15:00:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Conversion%20Rate%20Optimization/using-advanced-analytics-to-improve-conversion-rates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/conversion_rates_cover.png"></p>

<p>Every e-commerce web site owner would like to improve sales and one clear strategy to do this is to focus on increasing the conversion rate by effective use of website analytics leading to tested content changes that improve conversion.</p>

<h3>Why you Need to Start Doing this Today</h3>


<p>Let’s put it simple &ndash; without a proper use of analytics you are driving blind. You know that there is something happening but you really don’t know why, nor you can identify the bottleneck. We all know the saying &ndash; “A chain is only as strong as its weakest link” At that weakest spot you are losing most of your customers. If you can reduce the leak &ndash; more customers will make a purchase and your bottom line will be increased.</p>

<p>Check against these questions to make sure you do enough to catch and improve the bottlenecks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Have you already set up analytics for your e-commerce web site? </li>
<li>If you have - are you set up to get all of the essential metrics? </li>
<li>Do you act on the data provided? </li>
<li>Are your conversion rates increasing?</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/assets/conversion_strategy.png"></p>

<h3>The Strategy in a Nutshell</h3>


<p>Analytics enable you to track every important aspect of your conversion funnel and any additional funnels that generates or somehow supports the main conversion. By proper use of analytics you can track even the smallest action in great detail, it helps to understand the actual user behaviour and make improvements. Most commonly the process is to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Set up the analytics and determine the most important actions and funnels to track</li>
<li>Let the tracking run for enough time to get a decent amount of data (from one week to a month and more)</li>
<li>Learn from collected data and look for the bottleneck which if were fixed would bring the largest benefit (conversion rate improvement) </li>
<li>Create a strategy on how to fix the bottleneck and set up a split testing to see the actual difference</li>
<li>Go for next bottleneck and repeat</li>
</ul>


<p>Website optimization is never done, it is always possible to make improvements by repeating tests and looking for best solution possible. Solutions change as time goes, industry evlolves and people’s needs change.</p>

<h3>What is Conversion</h3>


<p>In internet marketing, conversion rate is ratio of visitors who convert casual content views or website visits into desired actions. See the definition on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conversion_rate" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>

<h3>Conversion Bottlenecks</h3>


<p>Conversion rate bottlenecks are the so called “bottlenecks” therefore they hurt your bottom line the most. You want you site to be intuitive and easy to use so your ecommerce site converts the most of the traffic into sales.</p>

<p>By setting up the analytics properly and learning from data you can see where are the most weakest spots and create a strategy on how to improve them.</p>

<p>Then start to test again and compare the results.</p>

<h3>Content Optimization by Experiment</h3>


<p>Once you have identified the bottlenecks you can start to experiment with different solutions to the problem. Every solution must be tested to make sure that it really reaches the goal effectively. That is why it is called experiment. You can not know for sure whether your new strategy will actually reach the goal more effectively and how much effectively.
Difference Between Improving Conversion and Increasing Traffic
The goals are the same &ndash; to increase the bottom line of your ecommerce business. However, the set of actions are completely different and they must come together to increase your income.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/conversion_rates.png"></p>

<p>By improving conversion rate your website will benefit more from the traffic it gets because more of the traffic will be converted. For example if you are getting:</p>

<ul>
<li>Traffic - 50000 visits a month</li>
<li>Conversions - 750 a month</li>
<li>Conversion rate - 1.5%</li>
</ul>


<p>Then obviously, in this oversimplified version of reality, you could either do the conversion rate optimization or increase the traffic, just flip the coin?</p>

<p>Not quite.</p>

<p>An increased traffic may not lead you to more sales as it would not persuade the customer to actually buy. Besides, you need the right target audience coming to your site which will more likely convert. However, if you do get to attract the right traffic it might double the conversion.</p>

<p>Then what is the difference?</p>

<p><strong>More traffic</strong> &ndash; your ecommerce site is more visible
<strong>More conversions</strong> &ndash; your ecommerce site is more usable</p>

<p>As you might notice then the second one is the one that makes the customer happy and builds long term relationships which results in return customer and again &ndash; results in repeated sale and increased bottom line.</p>

<p><strong>In short</strong> &ndash; conversion rate optimization is really vital to make your customer happy and to make more returning customers.</p>

<h3>Conversion and Usability</h3>


<p>Conversion rate and usability are going in hand-to-hand. The more usable your ecommerce site is, the more conversions you get.</p>

<h3>What is Analytics</h3>


<p>Business must be data-driven and that is exactly what analytics provide. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analytics" target="_blank">The simplest definition of analytics is “the science of analysis”</a>. It is the discovery and communication of meaningful patterns in the data.</p>

<h3>Google Analytics</h3>


<p><a href="http://www.google.co.uk/analytics/" target="_blank">Google Analytics</a> is a service offered by Google that generates detailed statistics about a website&rsquo;s traffic and traffic sources and measures conversions and sales. The product is aimed at marketers as opposed to webmasters and technologists from which the industry of web analytics originally grew. It is the most widely used website statistics service.</p>

<h3>Other Analytics Providers</h3>


<p><strong><a href="http://www.kissmetrics.com/why" target="_blank">Kiss metrics</a></strong>&ndash; lets you track the person not only overall data
<strong><a href="http://www.crazyegg.com/" target="_blank">Crazy Egg</a></strong> &ndash; provides you with heatmaps for eye tracking to understand onsite user behaviour.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
