<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 16:17:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Admin Login Not Working in Some Browsers &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-login-not-working-in-some-browsers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 16:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-login-not-working-in-some-browsers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are tearing your hair out trying to figure out why you are not able to log into the Magento admin on some browsers then this might be your solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solution will apply particularly if you are setting up Magento on a brand new server or VPS as you will see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is actually that the server time is wrong. The server time is used for generating cookies and the fact that the time is wrong means that cookies become invalidated immediately. Some browsers will deal with this in a less aggressive way than others and might actually let the cookie work, others will go for hard line security and will make the whole thing break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to check this is to SSH into the server and check the time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;date
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the time is wrong then you need to do the following to fix it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;yum install ntp
chkconfig ntpd on
ntpdate pool.ntp.org
/etc/init.d/ntpd start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above will install NTP, make it run on startup, will update the time and will set it running so the time should stay up to date from here on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check that has worked simply check the time again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;date
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then finally flush your Magento cache and sessions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;rm -rf var/cache/*
rm -rf var/sessions/*
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you should be good to go&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Auto Populate Form Fields - Form Fuzzer</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-auto-populate-form-fields-form-fuzzer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 10:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/chrome-auto-populate-form-fields-form-fuzzer.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you ever used Webmaster Tools in Firefox but have now switched to using Chrom(e|ium) instead then you probably miss the form filler - especially if you ever need to test checkouts or other form intensive web site user stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nice little extension that I just discovered takes care of this, &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/cbpplldpcdcfejdaldmnfhlodoadjhii&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chrome Form Fuzzer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can configure it for simple form filling or with a little creative configuration it could easily be used for security testing and more in depth testing to ensure that input is being sanitised and filtered properly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Profiler Improved - Aoe_Profiler by Fabrizio Branca</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Magento profiler is useful when you are trying to discover what potential bottlenecks are in place in a specific Magento implementation that are slowing down the performance of the site. Often when doing this kind of analysis you might find that a particular block or extension is responsible for more than 70% of the total page load time. At this point you would choose to either optimise, cache or disable the block altogether to remove this performance bottleneck and improve page speed significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever tried to use Magento&amp;rsquo;s built in profiler you will no doubt agree with Fabrizio&amp;rsquo;s comments that, when you have it working, the output is hard to read and not really very useful in terms of seeing what is actually going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To aid with this process and give us a nice colourful and friendly user interface to the Magento profiler, Fabrizio has built a Magento module that extends the default profiler and makes it a much more useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the extension from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fbrnc/Aoe_Profiler&#34; title=&#34;Magento Aoe Profiler on Git Hub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;git hub here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full blog story &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabrizio-branca.de/magento-profiler.html&#34; title=&#34;Fabrizio Branch blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like some help optimising the performance of your Magento store, feel free to get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today and we can assist in getting the very best performance from your Magento web site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Clock on Ubuntu - Its As Standard</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/world-clock-on-ubuntu-its-as-standard.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 08:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/world-clock-on-ubuntu-its-as-standard.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We are starting to get more and more international clients primarily from America and Australasia. It&amp;rsquo;s great to be getting a more global market, though keeping track of client&amp;rsquo;s local time is sometimes confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the thought occurs: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m using Linux, there&amp;rsquo;s bound to be an excellent app to help me deal with this&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out there is and its included with Ubuntu as standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desktop clock, normally displayed in the top right actually has functionality to allow you to add as many extra locations as you want, so with a single click you can check the current time in whatever locations you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set these up, simply click the clock which then drops down a calendar view. At the bottom of that view there is a Locations option. Click that to display a map and also an [Edit] button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit the [Edit] button and you can add whatever locations you wish. Once they are set up you can check the local time for any of your locations by simply clicking the clock in the top right again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome. Got to love Ubuntu and Linux :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento date() Wrong &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-date-wrong-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 10:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-date-wrong-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are finding that your calls to date() etc are displaying the wrong time then this is the solution for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magento sets the internal time reference to UTC which does not account for daylight saving time adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the correct date for your store, you need to get the store time, so the correct method is like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;echo date(&amp;#39;l, F j, Y, H:i:s&amp;#39;, Mage::app()-&amp;gt;getLocale()-&amp;gt;storeTimeStamp()); &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>