<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grass on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/grass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grass on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 16:53:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/grass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass Seed Store - Migration from OSCommerce</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/grass-seed-store-migration-from-oscommerce.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 16:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/grass-seed-store-migration-from-oscommerce.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grass Seed Store – Migration from OSCommerce with Custom Functionality&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grass Seeds Store wants to migrate away from OSCommerce to Magento in order to improve stock management. They also need to maintain DEFRA compliance and have custom reports generated to do so. The custom reporting was based on the sales of seeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Grass Seed Store&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grass Seed Store specialises in the sale of a many different types of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thegrassseedstore.co.uk/&#34;&gt;grass seed, fertiliser and live stock pasture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/grassseed-300x205.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is a great example of customising Magento to be compliant with an industry governing body and shows that Magento can be used in almost any for the sale of any type of product. The project is currently a work in progress and the Magento implementation is currently only a wire frame demonstrating the functionality that is ultimately required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>