<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>E Commerce on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/e-commerce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in E Commerce on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 13:48:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/e-commerce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylius E-Commerce based on Symfony</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/sylius-e-commerce-based-on-symfony.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 13:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/sylius-e-commerce-based-on-symfony.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As if there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new contender for the open source e-commerce crown, a platform called &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sylius.com/features&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sylius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;. The thing that makes this one especially interesting is that rather than being built from scratch it is based upon a very well established PHP framework called Symfony. Some would argue that Symfony is the &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; PHP framework alongside Zend Framework. In fact there are many frameworks however it would be fair to say that Symfony and Zend Framework are the most well established and up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basing an e-commerce platform upon an existing PHP framework has many advantages including transferrable skills, established best practice structure and also easier access to a wide range of functionality via library components and extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another e-commerce platform based upon a PHP framework. It is based upon Zend Framework - you might have heard of it - Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does look very much like Sylius is still quite a new offering and it can not boast the level of maturity and establishment that Magento has achieved. That said, things move quickly in this industry and who knows what will be top dog in the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are considering Sylius for your e-commerce website and would like to find a UK Sylius developer to work with then do get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup Balsamiq for Fast Mockup Process</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 11:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/how-to-setup-mybalsamiq-for-responsive-design-mockups.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here at Edmonds Commerce when we are working on Magento design projects we use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balsamiq.com/&#34; title=&#34;Balsamiq - Mockup tool&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MyBalsamiq&lt;/a&gt; on-line mockup tool which We&amp;rsquo;ve found as one of the greatest in terms of support provided and especially for - live linking, which allows you to create live mockups in order to deliver the overall feel of navigation and User Experience to client more effectively. It has awesome sharing function as well - really easy to work and communicate ideas with clients, especially important in e-commerce projects where we like to test different approaches and see which could generate highest conversion rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, nobody&amp;rsquo;s perfect as well as Balsamiq. They don&amp;rsquo;t have grid system integrated which makes mockup process messy as well as lacking some other essential forms and elements. The good news are that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to Upload existing grid templates and add them to your mockup, whether they are created by Balsamiq, other users or you! I was lucky enough to find well designed Twitter Bootstrap Grid Template mockup on Balsamiq on-line resource &lt;a href=&#34;https://mockupstogo.mybalsamiq.com/projects&#34; title=&#34;Balsamiq Mockups&#34;&gt;database&lt;/a&gt; so I could really save time and concentrate on more important tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After mockup is downloaded in .bmml format - it can be easily uploaded on the system here:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/Upload_mockup-600x426.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might be useful to create your own collection of most used elements and share with others! So Go ahead and create your own collection of most used elements to speed up your mock-up process and share with others. I will definitely create my own. See for updates from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento 2 Source Code Available on GitHub</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 07:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Magento version two is coming. For those of us who are eagerly awaiting the next major version of the most popular and powerful open source e-commerce platform, you can now see, track and download the code on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not had chance to have an in depth look as yet but we expect great things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/magento/magento2&#34;&gt;https://github.com/magento/magento2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>