<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: cli | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/cli/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-02T19:41:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GUI Editor Alike Terminal Editor]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/gui-editor-alike-terminal-editor.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-30T17:50:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/gui-editor-alike-terminal-editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Came across an interesting Github project today &ndash; a command line text editor that is designed to look and feel and largely behave like a GUI text editor such as Sublime.</p>

<p>Meet <a href="https://github.com/slap-editor/slap">Slap</a></p>

<p>Installation is trivial assuming you already have node installed:</p>

<p><code>
npm -g install slap
</code></p>

<p>Once its installed you can open any file as you would with any other cli text editor</p>

<p><code>
slap my-file.php
</code></p>

<p>Immediate impressions are quite positive. A familiar feeling file browser in the left column is coupled with a text editing pane on the right that responds well to mouse clicks and familiar key presses.
The text highlighting is very nice and things like brace matching are also included.</p>

<p>Unfortunately for me it seems that mouse usage often lead to garbage characters being inserted into the text which render it unusable for the moment though this could be an issue specific to my machine.</p>

<p>Definitely a project to keep an eye on though if you like trying new CLI text editors. That said I&rsquo;m writing this post in SPF13 Vim which I&rsquo;m pretty happy with :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running PHP Scripts on CLI and Faking a Web Request]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/running-php-scripts-on-cli-and-faking-a-web-request.html"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T17:31:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/running-php-scripts-on-cli-and-faking-a-web-request</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some times you build a PHP script that is designed to run from a web request and you want to run it on the command line.
The problem is that you have used the standard PHP super globals and you would rather not refactor the script loads.</p>

<p>Here is a nice quick solution:</p>

<p>``` php
if(isset($argc)){</p>

<pre><code>for ($i = 1; $i &lt; $argc; $i++) {
    $things = explode("=", $argv[$i]);
    if (false !== stripos($things[0], 'POST:')) {
         $post = str_replace('POST:', '', $things[0]);
         $_POST[$post] = $things[1];
    } else {
         $_GET[$things[0]] = $things[1];
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>echo &ldquo;\nGET:\n&rdquo;;
var_dump($<em>GET);
echo &ldquo;\nPOST:\n&rdquo;;
var_dump($</em>POST);</p>

<p><code>``
This will loop over the argc variable that is defined when running in CLI mode and will fake the</code>$<em>GET<code>and</code>$</em>POST` variables as required.</p>

<p>To run this with get and post variables you would do this:</p>

<p><code>
php -f script.php getvar1=test getvar2=foo POST:postvar1=bar
</code></p>

<p>And that&rsquo;s it. It is not particularly pretty but it can be pretty handy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
