<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: online | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/online/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-04T10:53:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Computer Science and Programming Online Courses]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/free-computer-science-and-programming-online-courses.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-07T12:49:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/free-computer-science-and-programming-online-courses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are looking to increase your knowledge in a variety of fields and are open to online training then you could be interested in this site:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.coursera.org/" target="_blank">www.coursera.org</a></p>

<p>There are loads of courses on there but of particular interest to us are the computer science ones. Not had a close look at them but they do look interesting and the fact they are free is of course a bonus!</p>

<p><a href="https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming" target="_blank"><a href="https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming">https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming</a></a> is the list of free computer programming courses</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Magento Training]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/online-magento-training.html"/>
    <updated>2010-05-12T09:33:17+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/online-magento-training</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<blockquote><b>UPDATE</b>:

This course is now live and we are actively taking bookings. There is some funding available for people in the Yorkshire area, though the amount of funding may change as part of Government cuts. 

It is delivered online in 2 mornings, a total of 8 hours training. The course content is the same as our face to face training course, its simply the online delivery that is different.

If you would like to book on please <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/?about=online-magento-training">get in touch</a>
</blockquote>


<p><b>original post</b>:</p>

<p>If you are looking for some Magento training but are a little too far away from Leeds to do our classroom based <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-uk/">Magento training course</a> then you may well be interested in this.</p>

<p>We are currently beta testing a new online training delivery system based upon Elluminate which is a professional online training delivery system &ndash; emulating as close as possible the classroom experience online.</p>

<p>There are no fixed details about this online magento training as yet, we will update this post as soon as we have more information. If you are interested though please do <a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/">get in touch</a> about our online magento training today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
