<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: optimisation | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/optimisation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-07T11:18:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Apache JMeter For Load Testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/load%20testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-27T13:01:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/load%20testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Load testing is something that you really need a decent solution for. A simple tool such as Apache Bench (ab) is overly simplistic for todays web applications.</p>

<p>After some research I decided to use Apache Jmeter as the tool of choice. It is written in Java so easy enough to run on any platform.
It features a GUI which is ideal for creating your tests, then a command line version which is what you should use to run your tests.</p>

<p>For my purposes I wanted to feed in a large list of URLs, for that I followed these instructions:
<a href="http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv">http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv</a></p>

<p>This allows you to create a csv file with your choice of URLs. It was actually quite hard to find a decent and succint guide to getting this set up but thankfully that page fitted my requirements.</p>

<p>Once I started to run the test I quickly realised that my system was grinding to a halt with out of memory errors. A bit more searching yielded this page which advises on how to properly run Jmeter including the fact that you really should run it on the command line for proper testing.
<a href="http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips">http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Block Caching Cache Key Helper Method - Generate Safe Unique Cache Keys]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-block-caching-cache-key-helper-method-generate-safe-unique-cache-keys.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T12:21:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-block-caching-cache-key-helper-method-generate-safe-unique-cache-keys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you do any work at all on Magento performance optimisation with a view to making pages load faster then you must have come across block caching. To understand block caching you need to first of all understand that a Magento page is actually made up of a lot of nested chunks called blocks.</p>

<p>Blocks can have their HTML generated dynamically every time though it is also possible to make Magento cache the block HTML output so that it loads a LOT faster, especially with heavy and slow blocks such as best sellers etc.</p>

<p>When setting up block caching, you need to specify a cache key. If your cache key is not unique enough then there is a risk that you will display the wrong cache for a particular scenario.</p>

<p>For this reason I created a block caching helper with this method that can generate a very unique cache key based on the current block usage.
/app/code/local/EdmondsCommerce/Helper/Data.php
```php</p>

<p>/**</p>

<pre><code> * Generate a nice unique block cache key
 *
 * @param Mage_Core_Block_Abstract $block
 * @return string
 */
public function ecCacheKey(Mage_Core_Block_Abstract $block){
    $class = get_class($block);
    $template = $block-&gt;getTemplateFile();
    $md5 = md5(var_export($block-&gt;getData(), true));
    $params = trim(implode(",", $block-&gt;getRequest()-&gt;getParams()), ',');
    $category=($block-&gt;getCurrentCategory())?$block-&gt;getCurrentCategory()-&gt;getName():'no-category';
    $store_id = Mage::app()-&gt;getStore()-&gt;getId();
    return 'edmondscommerce-'. $params . '-'. $category . '-' . $store_id . '-' . $class.'-'.$template.'-'.$md5;
}
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>You would use this in the following way:</p>

<p>In a block class, set up the following:
```php</p>

<pre><code>public function _construct(){
    parent::_construct();
    $this-&gt;addData(array(
        'cache_lifetime' =&gt; 999999999,
        'cache_tags' =&gt; array(Mage_Catalog_Model_Product::CACHE_TAG, Mage_Catalog_Model_Category::CACHE_TAG),
        'cache_key' =&gt; Mage::helper('blockcaching')-&gt;ecCacheKey($this)
    ));

}
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T17:36:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of our clients use <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.</p>

<p>The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.</p>

<p>The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.</p>

<p>The last release for PHP 5.2 was <a href="http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1" target="_blank">version 5.2.16 released back in 2010</a>. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.</p>

<p>You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php" target="_blank">this page</a>.</p>

<p>If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then <b><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today</a></b>.</p>

<p>Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> or <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/opencart">OpenCart</a>. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Profiler Improved - Aoe_Profiler by Fabrizio Branca]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T15:31:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-profiler-improved-aoe_profiler-by-fabrizio-branca</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Magento profiler is useful when you are trying to discover what potential bottlenecks are in place in a specific Magento implementation that are slowing down the performance of the site. Often when doing this kind of analysis you might find that a particular block or extension is responsible for more than 70% of the total page load time. At this point you would choose to either optimise, cache or disable the block altogether to remove this performance bottleneck and improve page speed significantly.</p>

<p>If you have ever tried to use Magento&rsquo;s built in profiler you will no doubt agree with Fabrizio&rsquo;s comments that, when you have it working, the output is hard to read and not really very useful in terms of seeing what is actually going on.</p>

<p>To aid with this process and give us a nice colourful and friendly user interface to the Magento profiler, Fabrizio has built a Magento module that extends the default profiler and makes it a much more useful tool.</p>

<p>You can download the extension from <a href="https://github.com/fbrnc/Aoe_Profiler" title="Magento Aoe Profiler on Git Hub" target="_blank">git hub here</a>.</p>

<p>Read the full blog story <a href="http://www.fabrizio-branca.de/magento-profiler.html" title="Fabrizio Branch blog" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you would like some help optimising the performance of your Magento store, feel free to get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today and we can assist in getting the very best performance from your Magento web site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How 10,000 Geeks break the UK's biggest distributors, RS and Farnell (Raspberry Pi)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T06:50:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, 6am this morning (Wed 29 2012), a bunch of geeks eagerly awaiting the Raspberry Pi have killed the websites of both RS Components and Farnell</p>

<p>Why, you ask? Because the servers were not prepared for the influx of visitors that such an announcement brings.  Raspberry Pi themselves (a UK Foundation, like a Charity) were well prepared and are presently serving up a static page.</p>

<p>So, if you&rsquo;re running an eCommerce site, like Magento or osCommerce, and are warned by one of your suppliers, or your manufacturing department that you&rsquo;re launching a new product, be prepared.  Raspberry Pi certainly were and provided their suppliers with the information that they would be getting a huge amount of traffic, unfortunately those suppliers didn&rsquo;t listen hard enough.</p>

<p>This is to all intents a DDoS attack, but not an intentional attack.  Well done for keeping everyone updated via twitter though @raspberrypi, we know it isn&rsquo;t your fault.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
