<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: mytop | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/mytop/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T17:30:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what you're waiting for? Mytop tells all]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/wondering-what-youre-waiting-for-mytop-tells-all.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-14T16:03:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/wondering-what-youre-waiting-for-mytop-tells-all</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mytop is a handy utility which shows what queries are currently being executed on your MySQL server &ndash; useful for those times when you&rsquo;re not quite sure if it&rsquo;s still on the job</p>

<p>Running mytop is easy, just run it from the command line and it&rsquo;ll give you a top-like list of any queries currently being executed on the server
You need to tell my top how it should connect to your database. You <em>can</em> specify everything as parameters on the command, such as
```bash</p>

<p>$ mytop -u=myuser -p=mypassword &mdash;db=mydatabase -P=3306</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>But chances are you&rsquo;re not changing your database server <em>that</em> often.</p>

<h3>Setting the default parameters for mytop</h3>


<p>If you want to save yourself the effort of repeatedly typing the same details over and over, just tell mytop what you want it to choose if you don&rsquo;t tell it any parameters</p>

<p>All you need to do is let mytop know how to connect to your MySQL database in the form of a config file called .mytop in your home folder, with the following contents (replace as necessary):</p>

<blockquote>
<code>
     user=myuser
         pass=
         host=my.host.name
         db=
         delay=5
         port=3306
         socket=
         batchmode=0
         header=1
         color=1
         idle=1
</code>
</blockquote>


<p>You can add as many or as few of these as you like for easy configuration, like specifying the db flag if you&rsquo;re primarily accessing only one database. I like to leave the password field blank, and use the &mdash;prompt flag to avoid any awkward leaks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
