<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stable on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/stable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stable on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 11:58:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/stable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento 1.4 Stable Released</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-4-stable-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 11:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-4-stable-released.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest and greatest version of Magneto has just been released (last Friday).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release includes some great new features like WYSIWYG editors on the admin side, performance improvements and loads more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what has been added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;disc&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented 3D Secure credit card validation (Visa and Mastercard)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Full reimplementation of PayPal modules, includes lot of new functionality and numerous bugfixes
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Full review of frontend themes, introduced design cross-package fallback and the base/default theme. Includes SEO and accessibility enhancements. Changes are oriented to dramatically reduce themes maintenance.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added ability to define arbitrary cache backends
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimized performance of sales reports, added new sales report types
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added image/media uploader/browser, that can browse entire media folder
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimized performance of search indexer
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Made order processing workflow more informative and severe
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reimplemented 404 and report pages, introduced 503 page, specifically for maintenance purposes
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved javascript files merging, added CSS files merging
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added Widgets functionality, added several widgets out of the box
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added Custom Variables functionality
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added lot of new System Configuration options
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved order placement reliability
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added WYSIWYG for CMS and Catalog
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimized cache initialization during startup
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimized export from grids in admin area
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improved tax and discount totals calculation
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Replaced admin notification flash popup into a simple HTML overlay
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implemented product and category URLs per store view
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added ability to configure entry point using virtualhost environment configuration, rather than creating another physical entry point
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Optimized simple product view without custom options
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>