<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ec2 on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/ec2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ec2 on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 16:14:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/ec2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Magento with Amazon EC2</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-with-amazon-ec2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 16:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/using-magento-with-amazon-ec2.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;What EC2 is and how it differs from standard hosting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from shared hosting, Virtual Private Servers and Dedicated Servers, another form is cloud hosting. EC2 is Amazon&amp;rsquo;s answer to this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EC2 allows you to run &amp;ldquo;instances&amp;rdquo; which are prebuilt images which from your perspective is just like a virtual machine. The difference being that it&amp;rsquo;s in no way fixed to a physical machine, or even datacentre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Using Magento with EC2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously there are prebuilt images for various platforms (Ubuntu, CentOS, Debian etc) and Magento can be installed on these as with any server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to avoid that Bitnami provides a very nice Magento EC2 instance which has Magento running out of the box, and it&amp;rsquo;s really the best way to get started with Magento on EC2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue we have previously hit is the machine reporting itself to be out of disk space, but actually the issue was down to running out of what are known as inodes. We&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-not-working-not-creating-report-files-either-solution/&#34; title=&#34;documented this previously&#34;&gt;documented this previously&lt;/a&gt;, but should be a very rare case&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#PHPNW12 Round UP</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpnw12-round-up.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/phpnw12-round-up.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All of the PHP developers from Edmonds Commerce made our annual pilgramage over the Pennines to Manchester this weekend to visit arguably one of the best PHP conferences around - PHP North West, PHPNW for short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a three track conference with a diverse range of expert PHP developers giving presentations on some really interesting topics. The team split up and chose their own route through the choice of talks meaning that between us all we got a real flavour of the entire conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They Keynote by Ade Oshineye was all to do with API development and DevX - developer experience as opposed to the more usual and in vogue UX - user experience. The point being that users are often getting a lot of thought put into their experiences but developers are often given sparsely documented and unwieldy APIs to work with. The metaphor of a door with an ambiguous push/pull requirement was really apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particular highlights for me included the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nodephp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ReactPHP&lt;/a&gt; talk by Igor Wiedler which was both entertaining and really informative. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeromq.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ØMQ (zero MQ)&lt;/a&gt; layer looks really interesting among other things. The guys that went to the Data structures talk by Patrick Allaert were really impressed with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take homes from the conference in terms of projects and technologies to keep an eye on include the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getcomposer.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Composer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silex.sensiolabs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Silex Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nodephp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;React PHP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeromq.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ØMQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/code/6752709412171743&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services Command Line Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Web Services Blog: AWS Elastic Beanstalk - Build PHP Apps Using Git-Based Deployment</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/hosting/amazon-web-services-blog-aws-elastic-beanstalk-build-php-apps-using-git-based-deployment.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 07:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/hosting/amazon-web-services-blog-aws-elastic-beanstalk-build-php-apps-using-git-based-deployment.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Easily deploy PHP applications to the Amazon Web Services infrastructure allowing you to take advantage of an easily scaled flexible cloud based system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore there is Git based deployment so your version control workflow can hook directly into deployment for speed and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does really look attractive. The Angry birds store recently launched on Magento using Varnish and Amazon Web Services and it runs very fast indeed. Perhaps the days of expensive dedicated hardware are really numbered. If its this easy to set something up that can perform as well as a complex server cluster at a fraction of the cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.typepad.com/aws/2012/03/aws-elastic-beanstalk-build-php-apps-using-git-based-deployment.html&#34;&gt;http://aws.typepad.com/aws/2012/03/aws-elastic-beanstalk-build-php-apps-using-git-based-deployment.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>