<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: mysql | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/mysql/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-03T19:48:06+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MySQL Substring not Returning Anything + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-substring-not-returning-anything-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-20T10:54:20+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-substring-not-returning-anything-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are puzzled why your simple usage of the MySQL SUBSTRING() function is not returning anything this could be your solution.</p>

<p>The substring function allows you to specify a string (eg a column), the start character and the length. If you are used to languages like PHP then you are probably used to this kind of function regarding 0 as the starting character. In fact this function regards 1 as the starting character. If you specify 0 then you simply won&rsquo;t get any results.</p>

<p>This does not work:
```</p>

<p>SELECT SUBSTRING(column, 0, 10) as tenchars</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This does work:
```</p>

<p>SELECT SUBSTRING(column, 1, 10) as tenchars</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ERROR 1062 (23000) at line [Line No]: Duplicate entry for key '[Key Name]']]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/error-1062-23000-at-line-line-no-duplicate-entry-for-key-key-name.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-02T14:09:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/error-1062-23000-at-line-line-no-duplicate-entry-for-key-key-name</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Importing a database dump from one location using mysqldump, and them importing it into a blank database I received this error:</p>

<p>ERROR 1062 (23000) at line [Line No]: Duplicate entry for key &lsquo;[Key Name]&rsquo;</p>

<p>The issue here is that a constraint is set up to prevent two rows containing the same value. Although key checks are disabled, it still can&rsquo;t add the rows. Sometimes as a useful technique to just get it running locally (obviously there&rsquo;s an issue here which does need resolving), simply change the &ldquo;INSERT INTO&rdquo; statement to &ldquo;INSERT IGNORE INTO&rdquo;, which will skip that entry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Implementation of Jewellery Site (White Label)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/magento-implementation-of-jewellery-site-white-label.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-20T20:19:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/magento-implementation-of-jewellery-site-white-label</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of our white label service we provided the development and design implementation requirements for a large London agency to deliver a high quality Magento site on budget and time.</p>

<p>The site required some customised functionality along with a full bespoke design implementation.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/screenshot-thumb1.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SQLSTATE[28000]: Invalid authorization specification: 1045 Access denied for user + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/sqlstate28000-invalid-authorization-specification-1045-access-denied-for-user-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-12T18:03:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/sqlstate28000-invalid-authorization-specification-1045-access-denied-for-user-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have recently been running some MySql scripts that wrote to a file.</p>

<p>These worked fine locally, but as soon as I deployed them I started to get the error above.</p>

<p>After much looking around I came across this solution.</p>

<p>When I was developing locally, I was connecting with a user that had global privileges. When I was running the code on the server I was connecting with a user that only had privileges for the database I was using.</p>

<p>The issue is that then FILE privilege is a Global setting, so the user did not have access to it, hence the access denied message.</p>

<p>Grant FILE privileges and you can connect as expected</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["Base table or view already exists: 1050 Table ‘*’ already exists" After Deleting Tables]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/base-table-or-view-already-exists-1050-table-already-exists-after-deleting-tables.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T16:27:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/base-table-or-view-already-exists-1050-table-already-exists-after-deleting-tables</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If for example you&rsquo;re removing an extension and want to clear out its information from the database, you&rsquo;ll need to establish the rows and tables it&rsquo;s inserted, as well as some standard Magento table entries.</p>

<p>So you&rsquo;ve removed everything, cleared your cache and now you go to the homepage to check everything is all good, and boom, PDOException:</p>

<p><code>
Base table or view already exists: 1050 Table ‘*’ already exists
</code></p>

<p>In my case it was <code>salesrule</code>, which made me question why it was trying to create the table afresh. The reason I got this is that I&rsquo;d erroneously removed salesrule_setup from core_resource, and therefore Magento was reinstalling the module. Reinstating the row, and clearing my cache solved the issue</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
