<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gmail | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/gmail/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-17T12:40:40+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting rid of the chain of quoted replies in Gmail]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/getting-rid-of-the-chain-of-quoted-replies-in-gmail.html"/>
    <updated>2015-03-02T19:02:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/getting-rid-of-the-chain-of-quoted-replies-in-gmail</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The problem with quoted replies</h2>

<p>One of Gmail&rsquo;s stronger features is its threaded email conversations, allowing you to see emails as a chain of the back-and-forth, instead of the classic Inbox and Sent folder situation.</p>

<p>Mail clients often include the email chain as part of the email itself, and for the most part these are marked up in such a way that Gmail can hide them with the small ellipses button.</p>

<p>Sometimes though this doesn&rsquo;t work, and you end up having to scroll past page after page of quoted replies, which can be a right pain.</p>

<p>In probably 75% of the cases these have some HTML wrapped around them, which we can use to hide them when needed.</p>

<h2>Using Stylish to hide them in your browser</h2>

<p>Because Gmail is a web-based client, you can use normal browser extensions to manipulate it. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stylish">Stylish</a> is a browser extension that allows you to set up CSS rules that are applied on the pages you&rsquo;re using.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a snippet of CSS that will hide the needless quoted replies, with the ability to hover over them if you really need to see them</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>// Make quoted replies a small block
.im, .gmail_extra {
  height:30px;
  width:100px;
  background:#EFEFEF;
  overflow:hidden;
  display:block;
}</p>

<p>// Allow these to be expanded when hovered
.im:hover,
.gmail_extra:hover
{
  height:auto;
  max-height:250px;
  width:auto;
  overflow:auto;
  background:#EFEFEF;
}</p>

<p>// Show a little notice that they can be expanded
.im:before, .gmail_extra:before {
  content:&ldquo;Snipped Quote, hover to expand&rdquo;;
  color:#666666;
}</p>

<p>// Don&rsquo;t hide nested quote blocks
.im .im,
.gmail_extra .gmail_extra,
.im .gmail_extra,
.gmail_extra .im</p>

<pre><code>  {
</code></pre>

<p>  height:auto;
  max-height:none;
  width:auto;
  overflow:auto;
  background:#EFEFEF;
}</p>

<p>.gmail_extra .im:before {
  content:&ldquo;&rdquo;;
}</p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>The result</h2>

<p>What was previously a big mess of nested quotes and signatures</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2015-03-02-GmailQuote1.png"></p>

<p>Becomes a small &ldquo;Hover to expand&rdquo; box</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2015-03-02-GmailQuote2.png"></p>

<p>Viewing it in the scrollable box</p>

<p><img src="/assets/2015-03-02-GmailQuote3.png"></p>

<p>These styles work at the date of publication, but obviously Google might change the classes used for these.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing Google Drive documents from Gmail when sending emails]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/sharing-google-drive-documents-from-gmail-when-sending-emails.html"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T17:17:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/sharing-google-drive-documents-from-gmail-when-sending-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was writing an email to a customer, and had created a Google Drive spreadsheet for us to collaborate on, I put a link to the document into the email, intending to share the document with the customer immediately after.</p>

<p>To my surprise when I hit Send a prompt came up asking me if I want to share the linked document with the email recipients. You can choose to have it publicly viewable/editable using the link, or even to add the email&rsquo;s recipients to the document&rsquo;s share list (which of course requires them to be using a Google account).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/gmail-drive-prompt.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
