<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: catalogue | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/catalogue/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-03T12:36:28+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce Easypopulate File Creator Class]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/ecommerce/product%20catalogue/oscommerce-easypopulate-file-creator-class.html"/>
    <updated>2008-09-10T14:30:04+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/ecommerce/product%20catalogue/oscommerce-easypopulate-file-creator-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>When doing spidering projects or other bulk catalogue management projects for osCommerce sites, I tend to finish by creating easypopulate format files so that the store owner can do any last minute edits and upload the products manually using the easypopulate system.</p>

<p>Creating easypopulate format files can be a bit of a chore, especially as every site seems to be slightly different with different columns etc.</p>

<p>For this reason, I have created a very easy to use easypopulate file creation class. You can read more about the class <a href="http://www.phpclasses.org/browse/package/4782.htm">here</a>.</p>

<p>I have numerous clients who are now enjoying much, <i>much</i> easier management of their product catalogues including fully automated spidering systems that grab all details from supplier web sites and format it correctly to be uploaded to their store.</p>

<p>If you want to discuss ways that Edmonds Commerce can save you time and money whilst boosting your business &ndash; get in touch today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
