<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: magento | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/magento/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-17T12:40:40+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Repeating Behat Scenarios when Testing Magento with SmartStep]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/behat/repeating-behat-scenarios-when-testing-magento-with-smartstep.html"/>
    <updated>2015-04-15T12:02:28+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/behat/repeating-behat-scenarios-when-testing-magento-with-smartstep</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When behat testing Magento I found myself repeating the same Homepage > Category > Product > Add-to-cart > Cart page scenario for a variety of tests &ndash; checking that a category page has products; checking that items are added to the cart; testing the checkout itself etc etc.</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t want to copy-paste the whole procedure because if I changed, say the <code>.product-list</code> class, I&rsquo;d have to update each of the Scenarios. Bit of a kick in the face to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_repeat_yourself">DRY</a>.</p>

<p>The standard Behat way is to create a method in the Context class which performs the add-to-cart procedure under the Step <code>Given I have added to cart</code> or similar, but this defeats the object of using Gherkin to write the tests.</p>

<p>Fortunately KnpLabs have soled this problem with <a href="https://github.com/KnpLabs/FriendlyContexts/blob/master/doc/feature-smartStep.md">SmartSteps</a>. This allows you to create a Scanerio that you want to be repeatable by tagging it as a <code>@smartStep</code>. Once it&rsquo;s tagged, you can easily embed that scenario into a new one by having a step <code>Given [scenario name]</code></p>

<h3>Adding SmartSteps to your behat tests</h3>

<ul>
<li>In <code>composer.json</code>, add a new dependency
<code>
"knplabs/friendly-contexts": "dev-master"
</code></li>
<li>In <code>behat.yml</code>
```
default:
  extensions:
      Knp\FriendlyContexts\Extension:
          smartTag: smartStep</li>
</ul>


<p>```
&ndash; Tag your scenario</p>

<p>```
  @smartStep
  Scenario: I arrive on the site and add a product to cart</p>

<pre><code>When I am on "/"
Then I follow "My category"
Then I follow "My product"
Then I press "Add to Cart"
And I should see "was added to your shopping cart"
</code></pre>

<p><code>
- And then use the Scenario in any other scenarios with
</code>
Given I arrive on the site and add a product to cart
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SUPEE-5344 - a New Patch for Magento Community 1.6, 1.7, 1.8 and 1.9; Enterprise 1.11, 1.12, 1.13 and 1.14]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/supee-5344-a-new-patch-for-magento-community-1-dot-6-1-dot-7-1-dot-8-and-1-dot-9-enterprise-1-dot-11-1-dot-12-1-dot-13-and-1-dot-14.html"/>
    <updated>2015-02-11T15:53:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/supee-5344-a-new-patch-for-magento-community-1-dot-6-1-dot-7-1-dot-8-and-1-dot-9-enterprise-1-dot-11-1-dot-12-1-dot-13-and-1-dot-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento has become aware of a vulnerability requiring patching as soon as possible. The vulnerability allows an attacker to send a specially crafted request to a Magento store and allow it to run Magento code as though it were on the live server. Magento aren&rsquo;t aware of this having been used in the wild, but now that the vulnerability is public, attackers may use it against existing stores.</p>

<p>This vulnerability affects all versions of Magento, and Magento have released patches for versions Community Edition 1.6 to 1.9, and Enterprise 1.11 to 1.14.</p>

<p>The fix is to apply some stricter IP address checks to requests.</p>

<h3>Patching your Magento store</h3>

<p>To get the patch:</p>

<p><em>Note: at time of writing, the Downloads of the CE edition seems to under heavy load and is currently presenting a white page instead of the shell file</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Community Edition</strong> users should go to the <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/download">Magento downloads page</a> and scroll to the &ldquo;Magento Community Edition Patches&rdquo; section. From there, select your version of Magento and click Download</li>
<li><strong>Enterprise Edition</strong> users should log into their Magento account Magento Support Portal</li>
</ul>


<p>You&rsquo;ll be presented with a shell file which will make the necessary changes to your store. Upload this patch to your server in the Magento root and run it against your store.</p>

<p>The patch changes core files, and it&rsquo;s always recommended to test changes on a development copy before the live site, especially if you have modifications to your core code. Also keep in mind that any upgrades pre-1.9.0.1 will remove these changes, and the patch will have to be re-run.</p>

<ol>
<li><code>cd /your/magento/root/</code> &ndash; Navigate to the root of Magento</li>
<li><code>./sh PATCH_SUPEE-5344_CE_1.8.0.0_v1.sh</code> &ndash; Run the patches</li>
<li><code>rm PATCH_SUPEE-5344_CE_1.8.0.0_v1.sh</code> &ndash; Delete the patch file, so that it can&rsquo;t be re-run by the public</li>
<li><code>rm -rf var/cache/*</code> &ndash; Clear Magento&rsquo;s cache</li>
</ol>


<p>Reload a page and the patch will have taken effect.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SUPEE-3941 - A new patch for Magento Community 1.6, 1.7, 1.8 and 1.9; Enterprise 1.11, 1.12, 1.13 and 1.14]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/supee-3941-a-new-patch-for-magento-community-1-dot-6-1-dot-7-1-dot-8-and-1-dot-9-enterprise-1-dot-11-1-dot-12-1-dot-13-and-1-dot-14.html"/>
    <updated>2015-02-11T10:54:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/supee-3941-a-new-patch-for-magento-community-1-dot-6-1-dot-7-1-dot-8-and-1-dot-9-enterprise-1-dot-11-1-dot-12-1-dot-13-and-1-dot-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post was published with the incorrect vulnerability code; <a href="/magento/supee-5344-a-new-patch-for-magento-community-1-dot-6-1-dot-7-1-dot-8-and-1-dot-9-enterprise-1-dot-11-1-dot-12-1-dot-13-and-1-dot-14.html">this article has been moved to this post</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intermittent PayPal IPN failure in Magento]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/intermittent-paypal-ipn-failure-in-magento.html"/>
    <updated>2014-10-15T09:53:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/intermittent-paypal-ipn-failure-in-magento</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On one or two store we had an issue with intermittent IPN failures. Some paypal orders would be stuck on the &lsquo;Pending&rsquo; status even if there was a sucessful paypal payment. In the exception logs there would be the following exception being thrown &lsquo;PayPal IPN postback failure. See paypal_unknown_ipn.log for details.&rsquo; on line 156 of app/code/core/Mage/Paypal/Model/Ipn.php.</p>

<h3>What the issue turned out to be</h3>

<p>The issue turned out to be curl adding in extra error. On occasions curl will send the following header &lsquo;Expect: 100&rsquo;. The idea behind that is that rather than curl just send the data. It will send a inital request just to check if the web server will accept the data. Curl will usually fall on this bahaviour if the request is above a certain size.</p>

<p>It turns out that the magento implementation assumes that the response will be consitant. But with the ocasional &lsquo;Expect&rsquo; header bing in the request this is not always the case.</p>

<p>In the _postBack method in the IPN class where it makes the curl post back is recived there is the following code near to the end of the method.
``` php</p>

<pre><code>$response = preg_split('/^\r?$/m', $response, 2);
$response = trim($response[1]);
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>This code assumes the line position of where the &lsquo;VERIFIED&rsquo; line would occur. To resolve the header issue the following code should be used instead.
``` php</p>

<pre><code>$response = preg_split('/^\r?$/m', $response);
$response = trim(end($response));
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>As the &lsquo;VERIFIED&rsquo; line will always be the last line in the response. Regardless of any extra headers being added. This should resolve the issue but of corse remeber to use the local method and copy the class to the local folder with the correct path before doing the modification.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento 1.9 &amp; 1.14 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-dot-9-and-1-dot-14-released.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T11:12:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-dot-9-and-1-dot-14-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento has released the latest version of both CE and EE.</p>

<p>The big changes that are included are as follows</p>

<p><strong>Responsive design included as default</strong></p>

<p>Both editions now come with a responsive theme. This introduces jQuery, SASS, and Compass into native Magento and should allow for easier customisation in the future.</p>

<p><strong>Bill Me Later</strong></p>

<p>The PayPal integration has been upgraded to include the <a href="https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/promotional-financing">Bill Me Later</a> financing option. This allows customer to pay for products over six months whilst the merchant gets paid straight away.</p>

<p><strong>Other security fix and performance fixes</strong></p>

<p>The full list of changes can be seen <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/knowledge-base/entry/new-features-ce19-ee114">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
