<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 12:33:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blog Is Dead, Long Live the Handbook</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/the-blog-is-dead-long-live-the-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 12:33:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/the-blog-is-dead-long-live-the-handbook/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We have run a blog at Edmonds Commerce for a long time. Historically it has been a repository of useful bits of information that we wrote up when we had the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, these days we hardly ever update the blog. The reason, simply enough, is that we have found a much better way of doing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter: the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/handbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Edmonds Commerce Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-handbook&#34;&gt;What is the Handbook?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The handbook is not a blog, instead its much more structured by categories and page level topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates are not sorted in chronological order at all, it is entirely by topic. This makes it much easier to find what you are looking for and also encourages more granular updates. You do not have to have something that is substantial enough to warrant an entire blog post, it can just be an extra sentence added to an existing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The handbook is built using a great package called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkdocs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mkdocs&lt;/a&gt; along with a nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://squidfunk.github.io/mkdocs-material/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;material design theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-did-it-come-from&#34;&gt;Where did it come from?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially the handbook was something internal and private, however we found that it started to become something that is probably useful for the wider world, so we decided to publish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, we had to redact some of the information because it has no public benefit and is really only for our internal use. However, I hope you agree, that there is a lot of information in there which is generally useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-did-we-do-it&#34;&gt;Why did we do it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our primary motivations for releasing the handbook publicly was so that developers with whom we are talking about joining our team could have a look through it and get a fuller understanding of what we are about and also get a head start on learning some of the many skills that we use day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we have a great page which purely lists useful links for developer who are learning Magento 1 and possibly studying to become a Magento Certified Developer. All of our developers gain this qualification. It is certainly not an easy one and so the more help we can provide the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-the-blog-really-dead&#34;&gt;Is the blog really dead?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry to say that I believe it is. We liked the blog, but then we liked the handbook better and so the blog got neglected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I think it is time to say goodbye, we had a good time, it isn&amp;rsquo;t you, it&amp;rsquo;s us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octopress auto building the site locally for one blog post</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/octoress/octopress-auto-building-the-site-locally-for-one-blog-post.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 17:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/octoress/octopress-auto-building-the-site-locally-for-one-blog-post.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Setting up a blog post using Octopress involves writing up your Markdown content, building the site, and previewing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be time-consuming when writing posts, having to run several commands repeatedly. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few lines you can put into a bash script and run once each time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ch&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;PATHTOLATEST&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;ls -t source/_posts &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; head -1&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$PATHTOLATEST&lt;/span&gt;
bundle &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;exec&lt;/span&gt; rake isolate&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$PATHTOLATEST&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
bundle &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;exec&lt;/span&gt; rake generate&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
bundle &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;exec&lt;/span&gt; rake preview&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PATHTOLATEST variable finds the latest post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;echo the variable for debugging purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rake isolate instructs octopress to build the site with only the latest blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rake generate builds the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rake preview initialises the web server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From then you can make changes to your post, and the site will be automatically regenerated. This uses a file watcher so it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to keep the terminal open to watch for it building, or having errors&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEO Blog Setup and Blog Article Writing Service</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/seo/seo-blog-setup-and-blog-article-writing-service.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 16:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/seo/seo-blog-setup-and-blog-article-writing-service.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We are big believers in the power of blogs and regular blog posts to boost the SEO performance of sites. Especially ecommerce style sites that can sometimes struggle to get the kind of SEO focus that is required to rank at the top of the search engine results pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason we have recently launched our new &lt;b&gt;SEO Blog Service&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of options and we will tailor a package to suit your specific requirements and budget starting from £120 per month for a minimum of 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will get high quality totally original blog stories written on the key themes, words and phrases that you want to promote. If you get us to install the blog for you, we will preconfigure it to get the maximum SEO benefit and will also link it up to a Twitter account so that you can push your message to the widest audience possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a blog, or you have one but you never find the time or ideas to write quality blog stories - we really do receommend you give us a call to discuss this exciting proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>