<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: integration | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/integration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-07T11:18:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release SagePay Form Orders via API]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/sagepay/release-sagepay-form-orders-via-api.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-19T17:54:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/sagepay/release-sagepay-form-orders-via-api</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you use SagePay Form integration then you might think that it is impossible to release orders created via this integration system via the API.</p>

<p>Historically this was true however thanks to the new admin and reporting API you can now grab all of the details you need to perform the kind of admin side integration previously only possible via Server and Direct integrations.</p>

<p>This does take a bit of work but if you like the fact that Form alleviates PCI compliance issues, allows your customers to use the nice easy to use Form interface and also gives you easy PayPal integration then this is a great solution.</p>

<p>Thanks goes out to SagePay&rsquo;s technical support who have proved really helpful in ironing out the kinks in getting this working.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paypoint Magento Modules Vanished into Thin Air!]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/paypoint-magento-modules-vanished-into-thin-air.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T16:23:49+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/paypoint-magento-modules-vanished-into-thin-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It appears that all the paypoint (formally secpay) modules have vanished from the magento connect site.</p>

<p>This is a pain for a lot of people who have chosen the gateway to service their payments, and leaves two options for most people :&ndash;</p>

<ul>
    <li>* Choose a different provider</li>
    <li>* Get a custom module written</li>
</ul>


<p>As Magento developers we&rsquo;re happy to quote for the latter option, but we expect a lot of people will go for the former.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CentOS + Sun Java + Amazon AMTU 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/amazon/centos-sun-java-amazon-amtu-2.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-14T17:33:31+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/amazon/centos-sun-java-amazon-amtu-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a follow up to our popular blog post describing the process of getting AMTU 1 set up on a Centos server, this post describes how to get the latest version 2 of AMTU running.</p>

<p>Things have moved on and thankfully it is a lot easier than it was.</p>

<p>Firstly get Sun Java installed. You will need to get the URL for downloading the RPM from here:
<a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jre7-downloads-1637588.html">http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jre7-downloads-1637588.html</a></p>

<p>Accept the agreement, download the correct RPM version and then pause it. Copy the download URL and paste it into this command:
```bash</p>

<p>cd /tmp
wget [paste-url]-here]
rpm &ndash; jre [hit tab to complete]</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Now check the correct java version is being used:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>java -version</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You should get something looking like:</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>[root@94 tmp]# java -version
java version &quot;1.7.0_05&quot;
Java&trade; SE Runtime Environment (build 1.7.0_05-b06)
Java HotSpot&trade; 64-Bit Server VM (build 23.1-b03, mixed mode)</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Now you can install AMTU</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>wget <a href="https://d28hcfptedr5ia.cloudfront.net/install/AMTU_unix.sh">https://d28hcfptedr5ia.cloudfront.net/install/AMTU_unix.sh</a>
chmod +x AMTU_unix.sh
./AMTU_unix.sh</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Keep hitting enter to get to the bottom of the terms and then agree, agree to all the other options. That is AMTU installed.</p>

<p>The final step is to configure this using the CLI configure utitlity.</p>

<p>You need to create an xml file for the AMTU configuration. You can see a sample file in /opt/amtu/xml/sample.xml.</p>

<p>Lets copy that file and then edit it accordingly.</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>cd /opt/amtu/xml
cp sample.xml configuration.xml
vim configuration.xml</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You do need to be signed up for MWS to get some of the keys etc that are required. If not already, go to this page and hit the sign up button.
<a href="https://developer.amazonservices.co.uk/index.html">https://developer.amazonservices.co.uk/index.html</a></p>

<p>Once you have updated the XML configuration you run this command to apply it:
```bash</p>

<p>/opt/amtu/Utilities/configure SETUP /opt/amtu/xml/configuration.xml</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you get some error messages at this point, edit the configuration and try again. Once you have the configuration set you can start the daemon.</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>/opt/AMTU/Utilities/amtu_daemon start</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento and eBay integration now Free]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-and-ebay-integration-now-free.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-11T12:46:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-and-ebay-integration-now-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the acquisition of Magento by eBay, one of the major extension developers, Ess, now has an agreement with eBay/Magento to provide their integration extension free.</p>

<p><a href="http://m2epro.ess-ua.com/">Here&rsquo;s their site</a> and <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/magento-connect/ebay-magento-integration-order-importing-and-stock-level-synchronization.html">here&rsquo;s the extension on Magento Connect</a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also worth knowing that the extension is avaiable on Magento Go, so if you&rsquo;re looking for hosted-only, management-free eCommerce with integration with eBay, that might be an option.  Remember that Magento Go is not extendable by third parties though as it is a locked-down solution.</p>

<p>Anyway, some of the features of the extension are :&ndash;</p>

<ul>
<li>Stock Level Synchronisation between eBay and Magento Stores</li>
<li>Create eBay listing templates which can create eBay listings direct from your Magento products</li>
<li>Multiple eBay accounts per store</li>
<li>Automatically leave feedback</li>
<li>eBay transaction and order import</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stage Gear - General Site Improvements]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/stage-gear-general-site-improvements.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T16:46:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/stage-gear-general-site-improvements</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<h2>Stage Gear – General Site Improvements</h2>


<p>Stage Gear needed a number of aspects of their OSCommerce site improving, including the look and feel, the addition of SEO URLs to improve site ranking, improving search on the site and adding basic Facebook integration.</p>

<h3>Stage Gear</h3>


<p>Stage Gear is a company that specialise in retailing <a href="http://www.sound-light-company.co.uk/">sound and lighting equipment</a> for use by clubs, pubs, bands and DJs.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/stagegear-300x224.png"></p>

<p>This project was terrific as it demonstrates that OSCommerce is still fully capable of running a modern web site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
