<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:57:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Security Update Testimonials</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/magento-security-update.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/magento-security-update.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you run a Magento store or are otherwise familiar with the world of Magento then you have no doubt seen the urgent security patch that live stores needed to apply quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We opted to offer the security patching service for free to our existing clients and then also to the rest of the world. The process of applying the patch is quick and painless thanks to a nice Bash script we put together so there was really no problem in offering this service. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-security-vulnerability-free-assistance/&#34;&gt;You can read all about that offer here&lt;/a&gt;. For anyone still not patched, the offer still stands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since that time we have had a few nice testimonials which we thought we would share:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chris from Mobile CAD Surveying&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Thank-you to Edmonds Commerce for highlighting a recent Magento security breach that we were unaware of. Edmonds let us know about this problem and offered to fix it for us at no cost.  We gave them our log in details and within an hour a patch had been installed and everything was working fine.
Thanks once again to Edmonds for their professional service and for attending to this matter very swiftly.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilecadsurveying.co.uk/&#34; title=&#34;Mobile CAD Surveying&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mobile CAD Surveying Ltd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Buckley Jewellery originally approached Edmonds Commerce to take our existing site and develop it onto a Magento platform.
Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp;amp; expand our ecommerce business.
The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design.
I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buckley-jewellery.com/&#34; title=&#34;Buckley Jewellery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buckley Jewellery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Clare from Libertinesque&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I can thoroughly recommend Joseph and his team for such a fantastic service and the security patch which was generously offered as a free service and efficiently applied with a very quick response time. Giving great personal attention every time, I have no hesitation in recommending the team for Magento upgrades and service.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.libertinesque.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Libertinesque&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Mayhew</title>
      <link>http://example.com/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 14:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magento Site Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Mayhew Ltd. required their Magento site to be upgraded from Enterprise 1.7 to the current release. They are looking to do this because the current site is having problems with some of the functionality which can only be correct by upgrading an extension and the extensions latest version is not compatibility with 1.7. 1.7 is also preventing them from improving the site and adding functionality. This mainly involved updating their site templates to function correctly the the new release as well as resolving issues related to old/new extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Kevin Mayhew&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Mayhew is a Christian religious product and music retailer, Christian church resource supplier and Christian book publisher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/kevinmayhew1-300x216.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project went really well with the pushing to live been successful. With the site now running the latest version of Magento the company can look forward toward to expanding the functionality of the site as well as resolving issues the old site was having.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinder Block Magento AppliedSB API Integration </title>
      <link>http://example.com/portfolio/cinderblock-magento-appliedsb-api-integration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 10:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/portfolio/cinderblock-magento-appliedsb-api-integration.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cinderblock.com/&#34;&gt;Cinder Block&lt;/a&gt; are a USA based company who retail merchandise for a wide catalog bands and artists in the music industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site is based upon a very large Magento Enterprise based multistore system with unique official store fronts for each band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cinder Block&amp;rsquo;s traditional merchandise is clothing, mainly T Shirts though they wanted to expand into selling downloadble music. Rather than use an inhouse system Cinder Block opted to use an external API and chose &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.appliedsb.com/&#34;&gt;Applied SB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project requirements were broadly to do the follwing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Populate the Product Page with API Data
&lt;/b&gt;
The Applied SB API provides image, title and price data for each product. For albums it also provides details of each individual track. Cinder Block needed to be able to get all of this data automatically from a single reference code or album_id. We created a Magento extension that handles all of the API communications to grab this data and also uses Magento block caching to keep the performance of the pages fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Allow Streaming of Sample Music from the Product Page&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the product page Cinder Block wanted visitors to be able to play from within the browser the sample tracks that the Applied SB API provides. Again all of this data is provided by the API and the Magento extension grabs and caches this data automatically. The previews are streamed directly from the Applied SB system and the browser player is based upon Sound Manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Allow Purchase of Downloadable Music through Standard Checkout Procedure&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For upgrade compatability and general ease of use we kept modifications to the checkout procedure to a bear minimum. The downloadable products are standard Magento products in every way. On successful checkout the Magento extension uses the event/observer system in Magento to trigger the extra functionality to register the purchase with the Applied SB and to retrieve the download links and utilise Applied SB&amp;rsquo;s download manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data is stored within a custom order attribute that is set up by the extension and is viewable from within the admin when looking at an order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Supply Download Links Upon Successful Checkout in Account Area and via Email&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After retrieving the download links, the extension sends a custom email with the download information. For this we hooked into Magento&amp;rsquo;s standard email templating system allowing Cinder Block to create a custom email template for each store front as they see fit. This works in the exact same way as all of the other email templates within Magento which means its very powerful and configurable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all the project was both challenging and rewarding. We encountered a few setbacks including core Magento bugs which were reported back to Magento and actioned, no doubt they will be fixed in forth coming Magento enterprise releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a quote from Mark at Cinder Block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#34;Despite being faced with many challenges, Joseph worked over time to successfully integrate music downloads into our Magento platform. And the follow up refining has been swift and on the mark. The result is incontestable: It just works. Period. Thanks, Joseph!&#34;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a screen shot of one of the product pages including the MP3 previews and also a related products carousel which we threw into the project for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/screenshot-thumb-150x150.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the live page &lt;a href=&#34;http://floggingmolly.cinderblock.com/flogging-molly-swagger-album-download.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Client Site Redesign Implemented - Looks Great</title>
      <link>http://example.com/portfolio/client-site-redesign-implemented-looks-great.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 10:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/portfolio/client-site-redesign-implemented-looks-great.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I have just finished a project for a client specialising in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ballicom.co.uk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Computers and Peripherals&lt;/a&gt; to take their osCommerce based site (though heavily customised) and apply a fresh new design to the existing site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the design work I have hooked up with local web designers &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creode.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creode&lt;/a&gt; who are actually based in the same office complex as Edmonds Commerce making colaboration a breeze. I have been impressed with the quality of their work and will definitely be hooking up with them for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce&amp;rsquo;s role in the project was to take the design ideas of Creode and apply them to the existing osCommerce system with the minimum of fuss. We have also added in a few extra nice features such as a popular searches system on sub category pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will shortly be upgrading the site with a streamlined fast checkout procedure as well which will be the icing on the cake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>