<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: theme | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/theme/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-05T12:25:08+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easily Test Mobile Version of your Site with Chrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/easily-test-mobile-version-of-your-site-with-chrome.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T15:33:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/easily-test-mobile-version-of-your-site-with-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have opted to have a customised mobile theme displayed for mobile users of your web site then it can be useful to be able to test this theme from the desktop. This is quite simple to do and there are plugins for most browsers. These days though Chrome users have this functionality built in, and quite nicely as well.</p>

<p>To access a mobile version of a site simply open Chrome and navigate to the site you would like to view in mobile version.</p>

<p>Then hit F12 to bring up the developer tools. Alternatively you can go to the right hand menu and select developer tools under the tools menu. This should bring up a screen looking similar to this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-162921-600x475.png"></p>

<p>In the bottom right hand corner of this screen you will see a little cog icon, please click that:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-162956.png"></p>

<p>This gives you the overrides menu where you can select the phone you want to emulate. You can also tick the device metrics box so that the displayable area corresponds to that of the phone giving you a good emultation of the phone experience.<img src="/assets/Screenshot-from-2013-06-03-163013-600x354.png"></p>

<p>Tick the box next to User Agent and choose a phone.</p>

<p>Once you have selected the phone you want to emulate under the &ldquo;user agent&rdquo; section and also optionally ticked the box next to &ldquo;Device metrics&rdquo; then you can reload the page (hit [ctrl] + [f5]) and the page will be reloaded and should show you the mobile version of your site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extending a Modules CSS within a Theme in PrestaShop]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/extending-a-modules-css-within-a-theme-in-prestashop.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T17:26:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/prestashop/extending-a-modules-css-within-a-theme-in-prestashop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop has a really nice structure for handling all the CSS that will appear in a site. It starts by splitting the CSS so that the CSS is split up per modules. There is a global CSS sheet but this should only be used for things that genuinely appear on all pages.</p>

<p>Extending the CSS of a module in PrestaShop is easy. All you need to do is create a CSS file that matches the naming convention of the module you are looking to extend.</p>

<p>For example if you wanted to change the CSS of the “Wishlist block” module (a.k.a. blockwishlist) in your theme, you would create the file themes/mytheme/css/modules/blockwishlist/blockwishlist.css. This file will then be included on every page that the CSS from the blockwishlist module appears on.</p>

<p>This system is good because it minimises the amount of CSS the browser has to load and also splits the concern of CSS into separate files making it much easier to manage. It also makes adding to a modules CSS with in a theme much easier.</p>

<p>One problem with this method of handling CSS is that by default a PrestaShop site may want the browser to download ten or more individual CSS files which is quite a overhead. Fortunately since PrestaShop 1.4 it has supported CCS merging (referred to as CCC in the admin) which causes the CSS for a page to be merged into a single file on the server to prevent the client having to download tens of CSS files.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Remove Hard Coded URLs from Theme]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-remove-hard-coded-urls-from-theme.html"/>
    <updated>2010-09-02T14:14:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-remove-hard-coded-urls-from-theme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are working on a theme, you may find that there are hard coded links dotted all over the place.</p>

<p>This can make testing a site offline (and thereby not on the same URL) a bit of a pain.</p>

<p>Here is a quick fix for you:</p>

<ol>
<li>Remove all hard coded links from the CMS section:</li>
</ol>


<p>```sql</p>

<p>update cms_block set content = replace(content, &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com/">http://www.domain.com/</a>&rsquo;, &lsquo;&rsquo;);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>```sql</p>

<p>update cms_page set content = replace(content, &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com/">http://www.domain.com/</a>&rsquo;, &lsquo;&rsquo;);</p>

<p>```</p>

<ol>
<li>Remove all hard coded links from the theme files.</li>
</ol>


<p>This is a command line one using grep and sed.</p>

<p>Firstly, cd into the root theme folder</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>cd app/design/frontent/default/hardtheme</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Now find files with hard coded links</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>grep -rl &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com">http://www.domain.com</a>&rsquo; ./</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Now to automatically remove all those,</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>grep -rl &lsquo;<a href="http://www.domain.com">http://www.domain.com</a>&rsquo; ./ | xargs sed -i &rsquo;s/<a href="http://domain.com//">http://domain.com//</a>&lt;?php echo Mage::getBaseUrl(Mage_Core_Model_Store::URL_TYPE_WEB);?>/'</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Design UK]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-design-uk.html"/>
    <updated>2010-08-31T14:36:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-design-uk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are looking for <strong>Magento Design</strong> and Magento theme or Magento template creation then you have come to the right place.</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce have traditionally been a Magento development specialist and have been working on custom Magento projects for a couple of years now. Now we have welcomed some design experts onto the team and so can now offer professional Magento ecommerce design services along with our development services. This means that we are on our way to becoming a full service agency for Magento site owners.</p>

<p>If you are looking to get a Magento site created and would like to enquire about our custom Magento design services then <b>get in touch today</b>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Tip - Rename Your Theme Directory]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-tip-rename-your-theme-directory.html"/>
    <updated>2009-02-19T16:40:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-tip-rename-your-theme-directory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>A common mistake made with Magento installations is that the the standard theme (eg default) is customised to suit the look of the site but is still kept in a folder called default. If you do this then whenever you want to upgrade your Magento store, the theme folder will be overwritten causing you all kinds of problems. I hope you had a backup!</p>

<p>All you need to do is make sure that if you are running a custom theme &ndash; even if it is simply a modified version of the default theme, make sure that it is set up a separate theme with it&rsquo;s own name. This way you will be able to upgrade Magento without too much theme problems.</p>

<p>We never recommend applying a Magento upgrade to a live site, instead set up a password protected dev subdomain which has a fully functional copy of your store. You can then test out upgrades on this version first, sort out any problems and then only update the live site once you are happy it will work fine.</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce specialise in helping ecommerce businesses set up or migrate to a Magento based solution &ndash; get in touch today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
