<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: 64bit | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/64bit/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-23T17:54:42+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu "No such file or directory" When it does exist + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-no-such-file-or-directory-when-it-does-exist-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2011-07-11T17:40:14+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-no-such-file-or-directory-when-it-does-exist-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are tearing your hair out trying to figure out why trying to run something is complaining that it doesn&rsquo;t exist when it clearly does, this is quite possibly your solution.</p>

<p>The problem is most likely that you are trying to run a 32bit package on a 64bit system.</p>

<p>The solution is easy enough, you need to set up your system to run 32bit packages.</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>apt-get install libc6-i386 lib32gcc1 lib32z1 lib32stdc++6 ia32-libs</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up a 64bit Linux PHP Development Enviroment]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/setting-up-a-64bit-linux-php-development-enviroment.html"/>
    <updated>2009-04-03T08:42:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/setting-up-a-64bit-linux-php-development-enviroment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>This is a guide to setting up a PHP web development environment on a 64 bit Linux. I have used this on Ubuntu Intrepid 64bit and also Open Suse 11.1 64bit.</p>

<p><b>Install XAMPP</b>
To get the ball rolling nice and quickly I have installed XAMPP for Linux which is available <a href="http://www.apachefriends.org/en/xampp-linux.html" rel="nofollow">here</a>. Then the first thing to do once XAMPP is running is to run the security wizard to set passwords etc.</p>

<p>It is possible to download all the LAMP components using your particular Linux package manager, however I like XAMPP because it is the same no matter which flavour of Linux you install it on, its set up to be a development environment rather than a production server and is generally nice and easy to use. It comes bundled with phpMyAdmin as well and requires no configuration to get up and running.</p>

<p><b>XAMPP Control Panel</b>
A nice easy way to start, stop and restart all or some of the LAMPP services is to set up the control panel. XAMPP comes bundled with a python control panel, however you will need to manually create a shortcut to load the control panel.</p>

<p>Create an application launcher with the command
<code>
gksudo python /opt/lampp/share/xampp-control-panel/xampp-control-panel.py
</code></p>

<p><b>Xdebug</b>
I want to get xdebug working so I have been following some instructions I found <a href="http://www.sanisoft.com/blog/2007/06/23/how-to-install-xdebug-php-extension-for-xampp-on-linux/">here</a></p>

<p>In order to get these instructions to work, I had to first install autoconf. I used Syntaptic Package Manager (System->Administration->Syntaptic Package Manager) and then searched for autoconf.</p>

<p>Then it turns out that as I am running 64bit, the xdebug.so I have just made won&rsquo;t work. Thankfully it turns out its possible to download a precompiled 32bit xdebug.so file from <a href="http://aspn.activestate.com/ASPN/Downloads/Komodo/RemoteDebugging" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p>

<p>You can download this file and whack it into your /opt/lampp/lib/php/extensions folder.  (Note for Open Suse I have installed <a href="http://www.kde-apps.org/content/show.php/Simple+Root+Actions+Menu?content=72762" rel="nofollow">this root menu extension</a> which helps in editing or moving things around as root without having to open the terminal.)</p>

<p>Next you need to add the following line to the bottom of your php.ini file (located in /opt/lampp/etc/php.ini):
```</p>

<p>zend_extension=/opt/lampp/lib/php/extensions/xdebug.so
xdebug.remote_enable=On
xdebug.remote_host=&ldquo;localhost&rdquo;
xdebug.remote_port=9000
xdebug.remote_handler=&ldquo;dbgp&rdquo;</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Then to check if its all working, go to <a href="http://localhost/xampp/phpinfo.php">http://localhost/xampp/phpinfo.php</a> and you should see a message like &ldquo;with Xdebug v2.1.0-dev, Copyright &copy; 2002-2008, by Derick Rethans&rdquo;.</p>

<p><b>Eclipse</b>
Found some excellent tutorials on setting up Eclipse <a href="http://www.64bitjungle.com/ubuntu/full-64-bit-or-32-bit-web-development-and-php-mysql-ide-with-eclipse-34-ganymede-and-pdt-2/" rel="nofollow">here</a>, including instructions on getting the JRE working properly and also linking it up to Xdebug. The tutorial isn&rsquo;t based on an XAMPP setup though but should be easy enough to apply to my situation.</p>

<p>Another tutorial that is useful is <a href="http://malibugarage.blogspot.com/2007/07/local-workstation-xamppeclipse.html" rel="nofollow">this one</a> and also <a href="http://2tbsp.com/node/40" rel="nofollow">this one</a></p>

<p>Once Eclipse is installed you will need to tweak the settings so that it can find the correct PHP executable and is set to use the xdebug extension for debugging.</p>

<p>Eclipse creates a folder called a workspace, which is where all the project files are stored. Its handy to make the workspace accessible to Apache and the easiest way to do this is to create a symbolic link from the htdocs folder in you lampp directory to the home/user/workspace folder.</p>

<h4>More...</h4>


<pre><code>        &lt;div style="font-size: .6em;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://linuxfilesystem.com/tech/flash-player-10-on-64bit-linux" rel="nofollow"&gt;Flash Player 10 on &lt;b&gt;64bit&lt;/b&gt; Linux | LinuxFileSystem.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tswarez.org/?p=1139" rel="nofollow"&gt;Dassault Systemes Catia V5R18 Sp8 &lt;b&gt;64Bit&lt;/b&gt; Rapidshare, Megaupload &lt;b&gt;...&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bulgariagazette.com/bulgaria-to-aid-the-financial-development-of-neighbouring-countries/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Bulgaria to aid the financial &lt;b&gt;development&lt;/b&gt; of neighbouring &lt;b&gt;...&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://developers.sugarcrm.com/wordpress/2009/04/02/php-testers-needed/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Sugar Developer Blog » Blog Archive » &lt;b&gt;PHP&lt;/b&gt; Testers needed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://techportal.ibuildings.com/2009/03/31/php-and-the-cloud/" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;b&gt;PHP&lt;/b&gt; and the Cloud - techPortal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
