<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: firebug | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/firebug/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-05T12:25:08+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox and Responsive Web Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/firefox-and-responsive-web-design.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-10T12:16:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/css/firefox-and-responsive-web-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Responsive web design is an excellent way to make a site work really well for a variety of different screen sizes without having to serve more than one design to users. Responsive web design does pose additional challenges however.</p>

<p>Some of the challenges for you, as the developer, are being able to implement, test and debug the design implementation. Fortunately built in to Firefox&rsquo;s arsenal of developer tools is an interface for exactly that!</p>

<p>Lets take a website that uses a responsive design:
<img src="/assets/large-no-tools-600x396.png">
Here is the &lsquo;mobile&rsquo; view:<img src="/assets/small-no-tools.png"></p>

<p>So every thing is normal you can use the developer tools and Firebug or whatever. If you then need to make changes to the smaller version and use Firebug you would have to pop out Firebug (which may or may not be to your preference) then resize the main window. This works ok but Firebug currently isn&rsquo;t great for working with responsive designs as it doesn&rsquo;t show you all the rules that might apply based on the screen size and other conditions. This is one area that the Firefox built in tools beat Firebug. The styles editor shows you all rules that could apply and their conditions.</p>

<p>To activate Firefox&rsquo;s responsive design view press Ctrl + Shift + M. You can open the inspector and stlyes by pressing Ctrl + Shift + I. You can also access the responsive design view by going to Tools > Web Developer. With responsive design view enabled you can still use Firebug without a problem, unless you enable the built in element inspector then you kind of lose loads of screen space.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/small-tools-600x447.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quickly testing HTML with Firebug]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/debugging/quickly-testing-html-with-firebug.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-05T12:13:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/debugging/quickly-testing-html-with-firebug</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>Ever need to quickly test some HTML that you copied from some where?</p>

<p>If you have Firebug installed, you can open a new tab, go the the HTML tab in Firebug, click edit and paste your HTML and Firefox will render it. This is faster than having to open a text editor, paste the contents and save the file, but JavaScript on load events won&rsquo;t fire.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Checkout "undefined" Pop Up + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-checkout-undefined-pop-up-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2010-09-07T16:39:15+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-checkout-undefined-pop-up-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are struggling to understand why you are getting a popup on the Magento checkout with the simple message &ldquo;undefined&rdquo; then here is what you need to do.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Use Fire Fox and install the extension Firebug</p></li>
<li><p>Switch Firebug on and go to the console tab</p></li>
<li><p>Hit the place order button and you will see the HTML response to the AJAX request (how did we cope with AJAX before Firebug!!)</p></li>
</ol>


<p>You should then see a meaningful error message telling you what is causing the problem and hopefully help you to fix it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zend Framework Easy SQL Info]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-easy-sql-info.html"/>
    <updated>2009-07-13T13:47:52+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/zend%20framework/zend-framework-easy-sql-info</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you develop using Zend Framework you will know that it is sometimes tricky to see exactly whats going on in terms of SQL queries. After trying a few different ideas including subclassing the database classes or other complex systems, the easiest I have found is this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Edit your app.ini config file and add a line:
```</li>
</ol>


<p>db_profiling_enabled = false</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Then in your development section in your ini file, set the same value to true</p>

<ol>
<li>Add the following lines to your bootstrap.php after the database adapter setup.</li>
</ol>


<p>```php</p>

<p>// DATABASE ADAPTER &ndash; Setup the database adapter
// Zend_Db implements a factory interface that allows developers to pass in an
// adapter name and some parameters that will create an appropriate database
// adapter object.  In this instance, we will be using the values found in the
// &ldquo;database&rdquo; section of the configuration obj.
$dbAdapter = Zend_Db::factory($configuration->database);
//$dbAdapter = new EC_Db_Mysqli($configuration->database->params);</p>

<p>if($configuration->db_profiling_enabled){</p>

<pre><code>// create a new profiler
$profiler = new Zend_Db_Profiler_Firebug('EdmondsCommerce DB Queries Debug');
// enable profiling (this is only recommended in development mode, disable this in production mode)
$profiler-&gt;setEnabled(true);
// add the profiler to the database object
$dbAdapter-&gt;setProfiler($profiler);
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Note you may need to move this chunk above the database adapter section:
```php</p>

<p>// CONFIGURATION &ndash; Setup the configuration object
// The Zend_Config_Ini component will parse the ini file, and resolve all of
// the values for the given section.  Here we will be using the section name
// that corresponds to the APP&rsquo;s Environment
$configuration = new Zend_Config_Ini(</p>

<pre><code>APPLICATION_PATH . '/config/app.ini', 
APPLICATION_ENVIRONMENT
</code></pre>

<p>);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>This is based on a modified quickstart layout for a project. If you have decided to use an alternative layout, you should be able to tell where the relevant code should be.</p>

<p>You will need to have the Firebug firefox extension to view this output. If you also install the FirePHP extension for firebug then there are even more cool things that you can do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
