<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Budget on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/budget/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Budget on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 10:38:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/budget/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Different Approach to Getting Designs Done</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/a-different-approach-to-getting-designs-done.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 10:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/a-different-approach-to-getting-designs-done.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are putting together a new web site and would like a logo and design creating, the traditional approach is to first choose a design agency and then get them to create a design for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However a new approach is to get the agencies to create the designs first and you choose your favourite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For logo designs, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://logotournament.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Logo Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For full site designs, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://99designs.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;99 Designs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both sites offer a similar idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the designs is often really quite good, though I think you have to accept that a lot of agencies will not be able to compete in this kind of market place so you are only really catering to designers who are freelancers and are able to do work with potentially no return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen mixed results with these kinds of sites, but they are definitely worth looking into especially if budgets are tight and you are prepared to take a bit of a risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>