<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: tax | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/tax/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T13:25:53+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play.com to Go Marketplace Only - Abandoning Retail Completely]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T15:14:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most online merchants who are into multichannel selling (that&rsquo;s all of you, right?) must have heard of Play.com.</p>

<p>Never quite up there with Amazon and Ebay it was often the one that merchants asked us to integrate with once the two big ones were taken care of. Play was originally a pure online retailer but decided a few years ago to jump on the marketplace bandwagon like market leaders Amazon.</p>

<p>Now it seems Play have been bought out by a Japanese company and thanks to a lucrative VAT loophole being closed (and rightly so) they have now decided to abandon retail sales completely and concentrate purely on their marketplace business.</p>

<p>You can read more about it here:
<a href="http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042"><a href="http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042">http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042</a></a></p>

<p>And it might be worth checking out their current clearance for particularly good offers as well from a punters point of view.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Catalog Prices Include Tax Not Working]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-catalog-prices-include-tax-not-working.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-10T16:47:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-catalog-prices-include-tax-not-working</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento will some times not treat catalogue prices as tax inclusive even if configured to do so. There can be a number of reasons for it but usually it&rsquo;s because the origin address is not configured correctly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
