<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: skype | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/skype/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-03T15:14:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Skype Working on Fedora 20]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Fedora/getting-skype-working-on-fedora-20.html"/>
    <updated>2014-01-17T14:45:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Fedora/getting-skype-working-on-fedora-20</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently needed to get Skype working on Fedora 20 and unfortunately the process wasn&rsquo;t completely smooth, there were a few hoops I had to jump through.</p>

<p>I am making a note of these here for my own future reference and to help out any one else hitting problems like these.</p>

<p>To install Skype on Fedora 20 64bit, the first thing you need to do is download the <a href="http://www.skype.com/en/download-skype/skype-for-linux/">Fedora 32bit RPM from Skype</a>.</p>

<p>To install this you should use Yum so that dependancies are handled properly:</p>

<p><code>
sudo yum install ~/Downloads/skype-4.2.0.11-fedora.i586.rpm
</code></p>

<p>However I hit issues around the libvpx package. I have Chromium installed however it packages an incompatible version of libvpx which was blocking the installation.
After a load of messing around the solution for me was so use Yum to remove that package, install the correct package and then install skype.
One issue was that removing the package also removed programs that had it as a dependancy so after installing the correct version of libvpx, I had to reinstall those programs as well.</p>

<p>Here is the process in commands:</p>

<p>Firstly remove the package and install the i686 version
<code>
yum remove libvpx.x86_64
yum install libvpx.i686
</code></p>

<p>Then install Skype
<code>
 yum install ~/Downloads/skype-4.2.0.11-fedora.i586.rpm
</code></p>

<p>Then reinstall the 64 bit version of libvpx
<code>
 yum install libvpx.x86_64
</code></p>

<p>Then reinstall the programs that were removed when I removed libvpx
<code>
 yum install firefox.x86_64 pidgin.x86_64 pidgin-libnotify.x86_64 php-gd.x86_64 shotwell.x86_64 gnome-shell-extension-pidgin.x86_64
</code></p>

<p>That got Skype installed however testing it the audio was terrible. There is one last tweak that fixed this for me:</p>

<p><code>
sudo gnome-open /usr/share/applications/skype.desktop
</code></p>

<p>Change the line that reads <strong>Exec=skype %U</strong> to the following:</p>

<p><strong>Exec=env PULSE_LATENCY_MSEC=30 skype %U</strong></p>

<p>Restart Skype and the audio issues should be resolved.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serious Skype Vulnerability Nov 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/serious-skype-vulnerability-nov-2012.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T12:54:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/security/serious-skype-vulnerability-nov-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is a current vulnerability with skype accounts where anyone who knows your email address can get access to your account, and even your private chat logs.</p>

<p>According to Kaspersky Labs (a leading computer security firm), the leader of the Russian Opposition has had his private chat logs leaked via this method.</p>

<p>This is a serious vulnerability and Microsoft (the current owners of skype) are looking into the issue.  At present there&rsquo;s no way to avoid the compromise, perhaps think about clearing your logs if you have anything private in there.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a good article <a title="The Register" href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2012/11/14/skype_disables_password_reset_bug/" target="_blank">here</a> that explains in more detail.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Voice Lands in the UK and elsewhere]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/internet%20news/google-voice-lands-in-the-uk-and-elsewhere.html"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T09:34:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/internet%20news/google-voice-lands-in-the-uk-and-elsewhere</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Looks like Google have finally rolled out Google Voice to the rest of the world.</p>

<p>A nice alternative to skype, the rates look fairly reasonable though not as cheap as Skype &ndash; in fact the only place it seems to beat skype is on calling the US.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
