<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sales on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/sales/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sales on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:14:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/sales/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Play.com to Go Marketplace Only - Abandoning Retail Completely</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most online merchants who are into multichannel selling (that&amp;rsquo;s all of you, right?) must have heard of Play.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never quite up there with Amazon and Ebay it was often the one that merchants asked us to integrate with once the two big ones were taken care of. Play was originally a pure online retailer but decided a few years ago to jump on the marketplace bandwagon like market leaders Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it seems Play have been bought out by a Japanese company and thanks to a lucrative VAT loophole being closed (and rightly so) they have now decided to abandon retail sales completely and concentrate purely on their marketplace business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about it here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042&#34;&gt;http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it might be worth checking out their current clearance for particularly good offers as well from a punters point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sales Reporting Zero for Second Store in Magento</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/sales-reporting-zero-for-second-store-in-magento.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 12:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/sales-reporting-zero-for-second-store-in-magento.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/base_rate.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
If you are running multi site Magento with different currencies and are finding that the sales reports on the stores that don&amp;rsquo;t use the Magento default currency all show zero this probably means the currency conversion rates have not been configured. Due to the way Magento orders work existing orders will not have there conversion rate updated. There is no way to do this from the admin, the only real option is to update the orders directly in the database.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>