<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: clear | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/clear/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-28T13:20:54+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Merged CSS Clear Not Working + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-merged-css-clear-not-working-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-18T18:42:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-merged-css-clear-not-working-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are having an issue with Magento and the optional Merge CSS Files (beta) turned on and it not updating with recent CSS changes, you may appreciate this.</p>

<p>Unlike other cached elements that are stored in var/cache, Magento stores the cached and minified CSS files in media/css</p>

<p>If you simply delete the contents of this folder, your CSS changes should kick in as Magento is forced to rebuild these files.</p>

<p>There is an option in cache management to flush CSS storage but for some reason this wasn&rsquo;t working for me. Could be a permissions issue or something else I am not sure, we simply needed to get this change implemented (emergency live site fix) so flushing this folder manually did the trick.</p>

<p>Hope it helps someone else looking for Magento merged CSS clear not working, Magento CSS cache, Magento CSS Files beta</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
