<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Repair on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/repair/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Repair on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 10:33:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/repair/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce Checkout Problems &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-checkout-problems-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 10:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-checkout-problems-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If your osCommerce checkout starts behaving badly and bits of info seem to go missing eg billing address then you should definitely try this fix before you tear your hair out completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most osCommerce installs store session information to a MySQL table called (suprisingly) sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes (I have only seen this twice on umpteen osCommerce sites) the sessions table will become corrupted. The irritating thing is that if this happens it seems that the site will not stop working completely with a useful error message, but instead will continue to work but will behave very strangely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your osCommerce site is behaving strangely then try this fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open phpMyAdmin and select your SQL database and then copy and paste the following into the SQL section and hit run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34; data-lang=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;x&#34;&gt;REPAIR TABLE `sessions`;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Database Repair Tool</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-database-repair-tool.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 08:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-database-repair-tool.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Varien have just released a new tool to help repair Magento databases. The system works by taking a reference database (a clean installation of the same Magento version your store is running) and comparing this to your live store DB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It then goes through and repairs your store DB, fixing things like missing foreign keys etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t personally seen a requirement for this as yet, but if they have gone to the effort of releasing a tool I imagine it is because there is a requirement for this kind of tool. Definitely something to bear in mind if you ever do need to repair an Existing Magento database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full wiki post here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/wiki/doc/db-repair-tool&#34;&gt;http://www.magentocommerce.com/wiki/doc/db-repair-tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>