<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: inode | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/inode/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-22T10:29:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running out of disk space but df shows you have lots of space left]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left.html"/>
    <updated>2015-05-07T10:32:04+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Had a strange occurency this morning with an server reporting it had no disk space when disk usage according to df was at 50%. After some head scratching I decided to read the man page for the df command and came across the -i flag. According the man page this lists inode information instead of block usage. After running it I got the following:</p>

<p><code>bash
Filesystem      Inodes   IUsed  IFree IUse% Mounted on
/dev/xvda1     2621440 2621440      0  100% /
udev            124879     398 124481    1% /dev
tmpfs           126892     288 126604    1% /run
none            126892       4 126888    1% /run/lock
none            126892       1 126891    1% /run/shm
none            126892       1 126891    1% /run/user
</code></p>

<p>So it turned out that the system had reached its max inodes so the next line of investigation was to find any excess of files in an directory. Which was sone by using:
<code>bash
for i in /var/*; do echo $i; find $i | wc -l; done
</code></p>

<p>This will list the total number of files in a given directory. You can change the path to work your way down the directory tree finding directories with lots of files. In the end we found excess of old logs which I was able to remove.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Not Working, Not Creating Report Files Either + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-not-working-not-creating-report-files-either-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T14:49:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-not-working-not-creating-report-files-either-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a Magento site that is consistently erroring out and giving you the report screen with the file name, but the file does not exist in the reports folder then this could be your solution.</p>

<p>The most likely culprit in this scenario is that the filesystem has run out of space. If this happens, Magento will die because it literally can&rsquo;t create any files and it needs to do this for caching, session etc.</p>

<p>You can easily check this by running this command:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>df -h</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you see any filesystems with 100% usage then you have your answer, you have run out of hard drive space and need to free some space up by deleting files.</p>

<p>On occasion though you might run this and see that you still have plenty of space. This can be puzzling at first though you need to bear in mind that Linux filesystems don&rsquo;t purely use space but also something called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inode" title="wikipedia explanation of inodes" target="_blank">inodes</a>.</p>

<p>An inode is like a file pointer, you need one for every file that is in the filesystem. Also there is a limit to the number of inodes in any file system. If something goes crazy and your system creates lots of small files then you might find that you run out of inodes before you run out of hard drive space.</p>

<p>To check if this is your issue run this command:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>df -i</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you see any lines with 100% then you have run out of inodes and you need to delete some files. There are numerous possible causes of this and tactics that can be used to clear them out. When dealing with Magento though there are a few usual suspects.</p>

<p>Magento is a real culprit for this behaviour as it uses file system based sessions by default. Session files are very small and can be very numerous.</p>

<p>The quick fix is just to completely remove the sessions directory:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>rm -rf /path/to/magento/var/session</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Magento will recreate it on the next request.</p>

<p>If you would like to try to clear out just older sessions then you can do something like this:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>find /path/to/magento/var/session -name &lsquo;sess_*&rsquo; -type f -mtime +7 -exec rm {} \;</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
