<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opacity on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/opacity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opacity on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 17:14:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/opacity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Netbeans Disable Transparent Undocked Windows</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/netbeans-disable-transparent-undocked-windows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 17:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/netbeans-disable-transparent-undocked-windows.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a dual monitor setup you might decide to undock some of your Netbeans windows, for example for running XDebug sessions or PHPUnit testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However you will find that by default, Netbeans sets the transparency of these windows to unreadable levels when they are not active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This really defeats the object and is quite irritating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a long time under the false impression that this was some errant compiz setting and trying to figure it out that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that this is a Netbeans &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; and you can disable it with a single untick of a box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools-&amp;gt;Options-&amp;gt;Miscellaneous-&amp;gt;Appearance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;untick the &amp;ldquo;Transparent floating windows&amp;rdquo; box&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy lots of usable desk space in Netbeans!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RGBA Cross Browser Support &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/rgba-cross-browser-support-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 07:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/rgba-cross-browser-support-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I recently came across rgba colours which are a very simple and logical way to produce a colour (rgb) with alpha transparency as well. This is ideal if for example you want to create a translucent white box to put some text in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS does have some (dodgy) opacity controls, but they set everything as transparent including any text or pictures contained within the element. By using rgba, we can set a translucent background colour and have opaque elements contained within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, to get it to work in IE requires some extra effort, however this hack mentioned  &lt;a href=&#34;http://css-tricks.com/rgba-browser-support/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and originally credited &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hedgerwow.com/360/dhtml/rgba/demo.php&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; seems to offer a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>