<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: gmail | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/gmail/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T19:16:14+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome AutoCorrect for Gmail (and Google Apps)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T13:54:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you use Gmail (also bundled with Google Apps) for your business then you probably write a lot of emails directly into the gmail interface. If you are like me you probably make teh the mistakes all teh time. (See what I did there!)</p>

<p>As the MD of Edmonds Commerce I probably write more emails than most people with everything from <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento">Magento</a> quotes, client communications, enquiries and maybe even the occasional personal email. At a guess I would say I write a good few thousand words per day. I should calculate that one day.</p>

<p>Well help is at hand with this wonderful chrome extension that will auto correct common typos as you type them in gmail. For me this is a real productivity booster as I type fast but badly and this really tidies up a lot of my common mistakes meaning less <em>backspace</em> and more <em>getting stuff done</em>.</p>

<p>You can grab the extension <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ezautocorrect-for-gmail/fholdolknchpdbajhpdenookmikblmda/related" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>I hope you find it useful. On another note, if you aren&rsquo;t currently using Google Apps (its free you know) and would like to look at transitioning your business to the system then get in touch with us and we would be happy to help you with it. I can not recommend the service enough to be honest, even if you go for the paid version the cost is negligible really. Smaller companies should be find with the free version though which you really can&rsquo;t argue with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Save space with the new gmail look!]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/save-space-with-the-new-gmail-look.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-10T18:15:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/save-space-with-the-new-gmail-look</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>The new gmail look certainly makes it look the same as many of Google&rsquo;s other services, but it&rsquo;s quite space in efficient by default. Fortunately Google thought of that and made it&rsquo;s space efficiency configurable! There is a button in the top right of gmail that allows you to change it.
<img src="/assets/gmail.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHP Swift Mailer Not Working with Google Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-swift-mailer-not-working-with-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-31T21:34:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-swift-mailer-not-working-with-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are struggling trying to get PHPMailer working with Google Apps then perhaps this is the solution for you.</p>

<p>I went to the PHPMailer site and found my way to a SourceForge download. After a lot of debugging and wrestling with this I just could not get it to work. In the end I looked at other projects that I knew were using PHPMailer for their mail and that were working with Google Apps or Gmail and found that their version was drastically more up to date than the one I downloaded from SourceForge.</p>

<p>In a nutshell &ndash; the version I had was never going to work.</p>

<p>A quick update later and I have PHPMailer working with Google Apps.</p>

<p>For reference the version <a href="https://github.com/KyleAMathews/phpmailer/blob/master/class.phpmailer.php">here</a> seems to be the up to date.</p>

<p>Here is some example code that IS working with Google Apps</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p><pre></p>

<pre><code>&lt;?php
$to = 'info@edmondscommerce.co.uk';
$message = 'testing swift mailer';

require("class.phpmailer.php");

$mail = new PHPMailer();

$mail-&gt;IsSMTP();
$mail-&gt;SMTPAuth = true;
$mail-&gt;SMTPSecure = 'tls';
$mail-&gt;Host = 'smtp.gmail.com';
$mail-&gt;Port = 587;

$mail-&gt;Username = 'your@email.com';
$mail-&gt;Password = 'yourpasswordwhatever';

$mail-&gt;From = $to;
$mail-&gt;FromName = 'test';
$mail-&gt;Subject = 'test';
$mail-&gt;WordWrap = 50; // set word wrap

$mail-&gt;Body = eregi_replace("[\]", '', $message);

$mail-&gt;IsHTML(true); // send as HTML
</code></pre>

<p>//To</p>

<pre><code>$mail-&gt;AddAddress($to);
$mail-&gt;SMTPDebug = true;

$mail-&gt;CharSet = 'us-ascii';
$mail-&gt;Encoding = $mail-&gt;Charset != 'us-ascii' ? '8bit' : '7bit';

if (!$mail-&gt;Send()) {
    echo "Message could not be sent. &lt;p&gt;";
    echo "Mailer Error: " . $mail-&gt;ErrorInfo;
    exit;
}
echo "Message has been sent";
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating to Google Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2010-06-10T07:48:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/business/migrating-to-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>We recently decided to give Google Apps a try, mainly due to the requirement for some decent webmail and it being a brilliant webmail system at the unbeatable price of free.</p>

<p>Here is my quick guide to migrating easily:</p>

<p>Migrating emails &ndash; sign up to the free trial of the premier edition and use the IMAP migration system. It is by far the slickest option and will faithfully and accurately import all of your emails across. Best, you can set it going and then shut down your local machine, its all handled server side, so no requirement to shunt emails up from your desktop or anything like that.</p>

<p>Nested Folders &ndash; if you do the above and have a lot of nested folders, you will notice a pretty ugly massive list of tags with forward slashes in. To get back your nested sub folder like functionality you need to go to settings, then labs and then enabled the nested tags extension. This will give you a sub folder like interface for your tags and tidy the whole thing up.</p>

<p>Turn off those adds at the top &ndash; If you notice adds being displayed at the top and would like to get rid, its easy &ndash; Gmail calls them web clips and you can turn them off in the settings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
