<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Waterproof Equipments on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/waterproof-equipments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Waterproof Equipments on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 14:28:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/waterproof-equipments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Swimmers Limited UK – Waterproof Audio Equipment</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/swimmers-limited-uk-%E2%80%93-waterproof-audio-equipments.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/swimmers-limited-uk-%E2%80%93-waterproof-audio-equipments.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Swimmers ltd specializes in offering the largest range of waterproof MP3 players and cases available in one store. They aim to be a trusted authority on selecting audio products and cases for use during water sports activities. They offer products such as Waterproof MP3 Players, Waterproof iPod Cases, Waterproof Headphones, Waterproof Phone Cases and Waterproof Radios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have worked from ground up for this project. The website is based on Magento. We received the design instructions as a word document. We then used a lot of imagination to try and come up with something that has a look and feel as the client would have wanted. Though it was a tough act, we managed to match expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client was also very keen to ensure his SEO work is still top of the range. We therefore had to do a lot of work behind the screen (code wise) to ensure that the website is as SEO friendly as it can possibly be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the work we have done is to rewrite the catalogue block to list products on the mouse over on categories on the top menu (please see the diagram below). This is practical for small stores and ensures your products are indexed on each page request on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://swimmer.please-script.me/waterproof-ipod.php&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/07/swimmers.png&#34; title=&#34;Swimmers category view&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>