<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: lightbox | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/lightbox/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T18:37:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost your Magento store's image display with MagicZoom]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/php/magento/jquery/boost-your-magento-stores-image-display-with-magiczoom.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T16:09:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/php/magento/jquery/boost-your-magento-stores-image-display-with-magiczoom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento&rsquo;s product images come with a workable, although somewhat unusual image zoom functionality. But many users want a lightbox which lets users click an image and see a large version. Of course, you can use just about any jQuery plugin in your templates &ndash; <a href="http://www.magictoolbox.com/magiczoom/" target="_blank">Magic Zoom</a> being one such perfect example.</p>

<p>But instead of manually installing and configuring the Javascript yourself, <a href="http://www.magictoolbox.com/magiczoom/modules/magento/" target="_blank">MagicZoom has its own Magento MagicZoom extension</a> which can be dropped straight in and integrates beautifully with Magento</p>

<p><img src="/assets/MagicZoomMagento1.png"></p>

<h2>Some highlights MagicZoom's Magento extension</h2>


<ul>
    <li>Automatically inserts the product title onto the zoomed box</li>
    <li>Automatically linking main image and thumbnails for navigation when zoomed</li>
    <li>Visible on pretty much any area of the site, not just the product view page</li>
    <li>Per-theme customisation</li>
    <li>An insane amount of user-configurable options without touching a line of code (see below)</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/assets/MagentoMagicZoomConfig.png"></p>

<h2>Installation</h2>


<p>MagicZoom&rsquo;s extension comes with its own installer, although for me it was perfectly sufficient to simply drop in the files</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Which Lightbox?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/which-lightbox.html"/>
    <updated>2009-12-14T14:57:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/which-lightbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are bewildered by the choice of lightbox style javascript plugins available, you might find this page useful:</p>

<p><a href="http://planetozh.com/projects/lightbox-clones/"><a href="http://planetozh.com/projects/lightbox-clones/">http://planetozh.com/projects/lightbox-clones/</a></a></p>

<p>Its a well organised matrix of lightbox clones so you can compare features and choose the right one for your specific requirements. Handy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
