<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vim on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/vim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vim on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 11:27:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/vim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP error checking in Vim with Syntastic</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/vim/php-error-checking-in-vim-with-syntastic.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 11:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/vim/php-error-checking-in-vim-with-syntastic.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are using Vim for any kind of PHP development work, then you may miss the sanity checking that is included in some IDEs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it possible to add this in using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scrooloose/syntastic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Syntastic&lt;/a&gt;
plug-in. Installation is quite simple and can be handled by any of the common plug-in managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the plug-in just calls external checkers, so you will need to have these setup and configured,
but you should have this done already&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Locking Up, Always When you are Ready to Save? Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vim-locking-up-always-when-you-are-ready-to-save-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 10:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vim-locking-up-always-when-you-are-ready-to-save-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are constantly frustated by Vim freezing up on you are editing a file on a server then this is quite possibly your problem, and your solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is that most text editors and IDEs have [ctrl]+[s] mapped to save. If you do a lot of file editing then you probably bash the [ctrl]+[s] combo all the time, without even thinking about it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now back to Vim. As it is running in the terminal then it can be frozen by using the [ctrl]+[s] combination. You probably weren&amp;rsquo;t aware of that feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring things back to life, just hit the [ctrl]+[q] combo. There are ways to permanently disable this which you can try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For full information on this, check out this great &lt;a href=&#34;http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/12107/how-to-unfreeze-after-accidentally-pressing-ctrl-s-in-a-terminal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;stack exchange page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash timeout and copying text in vim</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/bash/bash-timeout-and-copying-text-in-vim.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 12:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/bash/bash-timeout-and-copying-text-in-vim.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working with a server that had been configured differently from the way that I prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two biggest complaints that I had about it were that the timeout was set very low, meaning that the connection would break off every five minutes, and that vim had been set up so if you selected text using the mouse you could not copy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solutions to these two problems are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can tell the terminal not to timeout with the following command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;TMOUT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware that this will only work for the terminal that you are working with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue with vim is that the mouse was triggering visual mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get round this hold down shift when selecting text and everything will work as expected&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Save File You Didn&#39;t Sudo Edit - </title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vim-save-file-you-didnt-sudo-edit.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 05:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/vim-save-file-you-didnt-sudo-edit.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
How many times have you edited a file in Vim, made your changes and then realised you don&amp;rsquo;t have write permissions when it comes to save it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well if you do it again, this tip is for you. You CAN save the file using this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:w !sudo tee %
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lifesaver!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one direct from one of my personal favourite sites, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commandlinefu.com/commands/view/1204/save-a-file-you-edited-in-vim-without-the-needed-permissions&#34;&gt;Command Line Fu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>