<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/categories/job/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 16:15:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/categories/job/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Job Bradford</title>
      <link>http://example.com/job/php-job-bradford.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 16:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/job/php-job-bradford.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a PHP developer looking for a job in the Bradford area then please do get in touch with Edmonds Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a team of PHP developers who focus on e-commerce based on open source packages such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk&#34;&gt;Magento&lt;/a&gt;, osCommerce, Prestashop, OpenCart and others. We also do a fair bit of Wordpress, Drupal, Zend Framework etc as well. We even do bespoke PHP development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a skilled PHP developer and would like to join a team of enthusiastic developers in a friendly flexible environment with a focus on productivity, personal skills development and fun then get in touch with us today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs in Leeds, PHP and Admin/Sales</title>
      <link>http://example.com/job/jobs-in-leeds-php-and-adminsales.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 10:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/job/jobs-in-leeds-php-and-adminsales.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Edmonds Commerce are hiring at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;PHP Job Leeds&lt;/h2&gt;
We are always looking to grow our team of Leeds based professional PHP Developers. If you are at or around the Zend Certified Developer level and think you would pass the exam given a little time and preparation then please get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Administration Job Leeds&lt;/h2&gt;
At the moment we are also looking for someone to join the team to help with administration and general customer services requirements. There is the possibility for this role to grow to meet your personal skills and ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For either role, please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/contact-us/recruitment-contact-form/&#34;&gt;Job Application form&lt;/a&gt; to apply for a Job in Leeds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>