<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: drive | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/drive/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-24T10:23:39+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing Google Drive documents from Gmail when sending emails]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/sharing-google-drive-documents-from-gmail-when-sending-emails.html"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T17:17:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/sharing-google-drive-documents-from-gmail-when-sending-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was writing an email to a customer, and had created a Google Drive spreadsheet for us to collaborate on, I put a link to the document into the email, intending to share the document with the customer immediately after.</p>

<p>To my surprise when I hit Send a prompt came up asking me if I want to share the linked document with the email recipients. You can choose to have it publicly viewable/editable using the link, or even to add the email&rsquo;s recipients to the document&rsquo;s share list (which of course requires them to be using a Google account).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/gmail-drive-prompt.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrate to Google Apps - Google Apps Reseller]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T14:21:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/migrate-to-google-apps-google-apps-reseller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are big fans of Google Apps and have built a large portion of our business processes around the system. For this reason we have absolutely no problem recommending the service to our clients and have assisted numerous clients with a migration to the system.</p>

<p>The first benefit you will get is your emails migrated over and a much better email service. You have the option of using normal IMAP access so you can continue to use your preferred desktop application however we suspect that you will start to use the web interface as it is really quite powerful with some unique features that you can not access on a normal desktop client.</p>

<p>Along with this you have great support of mobile devices, especially if you opt for Android with powerful and free native apps meaning that you can have all the access to your emails that could possibly wish for.</p>

<p>Along with the really excellent email functionality you also have powerful online documents giving you the basic office application functionality along with really powerful collaboration features allowing multiple people to be working on the same document simultaneously from geographically separate locations. This can be great when putting together proposals, specifications etc.</p>

<p>Now called Google Drive, the documents system has grown from managing purely office documents into a fully featured online file store that can be used to store and share all kinds of files across your organisation and with third parties.</p>

<p>Finally the calendar functionality is great. If you have never used Google Calendar then I suspect the first things you will notice is the abilty to easily drag and drop appointments around when reorganising your schedule. The ability to quickly create appointments using natural language such as &ldquo;call steve at 11am&rdquo; is really nice. A full barrage of reminders can be set up if you wish including on screen, SMS and emails meaning you should never miss an appointment again.</p>

<p>All in all we think Google Apps is great and would love to help you move your organisation across to the system. If you would like to discuss this in more detail please do <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us"><b>get in touch today</b></a>.</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce are a Google Apps Reseller.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Not Working, Not Creating Report Files Either + Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-not-working-not-creating-report-files-either-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T14:49:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-not-working-not-creating-report-files-either-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a Magento site that is consistently erroring out and giving you the report screen with the file name, but the file does not exist in the reports folder then this could be your solution.</p>

<p>The most likely culprit in this scenario is that the filesystem has run out of space. If this happens, Magento will die because it literally can&rsquo;t create any files and it needs to do this for caching, session etc.</p>

<p>You can easily check this by running this command:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>df -h</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you see any filesystems with 100% usage then you have your answer, you have run out of hard drive space and need to free some space up by deleting files.</p>

<p>On occasion though you might run this and see that you still have plenty of space. This can be puzzling at first though you need to bear in mind that Linux filesystems don&rsquo;t purely use space but also something called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inode" title="wikipedia explanation of inodes" target="_blank">inodes</a>.</p>

<p>An inode is like a file pointer, you need one for every file that is in the filesystem. Also there is a limit to the number of inodes in any file system. If something goes crazy and your system creates lots of small files then you might find that you run out of inodes before you run out of hard drive space.</p>

<p>To check if this is your issue run this command:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>df -i</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you see any lines with 100% then you have run out of inodes and you need to delete some files. There are numerous possible causes of this and tactics that can be used to clear them out. When dealing with Magento though there are a few usual suspects.</p>

<p>Magento is a real culprit for this behaviour as it uses file system based sessions by default. Session files are very small and can be very numerous.</p>

<p>The quick fix is just to completely remove the sessions directory:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>rm -rf /path/to/magento/var/session</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Magento will recreate it on the next request.</p>

<p>If you would like to try to clear out just older sessions then you can do something like this:</p>

<p>```bash</p>

<p>find /path/to/magento/var/session -name &lsquo;sess_*&rsquo; -type f -mtime +7 -exec rm {} \;</p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Question: How to Create Bootable Linux USB Key/Drives Easily from Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/question-how-to-create-bootable-linux-usb-keydrives-easily-from-linux.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-13T21:49:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/question-how-to-create-bootable-linux-usb-keydrives-easily-from-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Answer to this quite clear and simple question is:</p>

<p>unetbootin</p>

<p>Not the easiest to find but definitely one of the easiest solutions.</p>

<p>If you search for USB bootable drive generators mostly you will find windows apps.</p>

<p>Not too useful if you are already on Linux and simply want to try the latest version or perhaps an alternative distro on something that is going to give more useful performance than the traditional live CD.</p>

<p><a href="http://unetbootin.sourceforge.net/">uNetbootin</a> is a nice solid cross platform USB bootable Linux generator that will even handle the download of ISOs for you if required.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Permanently and Automatically Mount HD in Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/permanently-and-automatically-mount-hd-in-ubuntu-linux.html"/>
    <updated>2011-05-22T21:19:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/permanently-and-automatically-mount-hd-in-ubuntu-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you have a secondary hard drive that you have to manually mount in Ubuntu/Linux everytime you boot up and you are not too comfortable with the syntax for fstab, this is a possible easy shortcut for you.</p>

<p>You can view the currently mounted partitions by looking at mtap</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>cat /etc/mtab</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you do this after you have mounted the drive, you can see the full mount command that has been used, eg</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>/dev/sdc1 /media/BigDrive ext4 rw,nosuid,nodev,uhelper=udisks 0 0</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You can copy that line and paste it into your fstab and from then on when you boot up the drive will be mounted automatically.</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>sudo gedit /etc/fstab</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>I have no idea what all that stuff means and to be honest I don&rsquo;t care I just want to use my hard drive.</p>

<p>ALWAYS back up your fstab before making changes!</p>

<p>Hope that helps ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
