<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: hosting | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/hosting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-12T14:02:06+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is DNS and how does it affect site owners?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/hosting/what-is-dns-and-how-does-it-affect-site-owners.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T15:34:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/hosting/what-is-dns-and-how-does-it-affect-site-owners</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>What DNS is</h2>


<p><strong>DNS (Domain Name System)</strong> is the system used to make sure that when users type in your web address into their browser, they end up on your website.</p>

<h2>How communication happens on the internet</h2>


<p>When using the web, every site has its own address. It might have extra bits on the start and end, but the core part will be &ldquo;yoursitename.com&rdquo;, or similar. This is your <strong>Domain Name</strong>.</p>

<p>Behind the scenes, servers have a unique number assigned to them, similar to how houses have phone numbers. This will look something like &ldquo;123.456.789.000&rdquo;. This is called an <strong>IP Address</strong>.</p>

<p>Like phone numbers, the problem with IP addresses is that they&rsquo;re hard to remember. It&rsquo;s not easy to tell other people a list of numbers and have them remember them when they get home. It&rsquo;s for this reason we have phone books. Fortunately the internet has its own built in way of looking up IP addresses by a name. This is where DNS comes in.</p>

<p>DNS is a way of looking up an IP address by a more memorable name. When you type in &ldquo;google.com&rdquo; it&rsquo;s actually being converted into an IP address without you realising.</p>

<h2>How Domain Names are converted into IP Addresses</h2>


<p>When you buy your domain from your registrar, you will also be provided an area where you can set up <strong>DNS Records, also called Zone Records</strong>. This is where you, or your development company, set up the conversion from the Domain Name to the IP address. When this is populated, people accessing your domain are able to end up on your server because of this translation.</p>

<p>In actual fact, this information is spread across the world so that every <strong>DNS Server</strong> in the world (a place where the translation happens) knows what your IP address is, exactly like sharing a phone book with the world.</p>

<p>This translation information is transmitted with a validity period, which is how often other DNS Servers should ask for updates. This is called a &ldquo;Time To Live&rdquo;, or TTL). This is generally set to a relatively high time, and is the reason you generally have a 24 hour wait period when you change where your site is hosted.</p>

<h2>Separating your Domain Registrar from your Name Server</h2>


<p>It&rsquo;s possible (and not unusual) to have the <strong>Domain Registrar</strong> (the company you bought the domain from) and the <strong>Name Server</strong> (the place where you update these DNS records) in completely different places. This is set up by telling your Registrar where your Name Servers are.</p>

<p>When this is changed, it means that the Registrar is no longer in control of the translation from Domain Name to IP Address</p>

<h2>The General Overview</h2>


<p>So when you access a website, here is what&rsquo;s actually happening behind the scenes</p>

<ul>
<li>You type in the web address into your browser</li>
<li>Your browser asks a DNS Server what the corresponding IP address is</li>
<li>The DNS server sends the IP address back to your computer</li>
<li>Your browser then knows which specific IP address to send subsequent messages to</li>
<li>The browser takes this IP adress and sends a message to the server it's assigned to for the web page</li>
<li>The server sends back the page to your computer, and it's displayed on your screen</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Drops Google Apps Free Tier]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/google-drops-google-apps-free-tier.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T14:19:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/email/google-drops-google-apps-free-tier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a move that will hurt a lot of small businesses and especially startups, Google have withdrawn their free Google Apps for Domains which has been slowly reducing in number of users from 50, to 10 to now 0 (almost).</p>

<p>They are keeping the existing accounts open so if you have Google Apps already, don&rsquo;t panic yet, your data is still there.</p>

<p>For one-man-band startups apparently there is the option of creating a single-user apps account still apparently, according to Greg D'Alesandre of Google.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T17:36:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of our clients use <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.</p>

<p>The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.</p>

<p>The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.</p>

<p>The last release for PHP 5.2 was <a href="http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1" target="_blank">version 5.2.16 released back in 2010</a>. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.</p>

<p>You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on <a href="http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php" target="_blank">this page</a>.</p>

<p>If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then <b><a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today</a></b>.</p>

<p>Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce">osCommerce</a> or <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/opencart">OpenCart</a>. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSH Access, what is it all about in Simple Words?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/server/ssh-access-what-is-it-all-about-in-simple-words.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-05T16:29:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/server/ssh-access-what-is-it-all-about-in-simple-words</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>What is an SSH access?</h3>


<p>SSH stands for Secure Socket Shell. SSH is a protocol, like HTTP, it gives us a way to gain a secure access to remote computers.</p>

<p>The principle is to connect two networked computers via a secure encrypted channel within an insecure network environment such as the Internet.</p>

<p>With SSH access we can easily move files around and run programs on your server. We can also transmit files to and from our own network onto your server, for example to take a copy of your site for local development or to push updated files onto your server.</p>

<p>SSH needs a server application installing on your server (most web servers will have this by default) and an SSH client on your local machine to allow you to connect to your server.</p>

<h3>Where do you get your SSH access from?</h3>


<p>If you need SSH access details you should ask your hosting company, they should be able to install it for you if it is not already in place. If you are on shared hosting then the chances are that you will not be able to get SSH access details, if you need SSH access then you should consider upgrading your hosting to something that will support it.</p>

<p>SSH access details will consist of at least:</p>

<p>domain or IP address:
```</p>

<p>domain.com</p>

<p><code>
</code></p>

<p>123.123.123.123</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>username:
```</p>

<p>mywebserverlogin</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>password:
```</p>

<p>ihy324579ySDWf</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>it may also include a port if SSH is not running on the standard port.
```</p>

<p>2020</p>

<p>```</p>

<h3>Why do we need the SSH access details?</h3>


<p>We will always ask our customers to provide us with SSH access details. This is for two main reasons:</p>

<h4>1. Power and Speed</h4>


<p>SSH access allows us to run commands directly on the server, compress files, run scripts etc. For example we will generally run some static analysis scripts for our <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento">Magento</a> customers using a bash script that we can run with SSH access. This gives us some instant feedback on the state of your Magento installation and allows us to spot any potential problems.</p>

<p>If we need to get a copy of your site files, using SSH we can prepare a compressed archive of your site files allowing us to download them much faster. Likewise we can easily get a reliable database dump, especially if you have a large database that might cause problems for browser based tools such as phpMyAdmin.</p>

<h4>2. Security</h4>


<p>SSH is a much more secure protocol than something like FTP. In SSH everything is encrypted. It has been built from the ground up to be a very secure way of networking and inter communicating between servers on an insecure network such as the web.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Live Images on Staging Without Absolute URLs (but a bit of JS)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/using-live-images-on-staging-without-absolute-urls-but-a-bit-of-js.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-27T11:05:49+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/javascript/using-live-images-on-staging-without-absolute-urls-but-a-bit-of-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a staging copy of your site anywhere then you might not bother copying over your entire catalogue of product images etc.</p>

<p>You might decide to drop in absolute URLs for those images so that they are pulled from live. However you really don&rsquo;t want absolute URLs in your code and you certainly don&rsquo;t want that to go live because it just adds unnecessary bloat.</p>

<p>A nice trick you can do here is make a change to your staging site as follows. Of course ensure this change doesn&rsquo;t go live, but it should be just one file so that&rsquo;s easy to handle.</p>

<p>(Note this assumes you already have jQuery available on your page)</p>

<p>```javascript</p>

<script type="text/javascript">
$().ready(function(){
    $('img').each(function(){
        var src = $(this).attr('src')+'';        
        if(-1 == src.indexOf('http')){
            var new_src = 'http://www.LIVEDOMAIN.co.uk/'+src;
            $(this).attr('src', new_src);
        }
    });
});    
</script>


<p>```</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t forget to change LIVEDOMAIN to be your real live domain</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
