<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/editor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 17:50:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GUI Editor Alike Terminal Editor</title>
      <link>http://example.com/linux/gui-editor-alike-terminal-editor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 17:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/linux/gui-editor-alike-terminal-editor.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Came across an interesting Github project today - a command line text editor that is designed to look and feel and largely behave like a GUI text editor such as Sublime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slap-editor/slap&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Slap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation is trivial assuming you already have node installed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm -g install slap
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once its installed you can open any file as you would with any other cli text editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;slap my-file.php
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediate impressions are quite positive. A familiar feeling file browser in the left column is coupled with a text editing pane on the right that responds well to mouse clicks and familiar key presses.
The text highlighting is very nice and things like brace matching are also included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for me it seems that mouse usage often lead to garbage characters being inserted into the text which render it unusable for the moment though this could be an issue specific to my machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely a project to keep an eye on though if you like trying new CLI text editors. That said I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post in SPF13 Vim which I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geany Text Editor Remove Hash Comments</title>
      <link>http://example.com/geany/geany-text-editor-remove-hash-comments.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 11:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/geany/geany-text-editor-remove-hash-comments.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently needed to quickly remove some commented lines from a .htaccess file using Geany (a really nice lightweight IDE or feature rich text editor depending on your point of view).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geany has some powerful regex replace functionality in there but I found that it was overly aggressive so removed lines that had more than one hash and were in fact title sections that needed to stay intact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working formula was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search for:
&lt;code&gt;
&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:-&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:-&#34;&gt;0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And replace with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;\1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course tick the regex box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://example.com/images/geany.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Prevent Focus Stealing</title>
      <link>http://example.com/ubuntu/ubuntu-prevent-focus-stealing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 15:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/ubuntu/ubuntu-prevent-focus-stealing.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself typing away whilst something else loads or another window pops open and all of a sudden your typing has gone into a different window then this solution is for you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open gconf-editor. Open a terminal and type gconf-editor and hit return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now navigate to /apps/compiz/general/screen0/options/focus_prevention_level key and set its value to 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might actually decide that focus stealing is sometimes useful in which case you can always change it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally found here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://askubuntu.com/a/55220&#34;&gt;http://askubuntu.com/a/55220&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>