<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Training on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Training on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 12:49:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Computer Science and Programming Online Courses</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/free-computer-science-and-programming-online-courses.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 12:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/free-computer-science-and-programming-online-courses.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to increase your knowledge in a variety of fields and are open to online training then you could be interested in this site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coursera.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.coursera.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are loads of courses on there but of particular interest to us are the computer science ones. Not had a close look at them but they do look interesting and the fact they are free is of course a bonus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/category/cs-programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the list of free computer programming courses&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Magento Training</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/online-magento-training.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 09:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/online-magento-training.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt;:

This course is now live and we are actively taking bookings. There is some funding available for people in the Yorkshire area, though the amount of funding may change as part of Government cuts. 

It is delivered online in 2 mornings, a total of 8 hours training. The course content is the same as our face to face training course, its simply the online delivery that is different.

If you would like to book on please &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/?about=online-magento-training&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;original post&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for some Magento training but are a little too far away from Leeds to do our classroom based &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-uk/&#34;&gt;Magento training course&lt;/a&gt; then you may well be interested in this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently beta testing a new online training delivery system based upon Elluminate which is a professional online training delivery system - emulating as close as possible the classroom experience online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no fixed details about this online magento training as yet, we will update this post as soon as we have more information. If you are interested though please do &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; about our online magento training today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Training Course Feedback</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-feedback.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 15:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-feedback.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We just ran our Magento training course last week and despite some technical issues at the start of the day I think it was a great success. By the end of the day the delegates all knew their Attribute Sets from their Attribute Groups, could set up layered navigation, create configurable products the fastest way possible without using spreadsheets and generally had a good grounding to go and make the most out of their Magento web shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in doing some Magento training, we have more course coming up all the time, just give us a call on &lt;strong&gt;0844 357 0201&lt;/strong&gt; or drop as a line via our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Teaching Zend PHP Courses</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/now-teaching-zend-php-courses.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 15:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/now-teaching-zend-php-courses.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished my first delivery of a Zend PHP course module. It was the databases section of the higher structures course. Everyone seemed to enjoy it and I think it went really well. Its great to be able to help newcomers to PHP to get a better understanding of the language and see the power and flexibility that it offers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Training Course Details</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-details.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 07:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-details.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As previously announced, we have started to run a Magento training course. The course is targeted at Magento site owners who are new to the system and are keen to get the most out of their Magento store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key advantages of Magento is it&amp;rsquo;s wealth of professional ecommerce features that all come bundled as standard. These really make it stand proud of the competition. However, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use those features then they are wasted. This course aims to rectify that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to book one of the limited number of places, please do so ASAP. Simply give us a call on &lt;strong&gt;0844 357 0201&lt;/strong&gt; or contact us via our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. There are multiple dates scheduled so get in touch to find out the latest information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Here are some details of the course:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a one day introductory course to the Magento Ecommerce system. Magento is an awesomely powerful cutting edge open source ecommerce package that is quickly gaining a large following due to its impressive array of powerful enterprise level features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will give you the background understanding and practical skills needed to get the best out of your Magento store. You will leave with a clearer understanding of some of the more complex principles in Magento and will learn how to leverage some of the core features of Magento to get the most out of your store.&lt;/p&gt;
                

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Recommended for:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This course is designed for business owners or staff who are or will be running a Magento based ecommerce business. It will enable your business to get the maximum return on your investment into Magento by ensuring you and your staff are using the system to it&amp;rsquo;s fullest capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You will learn how to:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Magento Principles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;MVC Code Architecture, EAV Database Structure, Module Based Customisation and Magento Connect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magento Product / Category Administration:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Attribute Sets, The Product Types (Simple, Configurable etc), Cross Sell, Up Sell, Related Products and  SEO Techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magento Order / Customer Administration:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Orders, Invoices, Shipments,Credit Memos and Customer Details and Passwords&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic Magento Configuration Options:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Payment Methods, Shipping Methods and General Configuation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Course outline:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
table{
margin: 5px;
background: #8E96CF;
}
td{
margin:2px;
background: white;
padding: 3px;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
                &lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;3&#34; width=&#34;454&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&#34;2&#34; width=&#34;142&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;19&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;123&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Magento Principles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A holistic overview of   the Magento system and its core principles, philosophy and background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;19&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;123&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magento Product /   Category Administration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up the   categories and products that make up your store and updating this catalogue.   In depth coverage of the extra features of the Magento products system. This   will be the largest element of the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;19&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;123&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magento Order /   Customer Administration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to manage orders,   customers, invoices, shipments and credits within the Magento adminstration   system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;td width=&#34;19&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;123&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic Magento   Configuration Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brief overview of how   the Magento configuration works and a look at some of the more commonly used   configuration options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Course dates:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/a&gt; for the latest dates - new dates being added all the time!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to book one of the limited number of places, please do so ASAP. Simply give us a call on &lt;strong&gt;0844 357 0201&lt;/strong&gt; or contact us via our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Training UK</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 15:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To find out about our Magento Training - please &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html&#34;&gt;Get in Touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are pleased to announce our new venture in offering professional training on the Magento open source ecommerce platform. We are firm believers in the Magento platform, but we realise that for many new or even established businesses running on Magento, the system can seem a bit daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many great features built into Magento as standard that it really does make sense to make sure you are utilising them all to their fullest potential. This is why we have established this training programme - to help ecommerce business owners and their staff learn how to use Magento to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To deliver the course, we have partnered up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ntileeds.co.uk/&#34;&gt;NTI&lt;/a&gt; who are based in Leeds City Centre. It has great accessibility from all parts of the country thanks to excellent road, rail and air connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we are still discussing the final details for the course and are definitely interested in hearing what you the public would like to see on that course. If you have any comments or would like to register your interest please get in touch about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training-uk.html&#34;&gt;Magento Training UK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>