<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: extract | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/extract/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-02T19:41:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Extract Files from Plesk Backups]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/plesk/how-to-extract-files-from-plesk-backups.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T17:25:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/plesk/how-to-extract-files-from-plesk-backups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you have a plesk backup file and you want to extract and open the files from it? No problem. This blog will show you how.</p>

<p>The file is a mime file. The &ldquo;mpack&rdquo; package will let you unpack it.</p>

<p>First we install the &ldquo;mpack&rdquo; package
<code>
sudo apt-get install mpack
</code></p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s imagine your file is called &ldquo;pleskDump.gz&rdquo;. If it doesn&rsquo;t have a &ldquo;.gz&rdquo; at the end it might not be bad to add it as some environments will complain if it&rsquo;s absent.</p>

<p>Next we unzip the file
<code>
gunzip pleskDump.gz
</code></p>

<p>Now let&rsquo;s un-mime the file
<code>
mkdir pleskDumpOutput
cd pleskDumpOutput
cat ../pleskDump | munpack
</code></p>

<p>Now we have a bunch of regular tar files, but be careful, if we just extract them, the root folders will not be recreated. In order to keep things together, it&rsquo;s best now to look at the output you have. Let&rsquo;s take a made up example:
<code>
example-domain.com.httpdocs
</code></p>

<p>Note that the format is essentially domain.rootfolder or in another way, the tar files have your domain name they are archiving, then a dot, then the name of the root folder they made up. We take that root folder and create it like this:
<code>
mkdir rootfolder
</code></p>

<p>Now let&rsquo;s apply that idea to our previoud example; &ldquo;example-domain.com&rdquo;
<code>
mkdir httpdocs
</code></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s time to untar into the folder you just created, let&rsquo;s assume you just created &ldquo;httpdocs&rdquo;
<code>
tar -xvf example-domain.com.httpdocs -C httpdocs
</code></p>

<p>There you go! You can now output any of the folders you wanted.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copying Text from PDF table is not formatted correctly + solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/copying-text-from-pdf-table-is-not-formatted-correctly-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-02T17:41:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/copying-text-from-pdf-table-is-not-formatted-correctly-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you need to extract the information from a PDF table sometimes when you copy and paste it into a text editor the formatting is incorrect making the information useless.</p>

<p>In cases like this, you can use pdfedit to extract the text in the correct formatting and then do what you need with it.</p>

<p>To use the program first make sure it&rsquo;s installed. If not install it like this</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install pdfedit
</code></p>

<p>then use it to open the PDF. Click through the the correct page and then click Page &ndash;> Extract Text From Page</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
