<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: linux | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-25T15:23:21+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Live USB Key Creation]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Fedora/fedora-live-usb-key-creation.html"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T17:38:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Fedora/fedora-live-usb-key-creation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have had continual problems getting most of my USB keys to work as liveusb drives.</p>

<p>This is pretty awkward however it looks like I have now found a solution that works. Instead of using the official Fedora live USB creator, we are going to use something called livecd-iso-to-disk</p>

<p>First of all install it:</p>

<p><code>bash
sudo yum -y install livecd-tools
</code></p>

<p>Then this is your command to create the liveusb. Note you need to set the sdX to whichever your USB key is using, and of course make sure the path to the iso file is correct</p>

<p><code>bash
sudo livecd-iso-to-disk --format --msdos --reset-mbr --overlay-size-mb 512 --home-size-mb 512 ~/Downloads/Fedora-Live-Desktop-x86_64-20-1.iso /dev/sdc
</code></p>

<p>And that&rsquo;s it</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prevent Ctrl+S Freezing Your Terminal]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/prevent-ctrl-plus-s-freezing-your-terminal.html"/>
    <updated>2014-06-11T10:30:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/prevent-ctrl-plus-s-freezing-your-terminal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As someone who types a lot of text everyday and am generally quite keen not to lose my work, I tend to hit the key combination [Ctrl]+[S] quite a lot.
In fact its almost become muscle memory that every sentence or two I will hit that combination.</p>

<p>When working on a terminal, this can have the unfortunate outcome that the terminal freezes up. For more time than I would like to admit, I thought that this was a Linux bug
And found myself frequently restarting terminal sessions that had locked up.</p>

<p>Then I discovered that you can unlock this when it freezes by hitting [Ctrl]+[Q]. However this is a bit of a pain.</p>

<p>I have now discovered a way of turning off this behaviour completely which is a real relief. Simply add the following to your .bashrc file:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>Prevent Ctrl+S Freezing Terminal</h1>

<p>stty -ixon
```</p>

<p>Credit goes to this Stackoverflow post:
<a href="http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/12107/how-to-unfreeze-after-accidentally-pressing-ctrl-s-in-a-terminal">http://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/12107/how-to-unfreeze-after-accidentally-pressing-ctrl-s-in-a-terminal</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Apache JMeter For Load Testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/load%20testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-27T13:01:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/load%20testing/using-apache-jmeter-for-load-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Load testing is something that you really need a decent solution for. A simple tool such as Apache Bench (ab) is overly simplistic for todays web applications.</p>

<p>After some research I decided to use Apache Jmeter as the tool of choice. It is written in Java so easy enough to run on any platform.
It features a GUI which is ideal for creating your tests, then a command line version which is what you should use to run your tests.</p>

<p>For my purposes I wanted to feed in a large list of URLs, for that I followed these instructions:
<a href="http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv">http://asciiville.com/musings/coder/how-to-feed-jmeter-from-csv</a></p>

<p>This allows you to create a csv file with your choice of URLs. It was actually quite hard to find a decent and succint guide to getting this set up but thankfully that page fitted my requirements.</p>

<p>Once I started to run the test I quickly realised that my system was grinding to a halt with out of memory errors. A bit more searching yielded this page which advises on how to properly run Jmeter including the fact that you really should run it on the command line for proper testing.
<a href="http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips">http://blazemeter.com/blog/jmeter-performance-and-tuning-tips</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoAccess - Nice CLI Access Log Parsing Tool (and how to install on CentOS)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/sysadmin/goaccess-nice-cli-access-log-parsing-tool-and-how-to-install-on-centos.html"/>
    <updated>2014-04-24T12:40:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/sysadmin/goaccess-nice-cli-access-log-parsing-tool-and-how-to-install-on-centos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Log files are probably the single most useful item on a web server when it comes to debugging. They are packed full of all the information you need to understand what is
happening on the server and detect any potential issues.</p>

<p>Reading log files by hand is basically imposssible for any meaningful overall monitoring. You can of course do some grepping and other bash tools to gain more insights but some times it&rsquo;s nice to just have a simple tool.</p>

<p>I am a big fan of tools like top, mytop, apachetop and ngxtop. GoAccess is a little bit different though, mainly it just seems a lot more fully featured.</p>

<p>Best thing to do is to try it. Here is how to install it on CentoOS</p>

<p>``` bash
yum install ncurses-devel glib2-devel geoip-devel
mkdir -p ~/goaccess
cd ~/goaccess
wget <a href="http://downloads.sourceforge.net/project/goaccess/0.7.1/goaccess-0.7.1.tar.gz">http://downloads.sourceforge.net/project/goaccess/0.7.1/goaccess-0.7.1.tar.gz</a>
tar -xzvf goaccess-0.7.1.tar.gz
cd goaccess-0.7.1/
./configure &mdash;enable-geoip &mdash;enable-utf8
make
make install</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>You can read more about GoAccess here:
<a href="http://goaccess.prosoftcorp.com/">http://goaccess.prosoftcorp.com/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bash Delete Everything But - Handy Function for your bashrc File]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/bash/bash-delete-everything-but-handy-function-for-your-bashrc-file.html"/>
    <updated>2014-04-11T11:23:16+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/bash/bash-delete-everything-but-handy-function-for-your-bashrc-file</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For me the use case was a cache directory that I wanted to clear out everything apart from one particular file that was expensive
to create and didn&rsquo;t need to be cleared for my purposes</p>

<p>I decided to add this to my ~/.bashrc file for ease of use in future.</p>

<p>Here is the function</p>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>Remove Everything But</h1>

<p>function rmbut(){</p>

<pre><code>local BUT="$@"
ls | grep -v *$BUT* | while read f; do rm -rf $f; done
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>To use the function, simply <code>cd</code> to the directory you want to clear out and then call <code>rmbut MyFileIWantToKeep</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
