<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ie on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/ie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ie on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 15:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/ie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of an Era: Internet Explorer Drops Below 50 Percent of Web Usage</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-design/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webmonkey.com/2011/11/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage/&#34;&gt;http://www.webmonkey.com/2011/11/the-end-of-an-era-internet-explorer-drops-below-50-percent-of-web-usage/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who had had to either do an extra 50% of work to get IE working, or had to pay someone else to do so. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you are thinking what we think. Yes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freely Available Windows Virtual Machines for Testing IE</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/freely-available-windows-virtual-machines-for-testing-ie.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 18:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/linux/freely-available-windows-virtual-machines-for-testing-ie.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you need to test your code against the (ahem) interesting interpretations of the various iterations of Internet Explorer then this is a great resource for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out Microsoft have thrown web devs a bone by offering free virtual machine images with the various IE/OS flavours for you to test on. You can download them &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/download/en/details.aspx?id=11575&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use VirtualBox and also a *nix based operating system such as Linux or OSX then you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xdissent/ievms&#34;&gt;this, frankly awesome, bash script&lt;/a&gt; to automatically download one or all of these machines and fully set them up in VirtualBox for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VirtualBox, if you are not aware, is a freely available Virtualisation platform allowing you to run other operating systems on your desktop. On todays powerful machines its perfectly easy to run Linux as your core operating system and then for either running windows only apps or for testing dodgy browsers, you can fire up one of these VMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind that they are not for keeps, you will need to reset them every 30 days due to the fact that they can not be activated. For our purposes though this is not really a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
Please note all of this has been copied and pasted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webupd8.org/2011/09/test-websites-in-internet-explorer-9-8.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Posted here for reference only, all original attribution and credit goes to webupd8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before proceeding, make sure you have the latest VirtualBox installed - you can find Ubuntu installation instructions HERE. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need &amp;ldquo;curl&amp;rdquo; (for both Linux and OSX) and &amp;ldquo;unrar&amp;rdquo; (Linux only). In Ubuntu, install them using the command below:
```&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install curl unrar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;

2. To download and run the CODE, use the following command in a terminal:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl -s &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&lt;/a&gt; | bash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;If you want to check out the bash source before running it, you can find it @ GitHub.

The above command will download Windows WHDs for IE7, IE8 and IE9. If you only need one Internet Explorer version, you can run:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl -s &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh&lt;/a&gt; | IEVMS_VERSIONS=&amp;ldquo;9&amp;rdquo; bash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;```
Where &amp;ldquo;9&amp;rdquo; is the IE version you want (you can also add two versions here, like &amp;ldquo;7 9&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the download should start and it will take a while so be patient.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Internet Explorer under Ubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-development/linux/ubuntu/web-design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 16:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/web-development/linux/ubuntu/web-design/running-internet-explorer-under-ubuntu-linux.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Ubuntu Linux is undoubtedly the most successful desktop version of linux available today. It has managed to tempt across many dedicated windows users with its easy installation procedure, comprehensive bundle of applications including open office and firefox, its greater security and reduced vulnerability to internet viruses and malware. And of course the fact that it is free to download and install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a web designer, it is nice to have a sleek desktop environment to code in whilst being able to run a full LAMP stack web server as the localhost - meaning that designing and developing web sites is a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are times when you simply need to check that a design is going to work with Internet Explorer. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Internet Explorer web browser is bundled with windows and is therefore the most popular web browser at the moment. However as a web designer it causes problems as it often behaves erratically or unexpectedly. For this reason a web designer always needs to make sure that they check their designs in Internet Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason that Ubuntu users may need to use Internet Explorer is to log into certain sites which are not compatible with anything other than Internet Explorer. This is a real pet hate as it is real sign of laziness on the part of the web designers not to ensure that their web sites are accessible by all web browsers. Unfortunately the sites that tend to be like this are the ones that you really need, such as online banking sites. Its probably something to do with sloppy handling of ssl secure and insecure content, but I am not sure on that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway - to save you having to maintain a windows installation and reboot everytime you need to check something in Internet Explorer - there is the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IEs 4 Linux package&lt;/a&gt;. This great package allows you to easily install Internet Explorer under Ubuntu (or any other version of Linux).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have WINE installed and working, and also have the cabextractor working. Both of these packages are available in the syntaptic package manager in Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://novicenotes.net/2006/08/04/ie_on_linux_wine/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.taragana.com/index.php/archive/how-to-run-microsoft-internet-explorer-7-6-55-51-in-linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://alternativenayk.wordpress.com/2006/11/27/internet-explorer-on-linux-help-for-xfld-ubuntu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.liewcf.com/blog/archives/2006/04/install-internet-explorer-6-on-linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>