<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rewrite on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/rewrite/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rewrite on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 11:05:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/rewrite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Mod Rewrite Escaped Slashes Problem &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/apache/apache-mod-rewrite-escaped-slashes-problem-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 11:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/apache/apache-mod-rewrite-escaped-slashes-problem-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of our Magento SEO service, the first thing we do is to make sure there are no issues with the crawlability and general health of the clients web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst working on the Google Webmaster Tools crawl errors for a client I noticed one specific and intruiging problem for which I couldn&amp;rsquo;t immediately see the reason, everything looked to be set up perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain URLs were getting 404 responses. The URL was being parsed by mod_rewrite but everything looked fine so why was apache giving a 404?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem turns out to be that the URLs contain escaped slashes (eg search/KTA-mb667k2%2F2g),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that Apache actually handles the escaped slash and helpfully converts it to a real slash. That then means that it is trying to look in a sub folder that does not exist and hence the 404.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are you don&amp;rsquo;t want escaped slashes to really be thought of as real directory separating slashes, especially if you are using mod_rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is a simple one liner to be added to your vhost.conf or httpd.conf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
AllowEncodedSlashes On

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force WWW Domain and Prevent Canonicalisation Issues</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/force-www-domain-and-prevent-canonicalisation-issues.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 11:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/force-www-domain-and-prevent-canonicalisation-issues.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A really easy problem to fix that we still see on some live sites is having the site accessible with and without the www (or whatever sub domain).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Magento sites this can cause issues with session IDs being appended to URLs that then get indexed by google and cause problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a snippet which you can add to your htaccess file to fix this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
RewriteBase / RewriteCond %{THE_REQUEST} ^[A-Z]{3,9} /index.php HTTP/
RewriteRule ^index.php$ http://www.domain.com/ [R=301,L]

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously you need to change domain.com to be your actual domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your store is running in a sub folder eg &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.domain.com/magento/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.domain.com/magento/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
RewriteBase /magento/ RewriteCond %{THE_REQUEST} ^[A-Z]{3,9} /magento/index.php HTTP/
RewriteRule ^index.php$ http://www.domain.com/magento/ [R=301,L]

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Upgrade for Love My Frames</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/magento-upgrade-for-love-my-frames.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 10:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/magento-upgrade-for-love-my-frames.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Magento Upgrade with Custom Modules Rewrite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project was to upgrade a store from 1.3 to 1.5, without losing the functionality of the site. The old version had had its core files modified, requiring a forensic examination of them in order to find and extract what had been changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Love My Frames&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love My Frames is run by highly trained technicians with over 40 years&amp;rsquo; optical experience, offering the kind of personal service you would normally expect from a high street opticians. Offering the best for considerably less, professional service and door-to-door delivery, they give their customers the ultimate shopping experience online plus the opportunity to purchase the &lt;a href=”http://www.lovemyframes.com/” &gt;very latest designs at a great price&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/lovemyframes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project asked for a clean install and then rewrite of the existing store. The biggest part of the project was taking the existing layered navigation and rewriting it to work on all pages with a custom design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>