<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ruby | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-10T11:40:03+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby Syntax Highlighting with PHPStorm]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/ruby/ruby-syntax-highlighting-with-phpstorm.html"/>
    <updated>2013-11-28T10:30:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/ruby/ruby-syntax-highlighting-with-phpstorm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PHPStorm is my IDE of choice for PHP development of course and also as many other languages as I can get it to support. One of my favourite plugins for PHPStorm is BASH Support which makes it into a fully featured BASH IDE with function support and syntax highlighting and some code inspections.</p>

<p>As we are now moving to Octopress for blogging functionality I wanted a way to get Ruby syntax highlighting. There is a full blown IntelliJ based Ruby IDE but that is overkill for my needs. I had a look at Netbeans however it has now stopped supporting Ruby though there is a community supported plugin apparently.</p>

<p>My best IDE solution so far is simply Vim, perhaps the <a href="http://vim.spf13.com/">spf13 flavour</a>.</p>

<p>After a bit of Googling good old Stack Overflow came through for me with <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/16451359/is-it-possible-to-get-ruby-syntax-highlighting-in-phpstorm">this post</a> that explains how to leverage PHPStorm&rsquo;s TextMate bundle support to get Ruby syntax highlighting. This works a treat though on my colour scheme (a slightly modified Darcula) it was unreadable. The final thing to do is to change the settings under Settings > TextMate Bundles and in the grid at the bottom next to my theme I switched the TextMate colour scheme from Mac Classic to RailsCasts and now it looks good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
