<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: seo | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/seo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-27T12:35:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First Thing You Should Read on SEO]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/SEO/the-first-thing-you-should-read-on-seo.html"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T12:16:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/SEO/the-first-thing-you-should-read-on-seo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is so much information about SEO out there and so many things that used
to be true but are no longer that it really has become a bit of a minefield.</p>

<p>For the average web master who simply wants to rank reasonably well and make sure that they are doign all of the basic things required to do so then this is the document you should read.</p>

<p>It is written by the company that are almost synonymous with the word search engine. In fact their company name has now become a verb meaning &lsquo;to use a search engine&rsquo;. It is of course Google.</p>

<p>You can read the official google SEO guidelines <a href="http://static.googleusercontent.com/media/www.google.co.uk/en/uk/webmasters/docs/search-engine-optimization-starter-guide.pdf">here</a></p>

<p>It is not a huge document and should be well within the technical understanding of the average webmaster.</p>

<p>I suggest you read it today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile Magento: App, Responsive Theme or Mobile Version]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/mobile-magento-app-responsive-theme-or-mobile-version.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-07T18:06:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Mobile%20optimisation/mobile-magento-app-responsive-theme-or-mobile-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mobile internet usage is perhaps one of the defining revolutions of this decade.</p>

<p>People love how quick and easy it is to quickly look up something on their mobile that they carry around 24/7.</p>

<p>Signs of mobile usage are now all around us. People scroll through websites on tablets, smartphones, notebooks and other web-enabled mobile devices to pass their time.</p>

<p>According to the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-14731757" target="_blank">BBC</a>, almost 50% of people have used the internet whilst away from their computer in a survey last year. In fact that article was published in 2011 so the reality now is probably much higher.</p>

<p>Have a look at these statistics which clearly show how mobile use is climbing year on year and now well over 10% of total usage:</p>

<iframe width="600" height="570" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="" id="na634982574962912257"></iframe>


<script type="text/javascript">document.getElementById("na634982574962912257").src="http://netmarketshare.com/report.aspx?qprid=61"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qptimeframe=M"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpsp=164"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpnp=6"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpch=350"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpdt=1"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpct=4"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpcid=fw486185"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpf=16"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpwidth=600"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpdisplay=1111"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"qpmr=10"+String.fromCharCode(38)+"site="+window.location.hostname</script>


<p>So if you are wanting to increase access to your site this is definitely something to consider!</p>

<h3>Developing World</h3>


<p>Mobile use is truly becoming a global phenomenon. Whilst China and India have the majority of mobile connections, the use of mobile phones by developing nations is also under a period of rapid growth.</p>

<p>Many people in the developing world are unable to buy or charge a computer but they can afford to use internet on their phone; they often lack a wired internet infrastructure, however the mobile technology is much easier to implement.</p>

<h3>Mcommerce</h3>


<p>As people have more access to sites on their phones, it is not surprising that they want to buy the things that they see on their phones.</p>

<p>According to a <a href="http://www.sas.com/offices/europe/uk/downloads/press/sas-verdict-retail2012.pdf" target="_blank">report by SAS and Verdict Consulting</a> survey m-Commerce &ldquo;is growing fast and will become an integral part of shopping for all ages –
retailers need mobile capability to engage with shoppers as well as sell to them.&rdquo;</p>

<h3>App</h3>


<p>Building Apps is quite a bespoke task which means you can modify your app to your specific modifications.</p>

<p>However designing the app means that you need to create it individually for each type of device, so this can become expensive as you will need at the least both an iOS (iPhone etc) app and also an Android app. You might also want a Windows Phone app giving you a total of three separate apps that need to be coded.</p>

<p>The popularity of mobile Apps has not gone unnoticed by Magento themselves as they have launched their own Magento mobile integration.</p>

<p>If you would like to find out more about Magento mobile app capability <a href="http://www.magentocommerce.com/product/mobile">here is the link to their website.</a></p>

<h3>Mobile Version of your Website</h3>


<p>Rather than opting for an app, we always recommend that instead you focus on having a mobile friendly web site.</p>

<p>There are two ways to optimise your site for mobile devices: these are responsive themes and mobile versions. They have positive points and drawbacks and it really depends on what you are looking for.</p>

<p>We offer both types of mobile optimisation so whatever option you decide, we are happy to implement it.</p>

<p>Just in case you are not sure about what the differences between responsive themes and mobile versions is, I shall give some more detail on this below.</p>

<h3>Responsive Theme</h3>


<p>Responsive themes are basically your current website but with the capability to scale itself to the size of a mobile device. The idea is rather than having one web page you can shape,size and place the elements of your site to fit any size browser.</p>

<p>According to <a href="http://googlemobileads.blogspot.co.uk/2012/07/mobile-websites-vs-responsive-design.html" title="Google" target="_blank">google</a> responsive themes are great for SEOs and for ease of updating the site. This may be because they minimise bounce rate which means it minimises problems of when a visitor presses the back button when the site is unresponsive. This in turn will improve your site ranking. Another SEO benefit is that it directs the user to one URL.  It is also easier to update than a mobile version of your site.</p>

<h3>Mobile Version</h3>


<p>A mobile version is literally a completely different website. This means that you can edit your site to be completely how you want it rather than tweak an existing site. The disadvantages of this is that it can time consuming and expensive.</p>

<p>A mobile version is served up as a completely alternative version of your website if a mobile user agent is detected. For Magento there are some modules that do a nice job of offering a fairly bog standard mobile version which is optimised for slow connections etc. These days with large screen powerful smartphones running on 3G networks, the issues that prompted the mobile version are less of an issue so we tend to lean more towards the responsive strategy these days.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>


<p>To summarise it is a great idea to optimise your site with mobile capability so that your customers can properly view your site. Responsive themes are best if you want to have a mobile version of your site that is easier, quicker and cheaper to update, while mobile versions are better if your aims are to have a bespoke mobile version of your site that you would not need to update regularly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reduce Catalog URL Rewrites Time in Magento]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/reduce-catalog-url-rewrites-time-in-magento.html"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T16:40:10+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/reduce-catalog-url-rewrites-time-in-magento</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had a client that wanted to remove the category structure from their product urls.</p>

<p>There is a option to do this in the admin, but they wanted to redirect all of the existing urls to the shorter one.</p>

<p>The way that I wanted to do this was to truncate the current core_url_rewrite table and regenerate the urls with the &ldquo;Use Categories Path for Product URLs&rdquo; set to no, and then override the 404 controller to redirect to the correct url.</p>

<p>However, after the urls were generated, I found that all of the urls including the category path were still included, which meant that the override would not work.</p>

<p>After spending quite a bit of time looking for a way to get round this, I put together a simple override to prevent the category path urls from getting generated.</p>

<p>This had the added benefit of reducing the number of entries in the core_url_rewite table from ~2k entries to under 500, which cut the amount of time that was needed to generate it.</p>

<p>The code is below for anyone else that needs to use this in the future. There are three files in total, set up like this</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>EdmondsCommerce/
`&mdash; Redirects</p>

<pre><code>|-- controllers
|   `-- Cms
|       `-- IndexController.php
|-- etc
|   `-- config.xml
`-- Model
    `-- Catalog
        `-- Url.php
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>This is the code for the Model</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>class EdmondsCommerce_Redirects_Model_Catalog_Url
  extends Mage_Catalog_Model_Url {</p>

<pre><code>/**
 * This method is called each time that a url 
 * is generated for a product. It is called for the 
 * root category and each category that the product is in.
 * 
 * This code checks to see if the category passed to it is
 * the root category. If it is it will 
 * add the url rewrite as normal. If not it does nothing
 * 
 * @param Varien_Object $product
 * @param Varien_Object $category
 */
protected function _refreshProductRewrite(Varien_Object $product, Varien_Object $category) {
    $rootCategory = $this-&gt;getStoreRootCategory($category-&gt;getStoreId());
    if($category-&gt;getId() == $rootCategory-&gt;getId()) {
        parent::_refreshProductRewrite($product, $category);
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>If you want to redirect from the existing urls to the new ones, you will need to use the following controller</p>

<p>```php</p>

<p>include_once(&lsquo;Mage/Cms/controllers/IndexController.php&rsquo;);</p>

<p>class EdmondsCommerce_Redirects_Cms_IndexController
extends Mage_Cms_IndexController {</p>

<pre><code>/**
 * This checks to see if the site can redirect
 * before displaying a 404
 * @param type $coreRoute
 */
public function noRouteAction($coreRoute = null) {
    // Get the request
    $request = $_SERVER['REQUEST_URI'];
    // Strip off get params if there are any
    if (strpos($request, '?') !== FALSE) {
        $request = substr($request, 0, strpos($request, '?'));
    }
    /**
     *  This makes sure that no part of the request is included
     *  in the base url. This should help
     *  the system work if it is running from a sub folder
     */
    $parts = explode('/', Mage::getBaseUrl());
    foreach ($parts AS $part) {
        $request = str_replace(array($part, '//'), '', $request);
    }
    /*
     * Combine the request with the base path to get the full url
     * and remove any trailing slashes
     */
    $path = trim(str_replace('http:/', 'http://', str_replace('//', '/', Mage::getBaseUrl() . $request)), '/');
    //Get the last section which should be the product title
    $cleanedPath = explode('/', $path);
    $key = array_pop($cleanedPath);
    //Here we find url keys like the title
    $collection = Mage::getModel('catalog/product')-&gt;getCollection();
    $collection-&gt;addAttributeToSelect('url_key');
    $collection-&gt;addFieldToFilter(array(
        array('attribute' =&gt; 'url_key', 'like' =&gt; "$key")));
    $products = $collection-&gt;load();
    /*
     * Proceed if there is only 1 result, if there are more we
     * don't know which one is correct
     */
    if (count($products) == 1) {
        foreach ($products AS $product) {
            $url = Mage::getBaseUrl(Mage_Core_Model_Store::URL_TYPE_WEB) . $product-&gt;getUrlKey();
            //Check to make sure the url is not the same as the path, should prevent infinite redirects
            if ($path != $url) {
                header('HTTP/1.1 301 Moved Permanently');
                header('Location: ' . $url);
                die();
            }
        }
    }
    // Could not find a suitable url carry out the 404
    parent::noRouteAction($coreRoute);
}
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Then use the following xml file</p>

<p>```xml</p>

<p>&lt;?xml version=&ldquo;1.0&rdquo;?>
<config></p>

<pre><code>&lt;modules&gt;
    &lt;EdmondsCommerce_Redirects&gt;
        &lt;version&gt;0.1.0&lt;/version&gt;
        &lt;depends&gt;&lt;/depends&gt;
    &lt;/EdmondsCommerce_Redirects&gt;
&lt;/modules&gt;
&lt;global&gt;
    &lt;models&gt;
        &lt;redirects&gt;
            &lt;class&gt;EdmondsCommerce_Redirects_Model&lt;/class&gt;
        &lt;/redirects&gt;
        &lt;catalog&gt;
            &lt;rewrite&gt;
                &lt;url&gt;EdmondsCommerce_Redirects_Model_Catalog_Url&lt;/url&gt;
            &lt;/rewrite&gt;
        &lt;/catalog&gt;
    &lt;/models&gt;
&lt;/global&gt;
&lt;frontend&gt;
    &lt;routers&gt;
        &lt;cms&gt;
            &lt;args&gt;
                &lt;modules&gt;
                    &lt;EdmondsCommerce_Redirects before="Mage_Cms"&gt;EdmondsCommerce_Redirects_Cms&lt;/EdmondsCommerce_Redirects&gt;
                &lt;/modules&gt;
            &lt;/args&gt;
        &lt;/cms&gt;
    &lt;/routers&gt;
&lt;/frontend&gt;
</code></pre>

<p></config></p>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Link Building Strategies – The Complete List | Point Blank SEO]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/link%20building/link-building-strategies-%25e2%2580%2593-the-complete-list-point-blank-seo.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T08:16:25+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/link%20building/link-building-strategies-%e2%80%93-the-complete-list-point-blank-seo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Very comprehensive list of link building strategies, some great inspiration for anyone looking to boost their SEO.</p>

<p>Mostly common sense though a few interesting ideas you may not gave thought of.</p>

<p><a href="http://pointblankseo.com/link-building-strategies"><a href="http://pointblankseo.com/link-building-strategies">http://pointblankseo.com/link-building-strategies</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento URL Request Routing]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-url-request-routing.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T16:13:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-url-request-routing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento is a typical PHP Model View Architecture (MVC) system which routes its URLs in ways not particularly different from other PHP MVC Frameworks like codeigniter, symphony etc. But the difference it has with other MVC architecture is that most of its routing directives or configurations are XML based i.e. found in one XML file or the other.</p>

<p>For example, www.yourstore.co.uk/index.php/checkout/cart/index, tells Magento to use the checkout module found in app/code/Mage/,  use the cart controller (i.e. CartController.php) in app/code/Mage/Checkout/controller/ and run the index action method in the CartController.php, when the last &ldquo;index&rdquo; is omitted Magento still defaults to run the index action method, and every other value in the url after the first three url steps, Magento treats them as PHP GET parameters i.e. www.yourstore.co.uk/index.php/checkout/cart/index/store/1 would make $_GET[&lsquo;store&rsquo;]=1</p>

<p>It is this action method that searches through the magneto xml configuration file using x-path to obtain information regarding this request e.g. the indexAction method found in app/code/Mage/Checkout/controller/CartController.php uses  Mage::getStoreConfig(&lsquo;sales/minimum_order/description&rsquo;) to get the value of the description node  in sales module, the minimum_order node and description child node, which can be found in system.xml in the Sales/etc/ folder.</p>

<p>Its is worthwhile also knowing that Magento uses Apache&rsquo;s URL rewrite engine (mod_rewrite) to make its URLs SEO friendly i.e. www.yourstore.co.uk/index.php/catalog/product/view/id/1 could be routed to www.yourstore.co.uk/index.php/product1.html which can be regarded as an alias for  www.yourstore.co.uk/index.php/catalog/product/view/id/1 to make Google happy and improve the sites SEO.</p>

<p>This basically describes how Magento decides what to do when accessed by a particular URL.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
