<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: github | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/github/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-06T12:06:51+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Merging Forks for Composer]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/composer/merging-forks-for-composer.html"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T19:53:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/composer/merging-forks-for-composer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am really enjoying using Composer with a Symfony2 project that I am currently working on.</p>

<p>Recently though I found an issue where I am using the FOSRest Bundle to provide JSON API functionality. This in turn uses the
JMS/SerializerBundle to handle the actual encoding into JSON.</p>

<p>The problem is that the JMS bundle converts camelCase to snake_case and I decided I really didn&rsquo;t want that. I want my property and entity names to be the same across formats.</p>

<p>A bit of digging and I found <a href="https://github.com/passkey1510/JMSSerializerBundle">this fork</a> which features a fix for exactly this problem, brilliant!</p>

<p>However on trying to get this to install with Composer I simply could not get it to work. Further investigation shows that the version of the JMS bundle that this fork does not meet
the minimum version requirements of the FOSRest bundle. Problem.</p>

<p>The solution in the end was to fork the JMSSerializerBundle Directly then pull this down locally. Once I had that locally I then added the fork with the fix I need as another remote:</p>

<p><code>
git remote add passkey1510 git@github.com:passkey1510/JMSSerializerBundle.git
git merge remote/passkey1510/master
git push
</code></p>

<p>Those three commands added the other fork as another remote allowing me to pull in the commits that feature the fix I need. Finally I pushed this back up to github.</p>

<p>I can now reference my fork in my composer.json file like this:</p>

<p>```
&ldquo;repositories&rdquo;: [</p>

<pre><code>    {
        "url": "https://github.com/edmondscommerce/JMSSerializerBundle.git",
        "type": "vcs"
    },
</code></pre>

<p>],
```</p>

<p>Now running a <code>composer update --dev</code> and composer successfully brought in my fork of the Serializerbundle with the extra fixes to allow the property names to stay in camelCase.</p>

<p>And that is it, problem solved :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress auto building the site locally for one blog post]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Octoress/octopress-auto-building-the-site-locally-for-one-blog-post.html"/>
    <updated>2013-12-03T17:47:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/Octoress/octopress-auto-building-the-site-locally-for-one-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Setting up a blog post using Octopress involves writing up your Markdown content, building the site, and previewing it.</p>

<p>This can be time-consuming when writing posts, having to run several commands repeatedly. Here&rsquo;s a few lines you can put into a bash script and run once each time:</p>

<p>``` bash</p>

<h1>!/bin/bash</h1>

<p>PATHTOLATEST=<code>ls -t source/_posts | head -1</code>;
echo $PATHTOLATEST
bundle exec rake isolate[$PATHTOLATEST];
bundle exec rake generate;
bundle exec rake preview;</p>

<p>```</p>

<ol>
<li>The PATHTOLATEST variable finds the latest post</li>
<li>echo the variable for debugging purposes</li>
<li>rake isolate instructs octopress to build the site with only the latest blog post</li>
<li>rake generate builds the site</li>
<li>rake preview initialises the web server</li>
</ol>


<p>From then you can make changes to your post, and the site will be automatically regenerated. This uses a file watcher so it&rsquo;s helpful to keep the terminal open to watch for it building, or having errors</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento 2 Source Code Available on GitHub]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T07:37:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-2-source-code-available-on-github</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magento version two is coming. For those of us who are eagerly awaiting the next major version of the most popular and powerful open source e-commerce platform, you can now see, track and download the code on GitHub.</p>

<p>Not had chance to have an in depth look as yet but we expect great things!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/magento/magento2"><a href="https://github.com/magento/magento2">https://github.com/magento/magento2</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symfony Moving to Github Source Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-moving-to-github-source-control.html"/>
    <updated>2010-01-13T17:01:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-moving-to-github-source-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is an old post. The information it contains is probably out of date or innacurate</h4>
<p>
This is a post that was written a long time ago and is only being kept here for posterity.
You should probably look up more recent blog posts related to the subject you are researching
</p>
</div>


<p>My favourite PHP framework of the moment, Symfony, is now moving to my favourite version control system &ndash; Git.</p>

<p>read more about it <a href="http://www.symfony-project.org/blog/2010/01/13/symfony-2-migration-to-git">Symfony 2 Migration to Git</a></p>

<p>Its only for the version 2 release, but its a nice step forwards. Github is a really nice system.</p>

<p>The blog post also mentions this great online Git book:</p>

<p><a href="http://progit.org/">Pro Git</a></p>

<p>Not actually come across that before, will be handy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
