<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: netbeans | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/netbeans/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-30T14:38:16+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStorm: Get More Info on Auto-Complete (like netbeans)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-get-more-info-on-auto-complete-like-netbeans.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T17:00:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-get-more-info-on-auto-complete-like-netbeans</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All developers love code completion, but sometimes the minimalist info that can come up in PHPStorm can be not quite enough.</p>

<p>Netbeans gave an excerpt that gave plenty of information from the docblock, and PHPStorm can do too, it just defaults to off.</p>

<p>The setting is under Editor->Code Completion and is &ldquo;Show full signatures&rdquo;.  The good news is it is an &ldquo;IDE Setting&rdquo; so it persists for all projects, the bad news is that that means the setting will be forgotten about before you next reinstall and want it again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tip: PhpStorm "Select in Projects" - Easier version]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/tip-phpstorm-select-in-projects-easier-version.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-08T18:26:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/tip-phpstorm-select-in-projects-easier-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Followers of this blog will remember the <a title="Replicate Netbeans “Select in project” in phpstorm" href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/phpstorm/replicate-netbeans-select-in-project-in-phpstorm/">Replicate Netbeans “Select in project” in phpstorm</a> post which gave a handy key combo to select the current file in the project window.</p>

<p>It has been brought to our attention that there&rsquo;s also a button to do this with the mouse in one click!  At the top of the Project window, there&rsquo;s a cross-hair/target icon labelled a rather cryptic &ldquo;Scroll from Source&rdquo;.  Click that and it does what netbeans users will be looking for as &ldquo;Select in Projects&rdquo;</p>

<p>So there you have it, &ldquo;Scroll from Source&rdquo;, is the magic words that you want.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStorm 5 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T09:07:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Edmonds Commerce we were staunch Netbeans users for years but we always struggled with large scale projects (<a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento/" title="Magento Platform Overview">Magento</a> I&rsquo;m looking at you) meaning that Netbeans would sometimes really crawl as it tried to reindex thousands of PHP files.</p>

<p>After a recent upgrade of our Linux desktop environment to the Mate edition of Linux Mint 13, Netbeans seemed to perform even worse and had a few bugs as well. At the same time we had been evaluating other IDE options including Eclipse and Zend Studio (which we all have free licences for thanks to being Zend Certified Developers).</p>

<p>In the end though, the one we tried that really impressed was PHPStorm. It isn&rsquo;t free open source but it isn&rsquo;t too expensive, especially considering it is perhaps the single most important and highly used tool of a professional PHP developer.</p>

<p>Now a new version has come out. Downloading and upgrading took all of 5 minutes and we are now going to enjoy better performance and some nice new features. I have yet to really test out the new version so I can&rsquo;t really report on them but they look good. You can read about all the new features in version 5 <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/whatsnew/" title="PHPStorm 5 Features" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Replicate Netbeans "Select in project" in phpstorm]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/replicate-netbeans-select-in-project-in-phpstorm.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T14:41:36+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/replicate-netbeans-select-in-project-in-phpstorm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Netbeans has a handy feature when you right-click a file in the editor window to take you to the file in the project (file manager tab) view.</p>

<p>To get phpstorm to do this is not as simple but is handily mappable to a shortcut key.</p>

<p>To enable this, go to Settings->Keymap->Main menu->Navigate->Select in&hellip; and choose a key.  I set it to Alt+P, so now I press Alt+P then press enter to go to the current file in the project view.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netbeans Xdebug "Waiting for connection" Ubuntu 12.04 Mint13 +SOLUTION]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/netbeans-xdebug-waiting-for-connection-ubuntu-12-04-mint13-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-21T17:07:20+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/netbeans-xdebug-waiting-for-connection-ubuntu-12-04-mint13-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have issues with netbeans and xdebug not connecting on recent distros, you might find that netbeans is listening on tcp6 and xdebug connecting on plain tcp.</p>

<p>To check if this is the case, run the following command whilst netbeans is &ldquo;waiting for connection&rdquo; (change 9000 if you&rsquo;ve set a different port) :&ndash;</p>

<p><code>netstat -aln | grep 9000</code></p>

<p>if you get a line similar to the following (specifically tcp6 and not just tcp), it may well be that xdebug can&rsquo;t connect over ipv6 :&ndash;
<code>tcp6       0      0 :::9000                 :::*                    LISTEN</code></p>

<p>One solution is to disable ipv6, which can be done by creating the file /etc/sysctl.d/10-disable-ipv6.conf with the following contents :&ndash;
<code>net.ipv6.conf.all.disable_ipv6=1
net.ipv6.conf.default.disable_ipv6=1
net.ipv6.conf.lo.disable_ipv6=1</code></p>

<p>then run (as root or sudo)
<code>sysctl -p /etc/sysctl.d/10-disable-ipv6.conf</code>
and restart netbeans.  Suddenly, netbeans will listen on tcp (ipv4) and xdebug will connect.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
