<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creloaded on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/creloaded/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creloaded on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 16:08:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/creloaded/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove footer from Loaded Commerce (CRELoaded new name)</title>
      <link>http://example.com/oscommerce/remove-footer-from-loaded-commerce-creloaded-new-name.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 16:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/oscommerce/remove-footer-from-loaded-commerce-creloaded-new-name.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Well known is how Loaded Commerce/CRELoaded protect their google banners they wack on all opensource versions of their code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have removed the footer in the current version though, it checks the output buffer and you will find it after the closing html tag of your page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function that does this is cre_uregisterBasicFunctions(); and if you remove the call to it from application_bottom.php, bye bye ads!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarily, if a hacker got control of www.loadedcommerce.com, php code could actually be inserted into EVERY Loaded Commerce installation that doesn&amp;rsquo;t remove this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce to Magento Migration with Redesign Starting from £1280</title>
      <link>http://example.com/magento/oscommerce-to-magento-migrations-with-redesign-starting-from-1280.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 11:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/magento/oscommerce-to-magento-migrations-with-redesign-starting-from-1280.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Migrate your &lt;strong&gt;osCommerce, CRE Loaded or Zen Cart&lt;/strong&gt; store to &lt;strong&gt;Magento&lt;/strong&gt; for as little as &lt;strong&gt;£1280&lt;/strong&gt;. Get in touch today and we can discuss your particular requirements and help you at every step of the way in your migration to &lt;strong&gt;Magento&lt;/strong&gt;, without a doubt the best open source ecommerce platform available today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of upgrading or migrating from your osCommerce, CRE Loaded or Zen Cart based store to Magento then you should definitely get in touch with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce have years of experience working with osCommerce and its derivatives and know the platform inside out, back to front. We have done all kinds of things with osCommerce and still have a large number of clients still using the platform with great success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However Magento is becoming more and more of an attractive option. It is new, modern, powerful and is definitely on the up. Certain Magento features, such as the multi store would be so hard to achieve with an osCommerce based store (or CRE Loaded, Zen Cart) that a migration to Magnento is the only realistic option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading Magento specialists, we have worked on a large number of Magento sites for a wide range of clients in all kinds of industries. We spotted Magento on the up when it was still in its infancy. We knew that osCommerce was getting a bit long in the tooth and the market was wide open for its successor as the most popular open source ecommerce platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later and it has certainly achieved that status, eclipsing osCommerce in every way apart perhaps from the number of sites running it. Having been around for a long time and being very successful, there are still a large number of sites using osCommerce (or CRE Loaded, Zen Cart). However we are now seeing more and more new and existing clients looking to move away from osCommerce and onto Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are able to help you perform and smooth and seamless transition from one platform to the other. We can migrate all the necessary data over and get your new store working perfectly and to your satisfaction before making a seamless switch so you suffer no down time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to get some Magento training we are also able to help you with this, offering both classroom based Magento training in Leeds, West Yorkshire and online training for those for whom Leeds is a bit difficult to get to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If you would like to know more or get in touch&lt;/b&gt;
Please &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;click here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to go to our contact form and get in touch with us regarding osCommerce to Magento migrations by osCommerce and Magento experts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRE Loaded PCI Compliance Validated</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/cre-loaded-pci-compliance-validated.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 12:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/cre-loaded-pci-compliance-validated.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
CRE Loaded osCommerce (by far my favourite and most highly recommended flavour of osCommerce) have recently posted on their blog about becoming the first open source ecommerce cart to be given PCI Approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refreshingly as well they have redesigned their site and have gone back to making their free open source version more prominent on the site. I think this is a really good thing. I was always uncomfortable about their policy of overly pushing the paid for versions and making it tricky to find the free version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is then down the customer to decide whether to go with the free version or to take advantage of the extra features offered by the paid for version. This also allows potential CRE Loaded store owners to download the software and play around with it and discover if it really is the system for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For smaller operations that require a good solid easy to use and cheap to set up ecommerce platform I firmly recommend CRE Loaded (free or otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For larger operations or those people wanting something a bit more advanced than straight forward ecommerce I strongly recommend Magento. The best open source ecommerce platform is still Magento in my opinion, but CRE Loaded definitely has its place secured.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRE Loaded UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/oscommerce/creloaded-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 19:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/oscommerce/creloaded-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a hell of a lot of time coding &lt;b&gt;Magento&lt;/b&gt; recently, and for any full time serious ecommerce business I would recommend a Magento solution. However I have spent much more of my time coding &lt;b&gt;osCommerce&lt;/b&gt; and usually &lt;b&gt;CRE Loaded&lt;/b&gt; osCommerce based ecommerce sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRELoaded is still a great package (once you get rid of the annoying nags and ads) and is really taking the osCommerce platform and polishing it up to a nice usable fully featured system. If you are looking for a UK based developer who specialises in ecommerce, osCommerce and CRELoaded development then definitely get in touch. Don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised though if I mention that Magento is definitely worth a close look!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce Easypopulate File Creator Class</title>
      <link>http://example.com/oscommerce/ecommerce/product-catalogue/oscommerce-easypopulate-file-creator-class.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 14:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/oscommerce/ecommerce/product-catalogue/oscommerce-easypopulate-file-creator-class.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
When doing spidering projects or other bulk catalogue management projects for osCommerce sites, I tend to finish by creating easypopulate format files so that the store owner can do any last minute edits and upload the products manually using the easypopulate system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating easypopulate format files can be a bit of a chore, especially as every site seems to be slightly different with different columns etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, I have created a very easy to use easypopulate file creation class. You can read more about the class &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phpclasses.org/browse/package/4782.htm&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have numerous clients who are now enjoying much, &lt;i&gt;much&lt;/i&gt; easier management of their product catalogues including fully automated spidering systems that grab all details from supplier web sites and format it correctly to be uploaded to their store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss ways that Edmonds Commerce can save you time and money whilst boosting your business - get in touch today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelance osCommerce UK</title>
      <link>http://example.com/php/freelance-oscommerce-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 15:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/php/freelance-oscommerce-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
It seems that there are many UK webmasters who struggle to find a reliable UK based web developer who specialises in PHP. I have heard stories of people who claim to be osCommerce experts but in reality they simply know how to install a few contributions and that&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a freelance osCommerce developer, especially if you would prefer to deal with someone else in the United Kingdom then you would do well to get in touch with me. I now have a long list of happy clients who have had their osCommerce sites improved, speeded up and automatically populated with huge catalogues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to clarify. Edmonds Commerce is a &lt;b&gt;Freelance web developer&lt;/b&gt; who specialise in &lt;b&gt;osCommerce&lt;/b&gt; and is &lt;b&gt;UK Based&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Edmonds Commerce also specialise in all &lt;em&gt;osCommerce Derived Systems&lt;/em&gt; including &lt;b&gt;CRE Loaded&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Zen Cart&lt;/b&gt; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>