<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: pa-dss | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/pa-dss/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-29T11:44:10+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento PCI Compliance and PA-DSS]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-pci-compliance-and-pa-dss.html"/>
    <updated>2010-11-02T11:09:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-pci-compliance-and-pa-dss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently came across a forum post which I would like to quote here as I think it sums things up nicely. You can see the original post <a href="http://www.nublue.co.uk/forums/post/622/#p622">here</a>.</p>

<p>The Community edition has not been verified as PA-DSS compliant, which is not the same as PCI-DSS compliancy.</p>

<p>PCI-DSS is the compliancy of your online environment, practices, software etc.  That is the standard that is required to be able to process on-site payments.
PA-DSS is not the same, it is part of PCI-DSS.  It&rsquo;s a standard for the software that you are using for processing payments, just as PCI-DSS is the standard for the merchants processing payments on-site.  PA-DSS is the standard whereby the software provider subjects the software to a rigorous set of standards, tests and development practices (all viewable on the PA DSS Website) to confirm that the PA-DSS requirements are entirely met.
Anyone using Community edition has 2 options:</p>

<p>1 &ndash; use an off-site payment gateway, so none of this matters (the gateway will be PA-DSS software running in a PCI-DSS environment and PCI-DSS is not therefore required) &ndash; this is by far the easiest option available!</p>

<p>2 &ndash; verify the software as PA-DSS compliant yourself by going through the PCI-DSS questionnaire and confirming the relevant data.
There is nowhere in the PCI-DSS questionnaire that says, &ldquo;if your payment software has not been certified as PA-DSS compliant, you cannot be PCI-DSS compliant&rdquo;.</p>

<p>However the basic tenets of PA-DSS compliancy is an essential part of becoming PCI-DSS compliant.
The only thing that PA-DSS provides, is a guarantee that any part of the compliancy questionnaire related to PA-DSS requirements (encryption of card #&rsquo;s, cardholder data etc) is a certified yes, that does not require any investigation and confirmation from the client first.  These areas are all listed within the PCI-DSS SAQ (Self Assessment Questionnaire).  There is also a lengthy PA-DSS document on the website that lists the requirements of PA-DSS &ndash; the community edition, presumably, doesn&rsquo;t meet these requirements, as it is a hook for paying for the Professional or Enterprise editions, as they have in turn paid and worked on having those editions verified, but don&rsquo;t see the benefits to implementing this for the Community edition.</p>

<p>Whereas the Pro/Enterprise editions will include certain best-practice features (such as auto-expiring passwords for instance) and of course are PA-DSS compliant, it&rsquo;s also worth mentioning while we&rsquo;re on the subject that they do not anywhere explicitly state that the Community edition is not PA-DSS compliant&hellip;</p>

<p>It really means the PCI-DSS responsibility is further placed on the clients' shoulders; PA-DSS means you have one less thing to worry about.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
