<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vps on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.com/categories/vps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vps on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 10:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.com/categories/vps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Running out of disk space but df shows you have lots of space left</title>
      <link>http://example.com/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 10:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/linux/vps/server/running-out-of-disk-space-but-df-shows-you-have-lots-of-space-left.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a strange occurency this morning with an server reporting it had no disk space when disk usage according to df was at 50%. After some head scratching I decided to read the man page for the df command and came across the -i flag. According the man page this lists inode information instead of block usage. After running it I got the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Filesystem      Inodes   IUsed  IFree IUse% Mounted on
/dev/xvda1     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2621440&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2621440&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  100% /
udev            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;124879&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;398&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;124481&lt;/span&gt;    1% /dev
tmpfs           &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;288&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126604&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126888&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/lock
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126891&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/shm
none            &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126892&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;126891&lt;/span&gt;    1% /run/user
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it turned out that the system had reached its max inodes so the next line of investigation was to find any excess of files in an directory. Which was sone by using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i in /var/*&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; find &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; wc -l&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will list the total number of files in a given directory. You can change the path to work your way down the directory tree finding directories with lots of files. In the end we found excess of old logs which I was able to remove.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why VPS is Not for Everyone - Yet</title>
      <link>http://example.com/hosting/vps/why-vps-is-not-for-everyone-yet.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 11:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/hosting/vps/why-vps-is-not-for-everyone-yet.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
There is a lot of buzz at the moment surrounding VPS hosting. For those of you who are not familiar with VPS, or virtual private server hosting - it is similar to shared hosting in that you are sharing a physical server with other web sites. The big difference is that with a VPS, you are not sharing the operating system with those other sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To clarify this. Think of your desktop PC and think of web sites as separate windows running Word for example (this is just to illustrate the idea). Each instance of Word is a separate entity but they are all running on the same instance of windows and are all running on the same machine. There are some security issues with this idea, for example someone elses instance of word might be able to get access to your folder with your files in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a VPS, there is only your instance of word running in your instance of windows. And only you can access your files. From your point of view, the VPS operates exactly as if it was a dedicated server. You have total control over every single bit of the operating system and can install whatever software you wish and make any changes that you would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also - VPS solutions tend to offer better protection against the physical server resources being hogged by one particularly demanding account at the cost of all the other accounts on the server. Instead on VPS systems, the resources are more rigidly shared out meaning that you have a guaranteed minimum level of performance that can not be degraded no matter how hard other VPS&amp;rsquo;s on the physical server are being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all sounds great, and for many people it is. However there is a big BUT&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drawback with VPS hosting is in the support. Often these VPS accounts are available very cheaply and when they are working they can work really well. The problem arises when they stop working. You go to the hosting company and ask them why the server has stopped working and they tell you that they do not support the software and its your responsibility to sort it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the average person who just wanted a hosting environment for their web site and is not an experienced systems administrator can come really unstuck because you simply might not be able to fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With dedicated server hosting, many hosts offer something called Managed hosting. This is where you not only get the machine but you also get a full support service and ongoing management to keep the machine up to date with the latest patches and security updates and also get the machine up and running again should there be any problems. If you can afford this kind of service then I highly recommend going for it, but it is significantly more expensive than VPS hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to conclude, if you do not regard yourself as an experienced systems administrator then I would highly recommend you double check the level of support offered with the VPS before you sign up for it. For UK based readers, I would especially recommend avoiding web fusion VPS servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need any help finding a suitable hosting solution for your online business - get in touch today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>