<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: productivity | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/productivity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-07T14:56:57+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing Google Drive documents from Gmail when sending emails]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/sharing-google-drive-documents-from-gmail-when-sending-emails.html"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T17:17:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/gmail/sharing-google-drive-documents-from-gmail-when-sending-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was writing an email to a customer, and had created a Google Drive spreadsheet for us to collaborate on, I put a link to the document into the email, intending to share the document with the customer immediately after.</p>

<p>To my surprise when I hit Send a prompt came up asking me if I want to share the linked document with the email recipients. You can choose to have it publicly viewable/editable using the link, or even to add the email&rsquo;s recipients to the document&rsquo;s share list (which of course requires them to be using a Google account).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/gmail-drive-prompt.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome AutoCorrect for Gmail (and Google Apps)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T13:54:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/chrome-autocorrect-for-gmail-and-google-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you use Gmail (also bundled with Google Apps) for your business then you probably write a lot of emails directly into the gmail interface. If you are like me you probably make teh the mistakes all teh time. (See what I did there!)</p>

<p>As the MD of Edmonds Commerce I probably write more emails than most people with everything from <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento">Magento</a> quotes, client communications, enquiries and maybe even the occasional personal email. At a guess I would say I write a good few thousand words per day. I should calculate that one day.</p>

<p>Well help is at hand with this wonderful chrome extension that will auto correct common typos as you type them in gmail. For me this is a real productivity booster as I type fast but badly and this really tidies up a lot of my common mistakes meaning less <em>backspace</em> and more <em>getting stuff done</em>.</p>

<p>You can grab the extension <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ezautocorrect-for-gmail/fholdolknchpdbajhpdenookmikblmda/related" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>I hope you find it useful. On another note, if you aren&rsquo;t currently using Google Apps (its free you know) and would like to look at transitioning your business to the system then get in touch with us and we would be happy to help you with it. I can not recommend the service enough to be honest, even if you go for the paid version the cost is negligible really. Smaller companies should be find with the free version though which you really can&rsquo;t argue with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
