<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelance on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/freelance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freelance on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 09:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/freelance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Programmer</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-programmer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 09:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-programmer.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These days we call programmers developers. When working with web sites the usual term is web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are a team of highly skilled PHP web developers that specialise in Magento Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a Magento programmer, i.e. a Magento developer, then you have come to the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/&#34;&gt;Get in touch&lt;/a&gt; with Edmonds Commerce today to get the technical Magento expertise you need to make the most of your business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Job Leeds, Still Hiring Developers</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-job-leeds-hiring-developers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 18:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-job-leeds-hiring-developers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Just an update for any PHP developers in and around the Leeds, Bradford and West Yorkshire region:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce are still looking for skilled and enthusiastic PHP developers to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our focus is entirely on e-commerce which is an exciting and challenging field for the right kind of person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect our developers to be at or around the Zend Certified Developer level but other than that there are no specific criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested please do get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will initially ask you to do a quick PHP quiz, if you want to do that straight away just go here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmonds-commerce.co.uk/PHPTest/form.php&#34;&gt;http://www.edmonds-commerce.co.uk/PHPTest/form.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us&#34;&gt;get in touch directly&lt;/a&gt; as well though, the spam bots quite enjoy filling it out as well and I haven&amp;rsquo;t got around to protecting it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento UK</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/ecommerce/magento/magento-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 15:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/ecommerce/magento/magento-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce specialise in &lt;strong&gt;Magento Ecommerce&lt;/strong&gt; and are available for &lt;strong&gt;Freelance Magento&lt;/strong&gt; projects and installations. If you are looking to set up a new ecommerce venture and are considering using Magento - get in touch today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magento is certainly making waves. For those of you who haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it, Magento is looking likely to become the successor to osCommerce as the most popular open source ecommerce platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things which make Magento a much better option than osCommerce. However for some people the tried and tested, &amp;lsquo;better the devil you know&amp;rsquo;, huge knowledge, customisation and support base of osCommerce  makes it the platform they would still prefer to put their development investment into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These justifications are valid to a point, however I now believe that the time is right to move into Magento and whilst I am not certain that it is worth worrying about upgrading if you already have a perfectly functional osCommerce site, I would recommend anyone looking to set up a new ecommerce site takes a close look at Magento.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>