<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ecommerce | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/ecommerce/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-11T10:37:52+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Practices for Highly Effective Email Marketing]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/13-best-practices-to-highly-effective-newsletter.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T11:52:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/13-best-practices-to-highly-effective-newsletter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Each email email must have specific and measurable goals defined. For example &ndash; to read an article, sell a product or sign up for an event. It&rsquo;s a Call to Action, a short but precise message which tells the recipient exactly what to do &ndash; no more, no less. The Call to Action is one of the most important email email elements; therefore it must be noticeable and inviting. This article will cover best practices on how to create a highly effective email.</p>

<p>If you are not sure on how to create a highly effective email that converts customers in to a successful sales leads, then here are the basic questions you need to ask yourself:</p>

<ul>
    <li>What I want my recipients to do?</li>

    <li>How will they know how to do it?</li>

    <li>How will they benefit from doing what I want?</li>
</ul>


<p>It sounds dead easy, but it&rsquo;s not that simple, because you don&rsquo;t want to scare away your customers with an overly insisting tone. On the other hand, if you don&rsquo;t give your recipient clear guidance on what to do it is most likely they will not do it.</p>

<p>Here are the core principles on how to create a highly effective email:</p>

<h3>1. The value of the email</h3>


<p>Your Call To Action must clearly communicate the benefits that the customer will receive. Benefits must be clearly visible, order them by priority.</p>

<h3>2. Use simple and convincing language</h3>


<p>Remember that your recipients are wise and most likely &ndash; very busy people. Therefore make the message as clear and simple as possible. Don&rsquo;t make their lives more complicated by using complex language and long paragraphs. Ease their decision and make the choice simple.</p>

<h3>3. Make the email urgent and limited</h3>


<p>When the message is urgent and somehow limited (for first 50 respondents or while product is in stock, etc), people are more motivated to act. Use words like Now, Today, Only, Limited, etc. Say why they must act now, explain the benefits.</p>

<h3>4. Catchy headlines</h3>


<p>Web users read by scanning the headlines, therefore they must be short, but catchy. The main point regarding the headline is not to sell the product (if you sell one), but to engage recipient to read the content of the email.</p>

<h3>5. Use numbers and make them meaningful</h3>


<p>Numbers deliver a clear message, they create an impression. However, numbers alone are meaningless, use them in context. For example, 4Gb of music storage is meaningless, say how many songs it can carry. Feel free to break it down even further.</p>

<h3>6. Ask questions</h3>


<p>Questions are great for attention grabbing. Especially, when you send a targeted email, you most likely know your audience and you know what they need. Make sure you ask. For example &ndash; Is your laptop too heavy? And follow with an immediate solution. Create questions so they are intriguing and recipients want to know more.</p>

<h3>7. Less is more. (Yes)</h3>


<p>Don&rsquo;t include too many Call To Actions. Don&rsquo;t over fill the email with products or offers. It is very easy for the recipient to get lost if there are too many adverts.</p>

<h3>8. Call To Action placement</h3>


<p>Remember to place your Call To Action in a highly visible location. If you have multiple Calls to Action make sure that the supporting information is clearly grouped. The primary message has to be as close to the top as possible with supporting information or offers taking position below the fold.</p>

<h3>9. Related design and style</h3>


<p>Your email email need to use represent your company and branding. Don&rsquo;t try to use different design, colours and overall style in your email. Recipients remember who you are (or at least they should), changing email design will only bring in confusion and most likely dramatically reduce the conversions.</p>

<h3>10. Use a consistent layout</h3>


<p>Your email must be well organized and content should be prioritized. Do this by placing elements within the layout. Once your email design is created, stick to it. Don&rsquo;t try to use different sizes and colours, unless you are testing various variations for better conversion rates.</p>

<h3>11. Use white space</h3>


<p>White space is good. It&rsquo;s not unused sales place. It actually helps the recipient to focus more on the proposal without distraction.</p>

<h3>12. Send relevant content to the right audience</h3>


<p>Emails shouldn&rsquo;t be generic. Most mistakes are made when a proposal is created that is very generic and sent out to everyone &ndash; it can apply to everybody on your list or none at all. Make sure that you know your audience and you send offers that are relevant to them. This can be done by automatically grouping customers by what they&rsquo;ve browsed or bought recently. This is normally called List Segmentation for example only emailing people who have bought a blue widget in the last six months.</p>

<h3>13. Don't send for the sake of it</h3>


<p>Add value to your emails. Send offers that are really beneficial to the target customer. Make them anticipate your offer. If you send overly frequent and generic emails, you risk simply loosing subscribers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play.com to Go Marketplace Only - Abandoning Retail Completely]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T15:14:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/play-com-to-go-marketplace-only-abandoning-retail-completely</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most online merchants who are into multichannel selling (that&rsquo;s all of you, right?) must have heard of Play.com.</p>

<p>Never quite up there with Amazon and Ebay it was often the one that merchants asked us to integrate with once the two big ones were taken care of. Play was originally a pure online retailer but decided a few years ago to jump on the marketplace bandwagon like market leaders Amazon.</p>

<p>Now it seems Play have been bought out by a Japanese company and thanks to a lucrative VAT loophole being closed (and rightly so) they have now decided to abandon retail sales completely and concentrate purely on their marketplace business.</p>

<p>You can read more about it here:
<a href="http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042"><a href="http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042">http://www.mcvuk.com//news/read/play-com-to-shut-down-retail-business/0109042</a></a></p>

<p>And it might be worth checking out their current clearance for particularly good offers as well from a punters point of view.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How 10,000 Geeks break the UK's biggest distributors, RS and Farnell (Raspberry Pi)]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T06:50:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/how-10000-geeks-break-the-uks-biggest-distributors-rs-and-farnell-raspberry-pi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, 6am this morning (Wed 29 2012), a bunch of geeks eagerly awaiting the Raspberry Pi have killed the websites of both RS Components and Farnell</p>

<p>Why, you ask? Because the servers were not prepared for the influx of visitors that such an announcement brings.  Raspberry Pi themselves (a UK Foundation, like a Charity) were well prepared and are presently serving up a static page.</p>

<p>So, if you&rsquo;re running an eCommerce site, like Magento or osCommerce, and are warned by one of your suppliers, or your manufacturing department that you&rsquo;re launching a new product, be prepared.  Raspberry Pi certainly were and provided their suppliers with the information that they would be getting a huge amount of traffic, unfortunately those suppliers didn&rsquo;t listen hard enough.</p>

<p>This is to all intents a DDoS attack, but not an intentional attack.  Well done for keeping everyone updated via twitter though @raspberrypi, we know it isn&rsquo;t your fault.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting an Ecommerce Business,  in a Nutshell]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/starting-an-ecommerce-business-in-a-nutshell.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-25T16:19:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/starting-an-ecommerce-business-in-a-nutshell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>It may be obvious but after a discussion in the office we decided to put together a simple guideline for getting into e-commerce.</p>

<p>This is a list of things that you need to do in order to start selling from your own web site.</p>

<p><b>Get a Domain Name</b>
These are so cheap yet so fundamentally important it really should be one of the first things you do. Always ensure you can get the .com even if you intend to run from the .co.uk. If budget allows, buy all the top level domains you can afford simply to ensure they are yours &ndash; eg .com, .net, .co.uk, .org.uk, .info etc etc.</p>

<p><b>Find a Supplier</b>
The first thing you need is a supplier that you can buy from cheap enough to markup and earn a reasonable profit. Often this is one of the hardest bits, especially when you are starting out, finding a supplier that will agree to supply you can be tough. Be prepared to pay for stock up front initially and also to take on stock holdings.</p>

<p><b>You May need Retail Shop</b>
Even though you intend to make ecommerce the primary focus of your business, you may find some suppliers simply will not work with you if you do not have a retail shop. You need to double check this. Some times it is enough to have a few counters or a display rack in your warehouse, or some kind of &ldquo;trade counter&rdquo;. Other times you may really need a plate glass high street store front to get supply.</p>

<p><b>Decide on your Fulfillment</b>
You need to decide how you are going to fulfill customer orders. Are you going to do everything yourself? Are you going to use a fulfilment company to take care of this for you. You may find that your supplier(s) offer a drop shipping service where they will fulfill orders directly for you.</p>

<p><b>Decide on Shipping Methods and Charges</b>
Are you going to offer next day courier? Do you need to worry about insurance? Can you get away with Royal Mail? There are lots of things to consider when thinking about this aspect of the business.</p>

<p><b>Merchant Account</b>
If you want to take credit card payments, and any serious ecommerce business should &ndash; I definitely believe it is not enough to simply offer paypal &ndash; then you are going to need a merchant account. You will also need a business account &ndash; these do not have to be from the same bank, though they would have you believe they do. Shop around for the best rates &ndash; this can have a distinct impact on your bottom line, especially if margins are tight.</p>

<p><b>Payment Service Provider</b>
The payment service provider is the system that will actually allow customers to enter card details and will report transactions back to your merchant account. Again its worth shopping around for the best rates. Bear in mind you can only have one PSP per merchant account.</p>

<p><b>Choose your Shopping Cart Platform</b>
You need to choose which platform you want to base the site on. Choices generally include Magento which is without a doubt the most popular and powerful, Open Cart, osCommerce and derivatives are still popular though not really for new sites these days.</p>

<p><b>Get a Design</b>
Your choices for design range from using an off the shelf theme which is the cheapest option through to getting a full custom design created. If you are looking for templates, simply search google for {platform} template or {platform} theme. For example <a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?gcx=c&sourceid=chrome&client=ubuntu&channel=cs&ie=UTF-8&q=magento+templates">Magento Templates</a>.</p>

<p><b>Implement your design on your Cart</b>
If you have chosen a template then this is usually a case of installing that template and then making whatever customisations you want/need to make in order to brand the site with your logos, colour schemes etc. If you have chosen to go for a custom design then this is a much larger task but the end result is something that is exactly what you want. This is definitely something that Edmonds Commerce can help you with.</p>

<p><b>Load your Product Data</b>
You need to populate your store with product information. In its barest form this should include name, description, SKU, price and images. You may find getting the data is tricky. Alternatively you may be lucky enough to have suppliers that offer a full data feed and images for their products making this very easy. If you need to bridge the gap, getting a custom scraper built to get product data from your suppliers web sites can be a very cost effective solution.</p>

<p><b>Choose a Hosting Company</b>
Whilst your store is in development you will not generally need hosting. All of our client work is carried out on our local environment and staging server. It is only when the site is ready to go live that hosting is required. When choosing a host there is lots to consider. The first and most obvious is the hardware spec of your server. Are you going to go for the cheapest shared hosting, a VPS with reasonable power or a dedicated with large RAM and CPU resources?</p>

<p>The other big question that I think a lot of people do not consider in enough detail is the level of support you need from your hosting company. This has a dramatic impact on the price. It&rsquo;s possible to get a very powerful dedicated for around the £100 per month mark. However don&rsquo;t bother calling the support line at 2am on a Saturday Morning. If you need full phone support, especially 24/7 then expect to pay for this. I would also advise trying to ring the support lines at these kinds of times just to check that it really is there.</p>

<p><b>Launch Your Store</b>
You can launch your store as soon as you have product data and a means of payment set up and the store is accessible by visiting your domain name. There are different schools of thought on when you should launch. One is that you should not launch until your site is 100% finished and ready to impress your visitors with its sheer amazingness. Another school of thought is that you should launch ASAP to allow search engine spiders to get in and also to allow visitors to start trickling in allowing you to ensure your systems are all working properly before you switch on the more powerful marketing that will drive large traffic.</p>

<p><b>Register Self Employed</b>
If you are starting out in business you need to remember to register yourself as self employed with the revenue. Here is some more <a href="http://www.hmrc.gov.uk/selfemployed/register-selfemp.htm">info</a>.</p>

<p><b>Unleash the Marketing</b>
Your store will not succeed unless you have an effective marketing strategy in place. This could involve simply SEO + PPC or might extend through to TV adverts, billboards etc. The main differentiator is scale and budget. SEO is a long term strategy, it is unlikley you will achieve great results from the get go. PPC offers an instant response though the costs can be very high so maintaining profitability can be a concern.</p>

<p><b>Continuous Improvement</b>
Once your ecommerce business is up and running you should commit yourself to a continuous cycle of improvement. It&rsquo;s the only way to ensure you stay ahead of the game and achieve the level of progress you desire.</p>

<p>You need to plan on the fact that you will need to periodically upgrade your shopping cart. Especially if you are using Magento &ndash; it is being updated all the time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Merchant Centre/Froogle/Google Shopping/Base Changes, Problems and Solutions]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/google-merchant-centrefrooglegoogle-shoppingbase-changes-problems-and-solutions.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-11T17:05:20+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ecommerce/google-merchant-centrefrooglegoogle-shoppingbase-changes-problems-and-solutions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>So now that everyone uses Google Shopping, Google are making life difficult for the merchants and they all have to jump through hoops.</p>

<p>The current push from Google is enforcing some things that are very difficult for small companies to conform with :&ndash;</p>

<p><strong> * EAN Numbers</strong> &ndash; This is the BIG one, Google are making EAN Numbers required &ndash; for some retailers, they just don&rsquo;t exist, and for a lot of older or cheaper shopping cart systems, they don&rsquo;t have anywhere to enter them.
<strong> * Google Category</strong> &ndash; This is a fairly obvious one, they are attempting to enable shoppers to browse products and find a motherboard for instance with a 1156 socket rather than a CPU that fits an 1156 socket.  The answer is to add an extra field to a site&rsquo;s category system to map site categories to Google categories, or to restructure your products into google&rsquo;s categorisations.
<strong> * Product Images</strong> &ndash; Google are making this mandatory as well, which most people are getting round by using stock or illustration-only images.
<strong> * Availability</strong> &ndash; This one actually helps retailers, putting orderable products that are out of stock in front of customers, and is a small change to most scripts exporting to Google</p>

<p>The above changes are being phased in now but should your feed suddenly stop working, how big is the impact on your business?  Whilst some of the changes are little tweaks, such as the availability flag, others require fairly substantial changes in the back-end of many cart systems.  We are getting many aggrieved businesses contacting us asking for fast turnaround on their Google products feed as they are loosing money all the time that Google are rejecting their products.</p>

<p>What normally (given past changes) has been little tweaks for feeds to be compatible has lately become hours and hours of work both on developers and store-owners.  Are you ready to jump through the latest burning hoop Google is holding out for you?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
