<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Symfony on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/symfony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Symfony on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 19:53:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/symfony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging Forks for Composer</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/composer/merging-forks-for-composer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 19:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/composer/merging-forks-for-composer.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am really enjoying using Composer with a Symfony2 project that I am currently working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently though I found an issue where I am using the FOSRest Bundle to provide JSON API functionality. This in turn uses the
JMS/SerializerBundle to handle the actual encoding into JSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the JMS bundle converts camelCase to snake_case and I decided I really didn&amp;rsquo;t want that. I want my property and entity names to be the same across formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit of digging and I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/passkey1510/JMSSerializerBundle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this fork&lt;/a&gt; which features a fix for exactly this problem, brilliant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However on trying to get this to install with Composer I simply could not get it to work. Further investigation shows that the version of the JMS bundle that this fork does not meet
the minimum version requirements of the FOSRest bundle. Problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution in the end was to fork the JMSSerializerBundle Directly then pull this down locally. Once I had that locally I then added the fork with the fix I need as another remote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add passkey1510 git@github.com:passkey1510/JMSSerializerBundle.git
git merge remote/passkey1510/master
git push
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those three commands added the other fork as another remote allowing me to pull in the commits that feature the fix I need. Finally I pushed this back up to github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can now reference my fork in my composer.json file like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;repositories&amp;quot;: [
        {
            &amp;quot;url&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/JMSSerializerBundle.git&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;vcs&amp;quot;
        },
],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now running a &lt;code&gt;composer update --dev&lt;/code&gt; and composer successfully brought in my fork of the Serializerbundle with the extra fixes to allow the property names to stay in camelCase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is it, problem solved :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symonfy2 PHPStorm Project Setup</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symonfy2/symonfy2-phpstorm-project-setup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 19:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symonfy2/symonfy2-phpstorm-project-setup.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was going to write a nice summary of how to set up PHPStorm with a Symfony2 project.
There are a few things to be aware of such as getting the right code style set up so that your code follows the Symonfy2 coding standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens though a quick google found that there is already an excellent summary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kevwebdev.com/blog/setting-up-a-symfony2-project-in-phpstorm.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; which I suggest you have a read of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I would add to this are that you should probably install these PHPStorm plugins to get the best out of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin?pr=&amp;amp;pluginId=7219&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Symfony2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7320&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PHP Annotations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do all of this then you should have a really nice PHPStorm set up for working on your Symfony2 projects, enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylius E-Commerce based on Symfony</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/sylius-e-commerce-based-on-symfony.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 13:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/sylius-e-commerce-based-on-symfony.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As if there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new contender for the open source e-commerce crown, a platform called &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sylius.com/features&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sylius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;. The thing that makes this one especially interesting is that rather than being built from scratch it is based upon a very well established PHP framework called Symfony. Some would argue that Symfony is the &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; PHP framework alongside Zend Framework. In fact there are many frameworks however it would be fair to say that Symfony and Zend Framework are the most well established and up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basing an e-commerce platform upon an existing PHP framework has many advantages including transferrable skills, established best practice structure and also easier access to a wide range of functionality via library components and extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another e-commerce platform based upon a PHP framework. It is based upon Zend Framework - you might have heard of it - Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does look very much like Sylius is still quite a new offering and it can not boast the level of maturity and establishment that Magento has achieved. That said, things move quickly in this industry and who knows what will be top dog in the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are considering Sylius for your e-commerce website and would like to find a UK Sylius developer to work with then do get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony 2 Looking Good :)</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-2-looking-good.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 13:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-2-looking-good.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://symfony-reloaded.org/&#34;&gt;http://symfony-reloaded.org/&lt;/a&gt;, a quick run down on the latest version of Symfony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s looking really good, especially exciting is the promise of massive performance advantages (3 times faster than Zend!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony Training UK</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-training-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 11:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-training-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
After a few enquiries, we are looking into the possibility of setting up a Symfony training course based in Leeds in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At present this is not a firm plan but we are definitely looking into it and would really like some feedback on what kind of Symfony Training course you would like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course would likely be an introduction to the Symfony PHP framework, possibly going through the Jobeet sample site documentation which represents an excellent training framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage it is not totally clear what we would need to include in the course, especially if we can expect candidates to already be familiar and confident with object oriented PHP. One option is that we do another course which is purely focussed on the object oriented aspects of PHP, like a crash course of OO PHP for coders who have no or little experience of this style of coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested and would like to share with us your ideas and expectations for a UK Symfony course please do get in touch. We will take your ideas on board and keep your info on file so we can let you know as and when the course goes live.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony Moving to Github Source Control</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-moving-to-github-source-control.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 17:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-moving-to-github-source-control.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
My favourite PHP framework of the moment, Symfony, is now moving to my favourite version control system - Git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symfony-project.org/blog/2010/01/13/symfony-2-migration-to-git&#34;&gt;Symfony 2 Migration to Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its only for the version 2 release, but its a nice step forwards. Github is a really nice system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog post also mentions this great online Git book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://progit.org/&#34;&gt;Pro Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not actually come across that before, will be handy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony Developer UK</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-developer-uk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-developer-uk.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you are looking for a freelance PHP developer or company to help you create or maintain your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symfony-project.org/&#34;&gt;Symfony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; based PHP application then you have come to the right place. Edmonds Commerce specialise exclusively in PHP web development and are able to assist you with all kinds of Symfony requirements from editing or extending existing sites through to creating new Symfony based web sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symfony is an excellent choice as a PHP framework for building secure, scalable web sites to meet all kinds of different requirements. Utilising best practices, design patterns and the latest Object Oriented features of PHP 5, Symfony is a delight to work with and enables us to deliver high quality web applications in a fraction of the time required for a fully bespoke development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to conclude - if you are looking for a UK based &lt;strong&gt;Symfony Developer&lt;/strong&gt;, or any kind of PHP developer then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-symfony.html&#34;&gt;get in touch today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony Colour Scheme for Netbeans</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/symfony-colour-scheme-for-netbeans.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 21:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/symfony-colour-scheme-for-netbeans.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you work with Symfony, or would just like to ape the colour scheme they use on the symfony site - check out this Netbeans symfony colour scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://piwam.googlecode.com/files/SymfonyColorScheme.zip&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFYZWqUVXAXSrsE7rLejL-p99bnMw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/url?sa=D&amp;amp;q=http://piwam.googlecode.com/files/SymfonyColorScheme.zip&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFYZWqUVXAXSrsE7rLejL-p99bnMw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have got it working on Netbeans 6.8 (though it did crash when I imported it - it seems to be working fine)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony.. More Thoughts as I Continue to Play</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-more-thoughts-as-i-continue-to-play.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 17:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/symfony-more-thoughts-as-i-continue-to-play.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Continuing to play around with Symfony I am impressed with what I am seeing. It definitely has a feeling of &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; that seems to pervade the whole framework. It feels like without any effort you are going to be working in a secure way. It also seems to do a hell of a lot for you automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it relies heavily on command line scripts, there is even room for further automation by creating my own custom scripts to chain together symfony commands. In fact I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel like I wont need to do any PHP coding at all any more, just figure out the data model and run a custom shell script, and then issue the invoice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course its not going to be that easy. For one thing, creating YAML files is still taking some getting used to. And deciphering errors on the command line is also taking some getting used to, even though they are probably the same old error messages. One thing that tripped me up was a typo in one of my YAML files that sent Propel looking for a non existant class when running the data-load command. That&amp;rsquo;s one of those &amp;ldquo;gotchas&amp;rdquo; that is bound to happen, but being so green it stumped me for a few minutes until I spotted the errant extra &amp;lsquo;l&amp;rsquo; in one part of the YAML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now have some nice generated class structures with data models, and Netbeans&amp;rsquo;s autocomplete is making life even easier for me, suggesting object property getters as I type so I don&amp;rsquo;t even need to refer back to the schema to double check column names, cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I have noticed is the use of good old fashioned procedural style functions. This is good, because PHP lets you do this and why should you have to have absolutely everything inside a class when all you need is a little function that you can use here and there. Namely the template system uses functions like &lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;?php include_metas()?&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;?php echo url_for(&#39;module/action&#39;)?&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;. I like this. I&amp;rsquo;m not a Java developer, I&amp;rsquo;m a PHP developer, so we can do this kind of thing :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with Symfony</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/playing-with-symfony.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 17:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/symfony/playing-with-symfony.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to play with Symfony for ages. I have played with Zend Framework and have also created my own light weight framework (which I will probably continue to use for light weight / rapid development projects or where I am working with a designer and need to keep the complexity to an absolute minimum). So I Checked Symfony 1.2 out of SVN and started with the quickstart guide and using the Jobeet tutorials as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that is weird for me is creating my DB schema in YML files. Thankfully Netbeans seems to be helping me out by handling YML properly, syntax highlighting etc. Another great thing that I have found are these awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://andreiabohner.wordpress.com/category/cheat-sheet/&#34;&gt;cheatsheets&lt;/a&gt;, especially the DB schema cheatsheet which tells me pretty much everything I need to know in once nice colour coded page :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future I would like to use MySQL workbench and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trac.symfony-project.org/wiki/SymfonyYamlMyqlWorkbenchPlugin&#34;&gt;Symfony YAML MySQL Workbench&lt;/a&gt; exporter plugin to make this process more streamlined, but for now I am going to try to get my head around the native YAML syntax. I always believe in learning to do things in a text editor first and then looking to to automate once I have at least a basic understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>