<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clear on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/clear/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clear on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 19:32:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/clear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Trigger Basic Auth Popup in Chrome</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/trigger-basic-auth-popup-in-chrome.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 19:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/chrome/trigger-basic-auth-popup-in-chrome.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Chrome, if you have already authenticated with a site using Basic Authentiation (a Web Server level authentication) then you will have probably realised that once you are authenticated, Chrome does not continuously prompt you for the details, and that is a good thing.
However, in a scenario where perhaps you want to authenticate as a different user or otherwise re enter the details then it can be tricky to figure out how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple enough, you can retrigger this prompt by putting your username@ the url and the pop up will be shown again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.somedomain.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;becomes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://username@www.somedomain.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Merged CSS Clear Not Working &#43; Solution</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-merged-css-clear-not-working-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 18:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-merged-css-clear-not-working-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are having an issue with Magento and the optional Merge CSS Files (beta) turned on and it not updating with recent CSS changes, you may appreciate this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other cached elements that are stored in var/cache, Magento stores the cached and minified CSS files in media/css&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you simply delete the contents of this folder, your CSS changes should kick in as Magento is forced to rebuild these files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an option in cache management to flush CSS storage but for some reason this wasn&amp;rsquo;t working for me. Could be a permissions issue or something else I am not sure, we simply needed to get this change implemented (emergency live site fix) so flushing this folder manually did the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope it helps someone else looking for Magento merged CSS clear not working, Magento CSS cache, Magento CSS Files beta&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>