<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upgrade on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/upgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upgrade on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 19:32:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading from Fedora 19 to 20 using FedUp</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/upgrading-from-fedora-19-to-20-using-fedup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 19:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/upgrading-from-fedora-19-to-20-using-fedup.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to upgrade to the latest version because why not, its the first Friday of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FedUp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; which explains how to use the tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spotted the note about the 19-20 upgrade not working unless you install the bleeding edge version of the tool so thats to do first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum -y --enablerepo=updates-testing install fedup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need to make sure that your system is fully up to date so lets do that. Once this is done you probably want to reboot to be on the safe side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum -y update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that is all done then you need to run the fedup command itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum -y update fedup fedora-release
sudo fedup --network 20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I did this though and had an issue with RMPFusion. To fix that you need to run this command, then run the fedup command again:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo rpm --import /etc/pki/rpm-gpg/RPM-GPG-KEY-rpmfusion-nonfree-fedora-20
sudo fedup --network 20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once fedup completes successfully you can reboot and will have an upgrade option as your first GRUB option when booting up. Select that to start the main upgrade.
It takes a while, make a brew or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you log in, you will no doubt notice some of your Gnome Shell Extensions are not working. Thankfully the process of upgrading these is pretty painless, just head over to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.gnome.org/local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://extensions.gnome.org/local/&lt;/a&gt; and you will see all your extensions. Any that are not compatible with your new version of Gnome Shell will have OUTDATED written where the on/off slider usually resides. Those with upgraded versions will have an upgrade button. Click that for each one, accepting the prompt.
When that&amp;rsquo;s done, refresh the page and you should see all your upgraded extensions are now working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me the only one I&amp;rsquo;m really going to miss is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/352/middle-click-to-close-in-overview/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Close in Overview&lt;/a&gt; which is really handy, hopefully will be updated soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento 1.8 released</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-8-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 10:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-8-released.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I got a notification through that Magento 1.8 had finally been released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been in beta since alpha since April, and contains server fixes that a lot of people have been waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important one for UK vendors is that the rounding issue in tax calculations has been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also improvements to caching and database performance. The full release notes can be seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/knowledge-base/entry/ce-18-later-release-notes&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are issues that have affected merchants since that change in the VAT rate, so we would recommend upgrading for everyone at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ongoing Magento Support and Consultation</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/featured/ongoing-magento-supports-and-consultation.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buckleylondon.com&#34;&gt;Buckley&lt;/a&gt; is a UK based company that prides itself on designing and manufacturing high quality fashion &amp;amp; costume jewellery at competitive prices since its inception in 1989. The company has rapidly expanded into a worldwide brand with jewellery collections available to a vast market of over 200 stores including more than 60 Duty Free shops and 120 airlines . We are glad to hear that Buckley has contributed over US$3 million to the funding of the Royal British Legion through the sale of its elegant Buckley Poppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The development idea:&lt;/h3&gt;
Buckley Jewellery was initially launched using Wordpress and used an ecommerce package called ShopperPress. As the company grew and they started to expand their business to Duty Free shops and airlines, it became apparent that WordPress could not provide enough support for their complex modifications and customisations. This is when the idea of re-building the site in Magento was suggested.

We started working with Buckley in 2011 and have been providing them with continuous support since then. Some of the main requirements were broadly to do the following:

&lt;h3&gt;1. Magento implementation and migration from previous platform&lt;/h3&gt;
We installed and configured Magento onto Buckley’s chosen hosting platform and installed the essential extensions such as shipping and payment gateways including PayPal and SagePay. We also migrated all of their products, customers and orders database from the previous platform into Magento. A clean and clear design was created and customised to their specification and we have been tweaking it per their needs and requirements ever since.

&lt;h3&gt;2. Magento training&lt;/h3&gt;
After successfully migrating the site to Magento, we did an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/magento-training-course-details/&#34;&gt;on-site one day introduction course&lt;/a&gt; with Buckley, where we gave them the background understanding and some useful skills required to get the most out of their new Magento store. 
Here is a quote from Mark at Buckley Jewellry: “&lt;em&gt;The day was extremely useful with just the right amount of content to set us on our way&lt;/em&gt;.”

&lt;h3&gt;3. Magento upgrade and Magento security patch applied&lt;/h3&gt;
It is important to make sure that your Magento site is up to date. We have done two upgrades for Buckley so far and they all went really well.The upgrades were done in three separate phrases - exploratory upgrade, bugs fixing and deployment to live. We hit a few bugs but managed to fix them within hours. 
Around mid July 2012, a serious security hole was found in Zend Framework which allow hackers to gain access to mysql server credentials. A patch was quickly applied to Buckley live store using a nice Bash script we put together. We offered this free security patching service to all Magento sites with a voluntary charity donation and had a lot of sites take us up on this offer.

&lt;h3&gt;4. Ongoing support&lt;/h3&gt;
Buckley have joined our retainer scheme where we provide them with daily maintenance supports, bugs fixing and consultation services. Various &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/magento/edmonds-commerce-successfully-leads-firesale-on-buckley-jewellery/&#34;&gt;firesale promotions&lt;/a&gt;, extensions and marketing exercises were installed and configured into their website.
Recently we had migrated Buckley and its sister site &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.attwoodandsawyer.com&#34;&gt;Attwood &amp; Sawyer&lt;/a&gt; to a dedicated server, which is faster, more secured and gives them better control over the sites.
Buckley also engages in designing beautiful vintage inspired pieces in the silver &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bouton.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Bouton&lt;/a&gt; rages and we are currently managing the merger process of Bouton into Buckley main sites. 

&lt;h3&gt;Testimonial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a quote from Mark Noble, IT Manager at Buckley Jewellery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Buckley Jewellery originally approached &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk&#34;&gt;Edmonds Commerce&lt;/a&gt; to take our existing site and develop it onto a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/platforms/magento/&#34;&gt;Magento platform&lt;/a&gt;. Since this first project we have used Joseph and his team for a further website and additional work to develop &amp;amp; expand our ecommerce business. The offer of installing the Magento patch across our websites was typical of a company who provide an honest and refreshing approach to website design. I would not hesitate to recommend Edmonds Commerce for any ecommerce development and advice”. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/screenshot-thumb1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 17:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of our clients use &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce&#34;&gt;osCommerce&lt;/a&gt; for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last release for PHP 5.2 was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;version 5.2.16 released back in 2010&lt;/a&gt;. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on &lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us&#34;&gt;get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce&#34;&gt;osCommerce&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/opencart&#34;&gt;OpenCart&lt;/a&gt;. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL 5.1 to 5.5 Migration</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-5-1-to-5-5-migration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 11:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-5-1-to-5-5-migration.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to pretty much every source there&amp;rsquo;s only one sensible way to migrate from 5.0, 5.1 or 5.2 to 5.5 of mysql (or mariadb/percona for that matter), and it&amp;rsquo;s not pretty (for a server with only two active magento installations for instance, this will take about 3 hours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is that you have to do an sql dump and restore.  This does take an age but does at least provide the reassurance that you are going to have nice clean databases after the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the commands are :-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;mysqldump --all-databases --routines --events &amp;gt; fulldump.sql
mysqldump mysql --tables user &amp;gt; users.sql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then upgrade mysql binaries to 5.5 and empty the database directory - such as /var/lib/mysql and start mysql with it&amp;rsquo;s script (e.g. /etc/init.d/mysql start).   Note, if you&amp;rsquo;re using a distribution that doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with start scripts, you may want to run mysql_install as root before starting mysql however you start it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the following will restore the databases and users :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;mysql -u root &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# add -p if you set up a default password when upgrading/installing 5.5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;se&#34;&gt;\r&lt;/span&gt; mysql
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; users.sql
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; fulldump.sql
FLUSH PRIVILEGES&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;se&#34;&gt;\q&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHPStorm 5 Released</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 09:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Edmonds Commerce we were staunch Netbeans users for years but we always struggled with large scale projects (&lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento/&#34; title=&#34;Magento Platform Overview&#34;&gt;Magento&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you) meaning that Netbeans would sometimes really crawl as it tried to reindex thousands of PHP files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a recent upgrade of our Linux desktop environment to the Mate edition of Linux Mint 13, Netbeans seemed to perform even worse and had a few bugs as well. At the same time we had been evaluating other IDE options including Eclipse and Zend Studio (which we all have free licences for thanks to being Zend Certified Developers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end though, the one we tried that really impressed was PHPStorm. It isn&amp;rsquo;t free open source but it isn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive, especially considering it is perhaps the single most important and highly used tool of a professional PHP developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a new version has come out. Downloading and upgrading took all of 5 minutes and we are now going to enjoy better performance and some nice new features. I have yet to really test out the new version so I can&amp;rsquo;t really report on them but they look good. You can read about all the new features in version 5 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/whatsnew/&#34; title=&#34;PHPStorm 5 Features&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Admin Menu not working after Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-menu-not-working-after-upgrade.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 09:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-menu-not-working-after-upgrade.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wondering why your Magento admin menu is not showing up after upgrading your live Magento store?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all attempts to get to a particular admin page with the exception of the dashboard proved abortive, this could be because there is a conflict between the Magento function that merges all Javascript files and the Apache URL rewrite.  This could be fixed by turning off this Magento function, and your can run the script below to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34; data-lang=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;your_magento_database_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;core_config_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;SET&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;0&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;core_config_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;dev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;js&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;merge_files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress Upgrade Bash Script</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/wordpress/wordpress-upgrade-bash-script.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 11:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/wordpress/wordpress-upgrade-bash-script.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you would like to upgrade wordpress directly on the command line using bash then you might like this little script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ch&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# This is a script to upgrade wordpress.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Put it in your wordpress document root (the folder that contains wp-config.php)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# chmod +x to make executable&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# ./wp-upgrade.bash to run&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Originally here: http://yabfog.com/blog/2011/12/12/wordpress-update-bash-script&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;DIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; -P &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt; dirname &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;si&#34;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;BASH_SOURCE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[0]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;si&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;pwd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;TMPDIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/tmp/wp-upgrader
mkdir -p &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$TMPDIR&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;WPDIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$TMPDIR&lt;/span&gt;/wordpress
mkdir -p &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$WPDIR&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$TMPDIR&lt;/span&gt;
rm -rf latest.zip ./wordpress &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Clean up from the last run&lt;/span&gt;
wget -nd http://wordpress.org/latest.zip
unzip latest.zip
mv &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$DIR&lt;/span&gt;/wp-config.php &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$DIR&lt;/span&gt;/.wp-config.php.backup &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Stash your configuration someplace safe&lt;/span&gt;
rm &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$DIR&lt;/span&gt;/*.&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;txt,html,php&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Delete the old install&lt;/span&gt;
rm -rf &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$DIR&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;wp-admin,wp-includes&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Delete more. Don&amp;#39;t delete plugins or themes.&lt;/span&gt;
cp -aR &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$WPDIR&lt;/span&gt;/* &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$DIR&lt;/span&gt;/
mv &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$DIR&lt;/span&gt;/.wp-config.php.backup  &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$DIR&lt;/span&gt;/wp-config.php &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Restore the configuration&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# You may not need the last two lines. I like to give my web server the ability to write files.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#chown -R .www-data $DIR/*.php $DIR/wp-admin $DIR/wp-includes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#chmod -R g+w $DIR/*.php $DIR/wp-includes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don&amp;rsquo;t use on a live site or anything like that, but for local development its a quick way to upgrade the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script was originally &lt;a href=&#34;http://yabfog.com/blog/2011/12/12/wordpress-update-bash-script&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; I simply edited it a little&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Post-upgrade: Illegal scheme supplied, only alphanumeric characters are permitted &#43;SOLUTION</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-post-upgrade-illegal-scheme-supplied-only-alphanumeric-characters-are-permitted-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 10:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-post-upgrade-illegal-scheme-supplied-only-alphanumeric-characters-are-permitted-solution.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So one of our customer&amp;rsquo;s sites started throwing this error message immediately following an upgrade.
&lt;code&gt;Illegal scheme supplied, only alphanumeric characters are permitted&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out 1.6.2.0 doesn&amp;rsquo;t like anything other than a-z and 0-9 in the store run code and the customer in question had underscores (_) in the store run code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple fix was to strip it out and alter the url to store code logic to match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps someone else out there.  As to why someone at magento thought this was a good idea is beyond me though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento 1.6.2 Released</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-6-2-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 18:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-6-2-released.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Magento have released the latest version of Magento CE (community edition), 1.6.2.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major interest to most of our clients will be the refactoring of the indexing process to prevent duplicate indexing processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with that is a nice list of fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to upgrade your Magento store to the latest version simply &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to disable netbeans auto-complete of method variables </title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/how-to-disable-netbeans-auto-complete-of-method-variables.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 13:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/how-to-disable-netbeans-auto-complete-of-method-variables.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a new feature in Netbeans that tries to auto fill the variables for methods and functions in PHP. Whilst this may be something that is a time saver for some, it often gets these wrong, and if you are using descriptive variables in the method then these are overwritten if you have a variable of the same type above your method call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully there is a way to disable this feature and revert to the old ways. In netbeans go to Tools -&amp;gt; Options -&amp;gt; Editor -&amp;gt; Code Completion and select Language PHP. From there you can deselect the Use Smart Parameters Pre-Filling and netbeans will work the way it used to&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Upgrade for Love My Frames</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/magento-upgrade-for-love-my-frames.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 10:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/magento-upgrade-for-love-my-frames.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Magento Upgrade with Custom Modules Rewrite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project was to upgrade a store from 1.3 to 1.5, without losing the functionality of the site. The old version had had its core files modified, requiring a forensic examination of them in order to find and extract what had been changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Love My Frames&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love My Frames is run by highly trained technicians with over 40 years&amp;rsquo; optical experience, offering the kind of personal service you would normally expect from a high street opticians. Offering the best for considerably less, professional service and door-to-door delivery, they give their customers the ultimate shopping experience online plus the opportunity to purchase the &lt;a href=”http://www.lovemyframes.com/” &gt;very latest designs at a great price&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/lovemyframes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project asked for a clean install and then rewrite of the existing store. The biggest part of the project was taking the existing layered navigation and rewriting it to work on all pages with a custom design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abordage - Magento Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/abordage-magento-upgrade.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 17:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/abordage-magento-upgrade.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Abordage – Magento Upgrade and multi language implementation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abordage required a Magento Upgrade from 1.3 to the latest version. This was to ensure future compatibility with extensions and add new functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Abordage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abordage specialises in the production of quality &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abordage.com/&#34;&gt;scale wooden ship models&lt;/a&gt; and matching display cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/abordage-600x432.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing multiple languages can be interesting as it has to integrate well with existing site configuration. The implementation used works well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aston&#39;s of London - Magento Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/astons-of-london-magento-upgrade.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 17:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/astons-of-london-magento-upgrade.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Aston&#39;s of London – Magento Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aston&amp;rsquo;s of London required that their Magento site be upgraded from 1.3 CE to the latest version. This is required so that new functionality can be easily introduced on to the site when required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Aston&#39;s of London&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aston&amp;rsquo;s of London is an eCommerce company specialising in the sale of &lt;a href=&#34;http://astonsoflondon.co.uk/&#34;&gt;luxury jewellery, comfort items and gifts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/astonsoflondon1-600x450.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was a standard upgrade from an older version of Magento to current dealing with issues related to the sites theme and extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over Board - Magento Migration</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 16:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Over Board – Migration to Magento from OSCommerce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board wished to move away from OSCommerce due to limitations encountered while using OSCommerce. Using Magento allows the company the flexibility they desired. This project involved implementing a new site design as well as importing data from the old OSCommerce site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Over Board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board are an eCommerce company specialising in the sales of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.over-board.co.uk/&#34;&gt;water proof device cases and bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/overboards-300x224.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was terrific as it demonstrates the ability to move away from a relativity old system to a new system and at the same time enabling a lot more functionality and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>