<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upgrade on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/upgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upgrade on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 15:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Keybinding to Dnf Upgrade and Shutdown to Gnome Shell</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/add-keybinding-to-dnf-upgrade-and-shutdown-to-gnome-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/add-keybinding-to-dnf-upgrade-and-shutdown-to-gnome-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fedora I prefer to apply updates just before shutting down so that next time I boot up the updates will be in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me this seems like the best way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make that easier I also then create a keybinding so that I can hit &lt;code&gt;[Start]+[q]&lt;/code&gt; to trigger the upgrade/shutdown process in a terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a lazy developer I prefer to have things automated and so here is a bash command to set this up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&#39;EOF&#39; | bash 
echo &amp;quot;setting up keybinding&amp;quot;;
keybindingsPath=&amp;quot;/org/gnome/settings-daemon/plugins/media-keys/custom-keybindings&amp;quot;
custom0path=&amp;quot;$keybindingsPath/custom0&amp;quot;
dconf write $custom0path/binding &amp;quot;&#39;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;q&#39;&amp;quot;
dconf write $custom0path/command &amp;quot;&#39;gnome-terminal --command=\&amp;quot;sudo bash -c \&#39;dnf -y upgrade; shutdown now\&#39;\&amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot;
dconf write $custom0path/name &amp;quot;&#39;upgrade and shutdown&#39;&amp;quot;
c0=&amp;quot;&#39;/org/gnome/settings-daemon/plugins/media-keys/custom-keybindings/custom0/&#39;&amp;quot;
gsettings set org.gnome.settings-daemon.plugins.media-keys custom-keybindings &amp;quot;[$c0]&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;

Done

try hitting [Start] + [q]

&amp;quot;
EOF
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;just copy/paste into an open terminal window to set this up&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading from Fedora 19 to 20 using FedUp</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/upgrading-from-fedora-19-to-20-using-fedup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 19:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/fedora/upgrading-from-fedora-19-to-20-using-fedup.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to upgrade to the latest version because why not, its the first Friday of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FedUp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; which explains how to use the tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spotted the note about the 19-20 upgrade not working unless you install the bleeding edge version of the tool so thats to do first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum -y --enablerepo=updates-testing install fedup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need to make sure that your system is fully up to date so lets do that. Once this is done you probably want to reboot to be on the safe side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum -y update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that is all done then you need to run the fedup command itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum -y update fedup fedora-release
sudo fedup --network 20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I did this though and had an issue with RMPFusion. To fix that you need to run this command, then run the fedup command again:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo rpm --import /etc/pki/rpm-gpg/RPM-GPG-KEY-rpmfusion-nonfree-fedora-20
sudo fedup --network 20
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once fedup completes successfully you can reboot and will have an upgrade option as your first GRUB option when booting up. Select that to start the main upgrade.
It takes a while, make a brew or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you log in, you will no doubt notice some of your Gnome Shell Extensions are not working. Thankfully the process of upgrading these is pretty painless, just head over to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.gnome.org/local/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://extensions.gnome.org/local/&lt;/a&gt; and you will see all your extensions. Any that are not compatible with your new version of Gnome Shell will have OUTDATED written where the on/off slider usually resides. Those with upgraded versions will have an upgrade button. Click that for each one, accepting the prompt.
When that&amp;rsquo;s done, refresh the page and you should see all your upgraded extensions are now working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me the only one I&amp;rsquo;m really going to miss is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/352/middle-click-to-close-in-overview/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Close in Overview&lt;/a&gt; which is really handy, hopefully will be updated soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>osCommerce PHP 5.2 Upgrade - You Really Should Get onto PHP 5.3 ASAP</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 17:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/oscommerce/oscommerce-php-5-2-upgrade-you-really-should-get-onto-php-5-3-asap.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of our clients use &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce&#34;&gt;osCommerce&lt;/a&gt; for their online store. osCommerce was very popular a few years ago and to date still powers a really large number of stores. Due to a variety of technical reasons, many osCommerce stores are still hosting on PHP version 5.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of PHP is 5.4 and 5.5 is due out fairly soon. Most hosting companies will now regard PHP 5.3 to be the minimum version they will support. By switching to PHP 5.3 they get better performance and better security. Unfortunately if you are running an osCommerce store and your hosting company decides to upgrade PHP then you might find that your entire store stops working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first instinct here is to get your store back online as quickly as possible and that is entirely understandable. These days though we really think that osCommerce store owners should be running on PHP 5.3. It is entirely possible to do this and does not necessarily entail a large amount of work depending on which contributions you are running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last release for PHP 5.2 was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php.net/archive/2010.php#id2010-12-16-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;version 5.2.16 released back in 2010&lt;/a&gt;. In software terms that is really quite a long time ago and really underlines how much of an issue this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about some of the performance gains of switching to PHP 5.3 or greater on &lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/features.gc.performance-considerations.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like some help getting your osCommerce store working on an up to date version of PHP then &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us&#34;&gt;get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course another option is to think about moving away from osCommerce and onto a more up to date platform such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/oscommerce&#34;&gt;osCommerce&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/opencart&#34;&gt;OpenCart&lt;/a&gt;. If you are thinking of ugprading then 5.3 compatability will be a bonus. If you are not thinking of upgrading platform any time soon though you really do need to schedule in an upgrade to PHP 5.3 at the earliest opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL 5.1 to 5.5 Migration</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-5-1-to-5-5-migration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 11:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/mysql/mysql-5-1-to-5-5-migration.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to pretty much every source there&amp;rsquo;s only one sensible way to migrate from 5.0, 5.1 or 5.2 to 5.5 of mysql (or mariadb/percona for that matter), and it&amp;rsquo;s not pretty (for a server with only two active magento installations for instance, this will take about 3 hours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is that you have to do an sql dump and restore.  This does take an age but does at least provide the reassurance that you are going to have nice clean databases after the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the commands are :-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;mysqldump --all-databases --routines --events &amp;gt; fulldump.sql
mysqldump mysql --tables user &amp;gt; users.sql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then upgrade mysql binaries to 5.5 and empty the database directory - such as /var/lib/mysql and start mysql with it&amp;rsquo;s script (e.g. /etc/init.d/mysql start).   Note, if you&amp;rsquo;re using a distribution that doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with start scripts, you may want to run mysql_install as root before starting mysql however you start it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the following will restore the databases and users :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;mysql -u root &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# add -p if you set up a default password when upgrading/installing 5.5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;se&#34;&gt;\r&lt;/span&gt; mysql
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; users.sql
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; fulldump.sql
FLUSH PRIVILEGES&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;se&#34;&gt;\q&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHPStorm 5 Released</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 09:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/phpstorm/phpstorm-5-released.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Edmonds Commerce we were staunch Netbeans users for years but we always struggled with large scale projects (&lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/platforms/magento/&#34; title=&#34;Magento Platform Overview&#34;&gt;Magento&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you) meaning that Netbeans would sometimes really crawl as it tried to reindex thousands of PHP files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a recent upgrade of our Linux desktop environment to the Mate edition of Linux Mint 13, Netbeans seemed to perform even worse and had a few bugs as well. At the same time we had been evaluating other IDE options including Eclipse and Zend Studio (which we all have free licences for thanks to being Zend Certified Developers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end though, the one we tried that really impressed was PHPStorm. It isn&amp;rsquo;t free open source but it isn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive, especially considering it is perhaps the single most important and highly used tool of a professional PHP developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a new version has come out. Downloading and upgrading took all of 5 minutes and we are now going to enjoy better performance and some nice new features. I have yet to really test out the new version so I can&amp;rsquo;t really report on them but they look good. You can read about all the new features in version 5 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/whatsnew/&#34; title=&#34;PHPStorm 5 Features&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Admin Menu not working after Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-menu-not-working-after-upgrade.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 09:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-admin-menu-not-working-after-upgrade.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wondering why your Magento admin menu is not showing up after upgrading your live Magento store?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all attempts to get to a particular admin page with the exception of the dashboard proved abortive, this could be because there is a conflict between the Magento function that merges all Javascript files and the Apache URL rewrite.  This could be fixed by turning off this Magento function, and your can run the script below to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34; data-lang=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;your_magento_database_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;core_config_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;SET&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;0&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;core_config_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;dev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;js&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;merge_files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento 1.6.2 Released</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-6-2-released.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 18:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-6-2-released.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Magento have released the latest version of Magento CE (community edition), 1.6.2.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major interest to most of our clients will be the refactoring of the indexing process to prevent duplicate indexing processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with that is a nice list of fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to upgrade your Magento store to the latest version simply &lt;a href=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to disable netbeans auto-complete of method variables </title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/how-to-disable-netbeans-auto-complete-of-method-variables.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 13:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/netbeans/how-to-disable-netbeans-auto-complete-of-method-variables.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a new feature in Netbeans that tries to auto fill the variables for methods and functions in PHP. Whilst this may be something that is a time saver for some, it often gets these wrong, and if you are using descriptive variables in the method then these are overwritten if you have a variable of the same type above your method call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully there is a way to disable this feature and revert to the old ways. In netbeans go to Tools -&amp;gt; Options -&amp;gt; Editor -&amp;gt; Code Completion and select Language PHP. From there you can deselect the Use Smart Parameters Pre-Filling and netbeans will work the way it used to&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Upgrade for Love My Frames</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/magento-upgrade-for-love-my-frames.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 10:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/magento-upgrade-for-love-my-frames.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Magento Upgrade with Custom Modules Rewrite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project was to upgrade a store from 1.3 to 1.5, without losing the functionality of the site. The old version had had its core files modified, requiring a forensic examination of them in order to find and extract what had been changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Love My Frames&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love My Frames is run by highly trained technicians with over 40 years&amp;rsquo; optical experience, offering the kind of personal service you would normally expect from a high street opticians. Offering the best for considerably less, professional service and door-to-door delivery, they give their customers the ultimate shopping experience online plus the opportunity to purchase the &lt;a href=”http://www.lovemyframes.com/” &gt;very latest designs at a great price&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/lovemyframes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project asked for a clean install and then rewrite of the existing store. The biggest part of the project was taking the existing layered navigation and rewriting it to work on all pages with a custom design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abordage - Magento Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/abordage-magento-upgrade.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 17:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/abordage-magento-upgrade.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Abordage – Magento Upgrade and multi language implementation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abordage required a Magento Upgrade from 1.3 to the latest version. This was to ensure future compatibility with extensions and add new functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Abordage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abordage specialises in the production of quality &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abordage.com/&#34;&gt;scale wooden ship models&lt;/a&gt; and matching display cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/abordage-600x432.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing multiple languages can be interesting as it has to integrate well with existing site configuration. The implementation used works well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over Board - Magento Migration</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 16:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/over-board-magento-migration.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Over Board – Migration to Magento from OSCommerce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board wished to move away from OSCommerce due to limitations encountered while using OSCommerce. Using Magento allows the company the flexibility they desired. This project involved implementing a new site design as well as importing data from the old OSCommerce site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Over Board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over Board are an eCommerce company specialising in the sales of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.over-board.co.uk/&#34;&gt;water proof device cases and bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/overboards-300x224.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was terrific as it demonstrates the ability to move away from a relativity old system to a new system and at the same time enabling a lot more functionality and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Mayhew</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 14:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/portfolio/kevin-mayhew.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Magento Site Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Mayhew Ltd. required their Magento site to be upgraded from Enterprise 1.7 to the current release. They are looking to do this because the current site is having problems with some of the functionality which can only be correct by upgrading an extension and the extensions latest version is not compatibility with 1.7. 1.7 is also preventing them from improving the site and adding functionality. This mainly involved updating their site templates to function correctly the the new release as well as resolving issues related to old/new extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Kevin Mayhew&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Mayhew is a Christian religious product and music retailer, Christian church resource supplier and Christian book publisher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://edmondscommerce.github.io/images/kevinmayhew1-300x216.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project went really well with the pushing to live been successful. With the site now running the latest version of Magento the company can look forward toward to expanding the functionality of the site as well as resolving issues the old site was having.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Git Install 1.7.5 and Why</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/ubuntu-git-install-1-7-4-and-why.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 12:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/git/ubuntu-git-install-1-7-4-and-why.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
If you use Git a lot, you probably want to run the latest version. Scroll down for some reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard repository version for Ubuntu is 1.7.1, the current latest is 1.7.5 and there are some significant differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How to Upgrade Git&lt;/h2&gt;
To get 1.7.5 on Ubuntu without too much messing about you can do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;1. Set up this PPA:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:pdoes/ppa/ubuntu

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2. Now run an aptitude update and upgrade git&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
sudo apt-get update
sudo aptitude upgrade git

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;3. Now check your git version&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
git --version

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Full Script for the lazy&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:pdoes/ppa/ubuntu &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo aptitude upgrade &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git --version

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why Upgrade Git?&lt;/h2&gt;
We have been having lots of merge hassles casued purely by white space changes. Apparently with 1.7.4 new recursive merge strategies came into play that should alleviate this pain and make merging a lot less hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Merge Ignore Whitespace&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
git merge -s recursive -Xignore-space-change $BRANCH_NAME

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less hassle equals more productive and happier developers :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento 1.4.2.0 Released - Upgrade Magento to 1.4.2.0</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-4-2-0-released-upgrade-magento-to-1-4-2-0.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 14:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-1-4-2-0-released-upgrade-magento-to-1-4-2-0.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Magento have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/blog/comments/magento-ce-version-1420-stable-now-available/&#34;&gt;just released&lt;/a&gt; the latest version of Magento Community Edition: 1.4.2.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This continues the 1.4 branch of Magento. If you are still running Magento 1.3 or earlier you definitely need to be upgrading onto the 1.4 branch, there are so many improvements. Now that this version has come out there has never been a better time to upgrade your store to the 1.4 branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help getting your store upgraded, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch with us&lt;/a&gt; - we have done loads of upgrades from the smooth to the painful - but all have been successful in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major highlights are the default installation of The Find feed functionality. No doubt this is thanks to a sizeable donation from The Find, but hey it won&amp;rsquo;t do any harm and might even bring in some more sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing to note is that the awaited new version of Magento Connect Manager has not been included in the final release despite being in the release candidates. Presumably some critical issues were found with the system so they decided not to roll it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things of note in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magentocommerce.com/download/release_notes#Release%20Notes%20-%20Magento%201.4.2.0%20%28December%208,%202010%29&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; we spotted are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgraded Zend Framework to version 1.10.8&lt;/strong&gt;
Not the very latest of Zend Framework (1.11.1 as of writing) but a more up to date version. Zend Framework is the foundation of Magento.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Invoices, Shipment, Credit Memos added possibility to show admin comments at user frontend (checkboxes “Visible on Frontend” in admin interface&lt;/strong&gt;
This is a familiar feature on other carts such as osCommerce. The ability to set some comments as customer visible so they can track the process of their order from their account area on the front of the web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Shopping Cart API&lt;/strong&gt;
Not yet detailed in the API documentation, presumably this will allow programmatic creation of shopping cart sessions so you can get a shopping basket filled up via an external system and then pipe the customer through straight into the checkout process. This will open up all kinds of customisation possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Added functionality to disable dashboard charts in backend&lt;/strong&gt;
This will save on server resources and page load times in the admin for those hosting on less powerful environments or simply looking for the best performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Added favicon manager under System &amp;gt; Configuration &amp;gt; Design &amp;gt; HTML Head&lt;/strong&gt;
Such a common mistake with Magento sites is to leave the standard favicon in there - the famous red M. This should make it very easy to set a custom favicon (though it was never that hard in the first place).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrade your Magento&lt;/strong&gt;
If you want to get your Magento store upgraded to the latest version, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento Upgrades - Need your Magento Site Upgraded?</title>
      <link>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-upgrades-need-your-magento-site-upgraded.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 13:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-upgrades-need-your-magento-site-upgraded.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are running an older version of Magento on your site then it is definitely worth thinking about getting the site upgraded to the latest version of Magento. Upgrading your Magento site means that you will benefit from all the latest features and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;strong&gt;Magento&lt;/strong&gt; is still a relatively new platform, the new releases are making significant steps forward, tackling short comings such as speed and also generally improving the interface and making things easier to work with. This means that you should really be upgrading your Magento site on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be challenges upgrading an existing Magento site though. Often the theme, especially if it is heavily customised, can not be used directly on an upgraded Magento site and will need to be modified accordingly. Other functional customisations might need to be tweaked to get them working properly on the upgraded version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edmonds Commerce have now upgraded a large number of Magento sites and we have built up a lot of experience and know how allowing us to tackle pretty much any Magento upgrade project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like us to upgrade your Magento site, please &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch with us today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>