<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dallamore on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/dallamore/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dallamore on Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 09:27:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tags/dallamore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>When Forum Spamming Goes Bad..</title>
      <link>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search-engine-optimisation/when-forum-spamming-goes-bad.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 09:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search-engine-optimisation/when-forum-spamming-goes-bad.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;oldpost&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information &lt;a href=&#34;http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io&#34;&gt;create a pull request on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Forum spammers beware - some times if you push it that bit too much then you might just find that you get the concerted effort of legitimate forum members to out SEO you and make the whole plan backfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take this forum thread about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallamore.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the UKBusinessForums.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that despite multiple bans etc they just kept on spamming, so in the end the forum members (some of which do really know their stuff with regards to SEO) decided they had had enough and would retaliate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is that as I type this blog post, the number three position for searches on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&#34;&gt;Dallamore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&amp;page=2&#34;&gt;Dallamore.com&lt;/a&gt; and for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&amp;page=3&#34;&gt;Dallamore Spammers&lt;/a&gt; they are getting number one. And it hasn&amp;rsquo;t finished yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its a nice reminder that forums, whilst they may have lots of tempting page rank and regular spidering making them excellent places to drop links, you have to consider the primary reason that forums exist - to give real people a forum for discussion on a particular subject. Get a few real people annoyed - especially ones with a bit of web savvy - and you might end up with more than you bargained for!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>