<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: yorkshire | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/tag/yorkshire/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-03T13:16:23+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jobs in Leeds, PHP and Admin/Sales]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/job/jobs-in-leeds-php-and-adminsales.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T10:25:31+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/job/jobs-in-leeds-php-and-adminsales</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Edmonds Commerce are hiring at the moment.</p>

<h2>PHP Job Leeds</h2>


<p>We are always looking to grow our team of Leeds based professional PHP Developers. If you are at or around the Zend Certified Developer level and think you would pass the exam given a little time and preparation then please get in touch.</p>

<h2>Administration Job Leeds</h2>


<p>At the moment we are also looking for someone to join the team to help with administration and general customer services requirements. There is the possibility for this role to grow to meet your personal skills and ambitions.</p>

<p>For either role, please visit the <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/recruitment-contact-form/">Job Application form</a> to apply for a Job in Leeds.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHP Job Leeds, Still Hiring Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-job-leeds-hiring-developers.html"/>
    <updated>2011-05-18T18:55:33+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/php/php-job-leeds-hiring-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Just an update for any PHP developers in and around the Leeds, Bradford and West Yorkshire region:</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce are still looking for skilled and enthusiastic PHP developers to join the team.</p>

<p>Our focus is entirely on e-commerce which is an exciting and challenging field for the right kind of person.</p>

<p>We expect our developers to be at or around the Zend Certified Developer level but other than that there are no specific criteria.</p>

<p>If you are interested please do get in touch.</p>

<p>We will initially ask you to do a quick PHP quiz, if you want to do that straight away just go here</p>

<p><a href="http://www.edmonds-commerce.co.uk/PHPTest/form.php"><a href="http://www.edmonds-commerce.co.uk/PHPTest/form.php">http://www.edmonds-commerce.co.uk/PHPTest/form.php</a></a></p>

<p>Do <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us">get in touch directly</a> as well though, the spam bots quite enjoy filling it out as well and I haven&rsquo;t got around to protecting it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magento Training Course Details]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-details.html"/>
    <updated>2009-10-28T07:43:57+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/magento/magento-training-course-details</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As previously announced, we have started to run a Magento training course. The course is targeted at Magento site owners who are new to the system and are keen to get the most out of their Magento store.</p>

<p>One of the key advantages of Magento is it&rsquo;s wealth of professional ecommerce features that all come bundled as standard. These really make it stand proud of the competition. However, if you don&rsquo;t know how to use those features then they are wasted. This course aims to rectify that.</p>

<p>If you would like to book one of the limited number of places, please do so ASAP. Simply give us a call on <strong>0844 357 0201</strong> or contact us via our <strong><a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html">contact form</a></strong>. There are multiple dates scheduled so get in touch to find out the latest information.</p>

<h3>Here are some details of the course:</h3>


<blockquote>
<p>This is a one day introductory course to the Magento Ecommerce system. Magento is an awesomely powerful cutting edge open source ecommerce package that is quickly gaining a large following due to its impressive array of powerful enterprise level features.</p>

<p>This course will give you the background understanding and practical skills needed to get the best out of your Magento store. You will leave with a clearer understanding of some of the more complex principles in Magento and will learn how to leverage some of the core features of Magento to get the most out of your store.</p>
                
<h3>Recommended for:</h3><br>
                <p>This course is designed for business owners or staff who are or will be running a Magento based ecommerce business. It will enable your business to get the maximum return on your investment into Magento by ensuring you and your staff are using the system to it's fullest capabilities.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>You will learn how to:</h3><br>
                <p><strong>Key Magento Principles:</strong><br>MVC Code Architecture, EAV Database Structure, Module Based Customisation and Magento Connect</p>
<p><strong>Magento Product / Category Administration:</strong><br>Attribute Sets, The Product Types (Simple, Configurable etc), Cross Sell, Up Sell, Related Products and  SEO Techniques</p>
<p><strong>Magento Order / Customer Administration:</strong><br>Orders, Invoices, Shipments,Credit Memos and Customer Details and Passwords</p>
<p><strong>Basic Magento Configuration Options:</strong><br>Payment Methods, Shipping Methods and General Configuation</p>
<br><br><h3>Course outline:</h3><br>                
<style type="text/css">
table{
margin: 5px;
background: #8E96CF;
}
td{
margin:2px;
background: white;
padding: 3px;
}
</style>
                <table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="3" width="454">
<p><strong>Day 1</strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" width="142">

<p>Lesson</p>
</td>
<td width="312">
<p>Description</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="19">
<p>1</p>
</td>
<td width="123">
<p><strong>Key Magento Principles</strong></p>
</td>

<td width="312">
<p>A holistic overview of   the Magento system and its core principles, philosophy and background.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="19">
<p>2</p>
</td>
<td width="123">
<p><strong>Magento Product /   Category Administration</strong></p>
</td>
<td width="312">
<p>Setting up the   categories and products that make up your store and updating this catalogue.   In depth coverage of the extra features of the Magento products system. This   will be the largest element of the course.</p>

</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="19">
<p>3</p>
</td>
<td width="123">
<p><strong>Magento Order /   Customer Administration</strong></p>
</td>
<td width="312">
<p>How to manage orders,   customers, invoices, shipments and credits within the Magento adminstration   system.</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>

<td width="19">
<p>4</p>
</td>
<td width="123">
<p><strong>Basic Magento   Configuration Options</strong></p>
</td>
<td width="312">
<p>A brief overview of how   the Magento configuration works and a look at some of the more commonly used   configuration options.</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Course dates:</h3><br>
                <p><strong><a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html">Get in touch</a> for the latest dates - new dates being added all the time!</strong></p>
</blockquote>


<p>If you would like to book one of the limited number of places, please do so ASAP. Simply give us a call on <strong>0844 357 0201</strong> or contact us via our <strong><a href="http://www.edmondscommerce.co.uk/contact-about-magento-training.html">contact form</a></strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
