<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: search engine optimisation | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/search-engine-optimisation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-09T16:11:23+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Forum Spamming Goes Bad..]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/when-forum-spamming-goes-bad.html"/>
    <updated>2010-06-02T09:27:55+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/when-forum-spamming-goes-bad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Forum spammers beware &ndash; some times if you push it that bit too much then you might just find that you get the concerted effort of legitimate forum members to out SEO you and make the whole plan backfire.</p>

<p>Take this forum thread about <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739"><strong>Dallamore.com</strong></a> on the UKBusinessForums.co.uk</p>

<p>It seems that despite multiple bans etc they just kept on spamming, so in the end the forum members (some of which do really know their stuff with regards to SEO) decided they had had enough and would retaliate.</p>

<p>The result is that as I type this blog post, the number three position for searches on <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739">Dallamore</a>, <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&page=2">Dallamore.com</a> and for <a href="http://www.ukbusinessforums.co.uk/forums/showthread.php?t=157739&page=3">Dallamore Spammers</a> they are getting number one. And it hasn&rsquo;t finished yet.</p>

<p>Its a nice reminder that forums, whilst they may have lots of tempting page rank and regular spidering making them excellent places to drop links, you have to consider the primary reason that forums exist &ndash; to give real people a forum for discussion on a particular subject. Get a few real people annoyed &ndash; especially ones with a bit of web savvy &ndash; and you might end up with more than you bargained for!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SEO Service Providers - What to Check For:]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/seo/seo-service-providers-what-to-check-for.html"/>
    <updated>2008-10-14T14:05:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/seo/seo-service-providers-what-to-check-for</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>Many organisations choose to outsource some or all of their SEO efforts. SEO is at once simple and also complicated. The basic principles are simple enough, but if you do things slightly wrong then you may inadvertantly do something which is actually counter productive to your SEO efforts.</p>

<p>To combat spammy sites, search engines use various methods to check if a site is spammy or not. Unfortunately like any automated system there will always be false positives. What this means to you is that if you accidently do something which the search engines will regard as spammy, you might actually harm rather than help your search engine performance.</p>

<p>Unfortunately there are many organisations who market themselves as SEO professionals and offer SEO services, but will at best do you no good and at worst could actually trigger your site to be labelled as spammy by the search engines and get you penalised.</p>

<p>Today I received a well written email from a UK based company (I won&rsquo;t name names) offering a link building service with a free 30 day trial. Why not is the first instinct &ndash; a free trial is worth having I suppose.</p>

<p>Upon ringing the company and speaking to one of their represenatives, I quickly determined that this company is not one that I would like to be handling any aspect of my SEO efforts. Here are the things that got me worried:</p>

<p><strong>Searching Google for the company name did not bring them up</strong>
If nothing else, every web site should rank number one for its own name. I asked them about this and they told me that they do not want to rank in the search engines&hellip;? An SEO company that doesn&rsquo;t want to rank in the search engines&hellip;.</p>

<p><strong>Their website has a pagerank of 0 &ndash; a white bar in the Google Toolbar</strong>
Many people will tell you these days that pagerank is not important. In general I agree, however having no pagerank at all is a particularly bad sign, especially considering the fact that link building is intended to build link popularity which is pretty much what pagerank is about. For a link building company that&rsquo;s ridiculous.</p>

<p><strong>They were unwilling to offer any examples of sites that they have done SEO for</strong>
They quoted privacy for this which is fair enough, however I am sure that a happy client would not have any complaints if their site was used to demonstrate the value of the SEO companies services.</p>

<p><strong>They only place links on their own network of sites</strong>
This is where it starts to get really bad. The technique they use is widely acknowledged to be a spamming tactic which Google can detect and will penalise. Getting your link spread across this link farm will almost certainly get your site penalised.</p>

<p>A real link building company would search out sites that are &ldquo;out there&rdquo; on the internet that are in the same niche as your site and will try to get these sites to link back to your site. It&rsquo;s an incredibly difficult and laborious task which is why so many people outsource it.</p>

<p>I have looked into loads of different companies that offer a link building service and have yet to find one that actually does what it says on the tin. I have seen companies that simply add your link to a bunch of link farms that they control (as in this case) which is at best totally useless.</p>

<p>I have also seen companies who charge high monthly rates for links on an ongoing basis. All these guys are doing is simply renting links for you. This is another tactic which Google is going after in a big way. The value of hired links is now questionable. There is no real need to use a middle man for this service as there are plenty of link renting sites set up that you can organise your own link rentals should you decide to go down this path.</p>

<p>In my opinion any SEO tactic that requires ongoing payment to sustain is not real SEO. To me real SEO is like building a wall. Every action you do is another brick in the wall. Your wall gets bigger and stronger every day and with consistent effort you have built a nice solid house that brings consistent traffic with no ongoing investment.</p>

<p>If you would like to discuss SEO services with Edmonds Commerce by all means get in touch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHP 301 Redirect Function with Headers Check and Javascript Fallback]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/php/php-301-redirect-function-with-headers-check-and-javascript-fallback.html"/>
    <updated>2008-05-22T15:46:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/php/php-301-redirect-function-with-headers-check-and-javascript-fallback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you are changing your URL structure, for example when moving to a search engine friendly URLs system, you need to be able to let Google and all the other search engines that the page has moved to the new URL. You really don&rsquo;t want to display the same content on two URLs</p>

<p>So to achieve this we can do what is called a 301 redirect. This is a special redirect message which basically says &ldquo;has permanently moved to&rdquo;. By doing this, all of the search engine power, rank or whatever you want to call it will be directly transferred to the new URL.</p>

<p><strong>However</strong></p>

<p>Sometimes your script might spit out the headers earlier than you expect. If this happens then your site will fail completely to load with a fatal error along the lines of</p>

<p><strong>warning: Cannot modify header information &ndash; headers already sent by (output started at .</strong>&hellip;</p>

<p>We really don&rsquo;t want this to happen, so what we can do is wrap the redirection in a headers_sent check and then fall back to a javascript redirect if headers have been sent for some reason. This is belt and braces logic.</p>

<p><i><b>Note script tags need spaces removing</b></i>
```php</p>

<p>function requrl_check($correct_url, $delay=3){</p>

<pre><code>$request_url = 'http://' . $_SERVER['HTTP_HOST'] . $_SERVER['REQUEST_URI'];
if($request_url != $correct_url){
    if(!headers_sent()){ //going to assume that headers are not sent
    header("HTTP/1.1 301 Moved Permanently");
        header('location: ' . $correct_url . ''); 
        exit();
    }else{
        echo "&lt;h3&gt;The Page $request_url has Moved&lt;/h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=$correct_url&gt;$correct_url&lt;/a&gt;";
        echo '&lt;h3&gt;Now Refreshing in ' . $delay . ' Seconds&lt;/h3&gt;Refreshing to:&lt;br&gt;' . $correct_url . '&lt;s c r i p t type="text/JavaScript"&gt;&lt;!--
    setTimeout("location.href = \'' . $correct_url . '\';",' . ($delay * 1000) . ');
    --&gt; &lt;/s c r i p t&gt;';
        exit();
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>tidy :&ndash;)</p>

<p><b>Further Reading:</b>
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.stuntdubl.com/2005/09/06/301-redirects/">www.stuntdubl.com</a>
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.intertwingly.net/blog/911.html">www.intertwingly.ne</a>
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://webgasm.actiononline.biz/seo/?p=87">webgasm.actiononline.biz</a>
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.techcounter.com/seo/permalink-migration-for-a-wordpress-blog-using-a-301-redirect/">www.techcounter.com</a>
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chiropractichomepage.com/2007/03/16/chiropractor-web-page-gets-301-redirect/">www.chiropractichomepage.com</a>
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://123howtoguide.com/seo/how-to-redirect-a-web-page-using-301-redirect">123howtoguide.com</a>
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://searchblog.tamar.com/2007/07/understanding-t.html">searchblog.tamar.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meta Title Tag and SEO]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/meta-title-tag-and-seo.html"/>
    <updated>2008-04-08T18:20:47+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/meta-title-tag-and-seo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>There are some very complicated aspects to a successful on page search engine optimisation strategy. However there are also some incredibly simple ones.</p>

<p>At the very top of the list of simple things you can do to improve your SEO is to make sure that your &#60;&#116;&#105;&#116;&#108;&#101;&#62; tag contains a unique and descriptive page title for each and every page of your web site.</p>

<p>If you have a smaller site with not too many pages then you can handle this by hand. On the other hand, if you have an ecommerce store for example with hundreds or thousands of products and categories then it is going to be easier to build in some kind of dynamic title functionality.</p>

<p>Edmonds Commerce have helped out numerous web masters by implementing a bespoke and automatic dynamic meta tag system which creates a highly optimised title for each and every page.</p>

<p>If you would like us to help you out, simply get in touch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Backend System]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/online-backend-system.html"/>
    <updated>2008-03-10T16:45:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/search%20engine%20optimisation/online-backend-system</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>What could be more convenient than having all of your business systems integrated into one online package. No more hassles moving information from online to offline systems. No more out of date or vague information regarding stock figures or supplier invoices.</p>

<p>For an online business with a well specified and rigorously backed up dedicated server, it makes a lot of sense to move away from applications that run on the desktop to applications that run on the server. For your employees to interact with your business systems, they only need a broadband internet connection and a web browser. This in turn opens up the possiblity of moving away from costly and insecure windows desktops to a more robust and cheaper to run Ubuntu Linux desktop. Preloaded with firefox web browser and the open office suite of office applications, Ubuntu is an excellent choice for a business desktop.</p>

<p>If you want to increase productivity whilst simultaneously slashing operating costs, get in touch with Edmonds Commerce today to find out how a bespoke online business system can improve your business.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
