<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ubuntu | Edmonds Commerce Dev Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/category/ubuntu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-12T15:36:15+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EdmondsCommerce Development Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 10.10 is Dead... What next?]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-10-10-is-dead-what-next.html"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T09:21:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-10-10-is-dead-what-next</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we and no doubt countless other Ubuntu 10.10 users got the dreaded:
<img src="/assets/1010dead.png">
You can read the official announcement <a href="http://fridge.ubuntu.com/2012/04/10/ubuntu-10-10-maverick-meerkat-end-of-life-reached-on-april-10-2012/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=ubuntu-10-10-maverick-meerkat-end-of-life-reached-on-april-10-2012">here</a>.
As everyone is aware, Ubuntu and Gnome have both moved towards a new desktop environment paradigm which is designed to be a bit more dumbed down and accessible to less technical users.</p>

<p>Unfortunately its not really suitable for power users who might have a LOT of open windows spread over multiple desktops and often running multiple monitors.</p>

<p>Gnome 2, simple as it was, has some really nice desktop features that once you are used to them it feels like you can&rsquo;t live without them.</p>

<p>So now the big question is, what next?</p>

<p>We already have one Linux Mint fan in the office and it is looking like this project is going in the right kind of direction for us with their support for MATE (Gnome 2 basically) and also the Cinnamon desktop which is a more modern take on the classic Gnome 2 desktop paradigm. Its more than likely this is where we will be going to next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Prevent Focus Stealing]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-prevent-focus-stealing.html"/>
    <updated>2012-04-05T15:07:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/ubuntu-prevent-focus-stealing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you find yourself typing away whilst something else loads or another window pops open and all of a sudden your typing has gone into a different window then this solution is for you</p>

<p>Open gconf-editor. Open a terminal and type gconf-editor and hit return.</p>

<p>Now navigate to /apps/compiz/general/screen0/options/focus_prevention_level key and set its value to 4.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it.</p>

<p>You might actually decide that focus stealing is sometimes useful in which case you can always change it back.</p>

<p>Originally found here: <a href="http://askubuntu.com/a/55220"><a href="http://askubuntu.com/a/55220">http://askubuntu.com/a/55220</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Path Tools Netbeans Open File in external program plus guake code]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/path-tools-netbeans-open-file-in-external-program-plus-guake-code.html"/>
    <updated>2012-01-10T16:30:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/path-tools-netbeans-open-file-in-external-program-plus-guake-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not many people are aware of the Path Tools extension for netbeans, and even fewer know how to make it really useful.</p>

<p>Effectively it provides 4 buttons &ndash; Copy Path, Open Folder, Open Terminal and Edit Path, the latter three being configurable.</p>

<p>Its default for Open Folder is great (for gnome users) but that&rsquo;s the only one that has a default.</p>

<p>I use Guake (a pull-down transparent terminal) and for the two options (For Folder and For File) I set to the following for a nice &ldquo;New tab in guake&rdquo; :&ndash;
<code>
guake --new-tab "{path}" -t
</code>
and
<code>
guake --new-tab "{parent-path}" -t
</code></p>

<p>And for the &ldquo;Edit Path&rdquo; button, I find it extremely useful to create a &ldquo;run external program&rdquo; script &ndash; sat in my personal bin directory ($HOME/bin/) containing the following code :&ndash;
```</p>

<h1>!/bin/bash</h1>

<p>ESCAPEDPARAMS=<code>echo $* | sed -e 's/\([[\/.*]\|\]\)/\\\&amp;/g'</code>
MIME=<code>file --mime-type $* | cut -f2 -d: | cut -f2 -d' '</code>
DESKTOPFILE=/usr/share/applications/<code>xdg-mime query default $MIME</code>
EXEC=<code>grep '^Exec=' $DESKTOPFILE | cut -f2 -d=</code>
COMMAND=<code>zenity --width 600 --entry --title="Path Tools" --text="Run Command : " --entry-text="$(echo $EXEC | sed s/'%U'/"$ESCAPEDPARAMS"/)"</code></p>

<p>if [ &ldquo;$?&rdquo;==&ldquo;0&rdquo; ]; then
  sh -c &ldquo;$COMMAND&rdquo;
else
  echo &ldquo;&rdquo;
fi
```
and set that up as the command &ldquo;For Folder&rdquo; and &ldquo;For File&rdquo; with {path} for both (not {parent-path} notice).</p>

<p>So, what does it do?</p>

<ul>
    <li>MIME variable is set to the mime-type of the file (e.g. image/jpeg)</li>
    <li>DESKTOPFILE is set to the .desktop file that is associated with that mime-type (for my gnome setup this is /usr/share/applications/${DESKTOPFILE} )</li>
    <li>EXEC is the command contained within that desktop file</li>
    <li>COMMAND uses zenity to prompt for the commandline I want to run, pre-populated with the gnome default</li>
</ul>


<p>This means when I press the &ldquo;Edit Path&rdquo; button on a JPeg file, a popup asks for a commandline, prepopulated with my defaults (in this instance &ldquo;eog /path/to/file.jpg&rdquo;) and if I want I can change the command to gimp.  If I click OK in the box, the command is run.  If I just wanted to see the full path, I can maximise the box, look at it and click Cancel.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secure dropbox alternative]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/secure-dropbox-alternative.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-14T16:39:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/secure-dropbox-alternative</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>So there is often a requirement for sharing files but what happens if those files are files that absolutely must be secure, like private ssh keys?</p>

<p>Well Dropbox whilst a good product is third-party and not encrypted so if there&rsquo;s an exploit, the contents of the files could well be exposed to people you don&rsquo;t want.</p>

<p>Enter Wuala, a service by Lacie.  Similar to Dropbox in many ways, but differing in that the files are encrypted locally, so if you loose your password, the files will be inaccessible, permanently.  Believe it or not, that&rsquo;s a really good thing!</p>

<p>Oh, and there&rsquo;s a client for Linux, Mac, Windows and Mobile (Android and iPhone).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copying Text from PDF table is not formatted correctly + solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/copying-text-from-pdf-table-is-not-formatted-correctly-solution.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-02T17:41:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://edmondscommerce.github.io/ubuntu/copying-text-from-pdf-table-is-not-formatted-correctly-solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="oldpost"><h4>This is post is now quite old and the the information it contains may be out of date or innacurate.</h4>
<p>
If you find any errors or have any suggestions to update the information <a href="http://edmondscommerce.github.io/contact-us/index.html">please let us know</a>
or <a href="https://github.com/edmondscommerce/edmondscommerce.github.io">create a pull request on GitHub</a>
</p>
</div>


<p>If you need to extract the information from a PDF table sometimes when you copy and paste it into a text editor the formatting is incorrect making the information useless.</p>

<p>In cases like this, you can use pdfedit to extract the text in the correct formatting and then do what you need with it.</p>

<p>To use the program first make sure it&rsquo;s installed. If not install it like this</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install pdfedit
</code></p>

<p>then use it to open the PDF. Click through the the correct page and then click Page &ndash;> Extract Text From Page</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
